<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://Furyton.github.io/misc-feed/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-03-14T03:18:46.386Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://Furyton.github.io/misc-feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://Furyton.github.io/misc-feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[kuva Lapista² [jatp]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52544</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/14/kuva-lapista%c2%b2-jatp/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T23:23:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transcriptional Chinese animal imagery for English daily greetings]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58199</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58199&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=transcriptional-chinese-animal-imagery-for-english-daily-greetings"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T22:35:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As those students who take my early morning classes know, I sometimes greet them with "gǒutóu māo níng 狗头猫咛" ("good morning"; lit. "dog's head cat's meow").  I learned that method of transcription from my father-in-law, who didn't know the alphabet but picked up a few words of English and wanted to write them down for […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DORA: Exploring outlier representations in Deep Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.04530</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.04530"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T07:15:14.746Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kirill Bykov, Mayukh Deb, Dennis Grinwald, Klaus-Robert M\"uller,
  Marina M.-C. H\"ohne]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An analytic theory for the dynamics of wide quantum neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16711</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16711"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T07:15:14.740Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Junyu Liu, Khadijeh Najafi, Kunal Sharma, Francesco Tacchino, Liang
  Jiang, Antonio Mezzacapo]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[POLICE: Provably Optimal Linear Constraint Enforcement for Deep Neural
  Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01340</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01340"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T07:15:14.703Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Randall Balestriero, Yann LeCun]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variance-aware robust reinforcement learning with linear function
  approximation with heavy-tailed rewards]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.05606</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.05606"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T07:15:14.697Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Xiang Li, Qiang Sun]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seq2Seq Surrogates of Epidemic Models to Facilitate Bayesian Inference]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.09617</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.09617"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T07:15:14.690Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Giovanni Charles, Timothy M. Wolock, Peter Winskill, Azra Ghani, Samir
  Bhatt, Seth Flaxman]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[alone in Napoli]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52333</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/13/alone-in-napoli/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-12T23:23:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A combinatorics puzzle from The Riddler about a Napoli solitaire where 4 x 10 cards numbered from 1 to 10 are shuffled and the game is lost when a number (1,2, or 3) is equal to its position modulo 3 (1,2 or 3). A simple R code shows that the probability of winning is around […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[kuva Lapista¹]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52539</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/13/kuva-lapista/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-12T23:23:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[a journal of the plague, sword, and famine year [no end on sight]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52340</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/12/a-journal-of-the-plague-sword-and-famine-year-4/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-11T23:23:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read the second volume of The Craft Sequence, Two Serpents Rise, by Max Gladstone,  with great difficulties as I found the story (again) poorly constructed, despite some characters being mostly well-designed (no connection with volume 1, except for taking place in the same universe, if at another time period). Mixing steampunk and hard fantasy involving […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Idle thoughts upon the Ides of March:  the feathered man]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58178</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58178&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=idle-thoughts-upon-the-ides-of-march-the-feathered-man"/>
        <updated>2023-03-11T19:16:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's a bad month in general:  dark, dreary, drizzly, dank, and damp.  Soon one's thoughts are flitting* about as though one had taken wings, like Eros or Cupid. In Chinese mythology, there is a deity called Yǔrén 羽人 ("Feathered Man").  It has an ambiguous origin — first appears in Shānhǎi jīng 山海經 (Classic of the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[off to BayesComp!]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52425</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/11/off-to-bayescomp/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T23:23:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PaLM-E: An embodied multimodal language model]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/palm-e-embodied-multimodal-language.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/palm-e-embodied-multimodal-language.html"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T17:25:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Danny Driess, Student Researcher, and Pete Florence, Research Scientist, Robotics at Google  
Recent years have seen tremendous advances across machine learning domains, from models that can explain jokes or answer visual questions in a variety of languages to those that can produce images based on text descriptions. Such innovations have been possible due to the increase in availability of large scale datasets along with novel advances that enable the training of models on these data. While scaling of robotics models has seen some success, it is outpaced by other domains due to a lack of datasets available on a scale comparable to large text corpora or image datasets.  
  
Today we introduce PaLM-E, a new generalist robotics model that overcomes these issues by transferring know…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ludwig Schmidt - A data-centric view on reliable generalization: From ImageNet to LAION-5B]]></title>
        <id>https://mlfoundations.org/talk/schmidt/</id>
        <link href="https://mlfoundations.org/talk/schmidt/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers have proposed many methods to make neural networks more reliable under distribution shift, yet there is still large room for improvement. Are better training algorithms or training data the more promising way forward? In this talk, we study this question in the context of OpenAI’s CLIP model for learning from image-text data. First, we survey the current robustness landscape based on a large-scale experimental study involving more than 200 different models and test conditions. The CLIP models stand out with unprecedented robustness on multiple challenging distribution shifts. To further improve CLIP, we then introduce new methods for reliably fine-tuning models by interpolating the weights of multiple models. Next, we investigate the cause of CLIP’s robustness via controlled experiments to disentangle the influence of language supervision and training distribution. While CLIP leveraged large scale language supervision for the first time, its robustness actually comes from the pre-training dataset. We conclude with a brief overview of ongoing work to improve pre-training datasets: LAION-5B, the largest public image-text dataset, and initial experiments to increase the robustness induced by pre-training data. Bio: Ludwig Schmidt is an assistant professor in the Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science & Engineering at the University of Washington. Ludwig’s research interests revolve around the empirical foundations of machine learning, often with a focus on datasets, reliable generalization, and large models. Ludwig completed his PhD at MIT under the supervision of Piotr Indyk and was a postdoc at UC Berkeley hosted by Benjamin Recht and Moritz Hardt. Recently, Ludwig’s research group contributed to multimodal language & vision models by creating OpenCLIP and the LAION-5B dataset. Ludwig’s research received a new horizons award at EAAMO, best paper awards at ICML & NeurIPS, a best paper finalist at CVPR, and the Sprowls dissertation award from MIT.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harvard ML Foundations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Subspace Designs, Unit and Distinct Distances, and Piercing Standard Boxes.]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=23968</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/03/10/subspace-designs-unit-and-distinct-distances-and-piercing-standard-boxes/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T11:28:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of things are happening and let me briefly report on three major advancements in combinatorics. Peter Keevash, Ashwin Sah and Mehtaab Sawhney proved the existence of subspace designs with any given parameters, provided that the dimension of the … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Subspace Designs, Unit and Distinct Distances, and Piercing Standard Boxes.]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=23968</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/03/10/subspace-designs-unit-and-distinct-distances-and-piercing-standard-boxes/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T11:28:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of things are happening and let me briefly report on three major advancements in combinatorics. Peter Keevash, Ashwin Sah and Mehtaab Sawhney proved the existence of subspace designs with any given parameters, provided that the dimension of the … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Expressiveness and Generalization of Hypergraph Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.05490</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.05490"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T07:15:52.089Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zhezheng Luo, Jiayuan Mao, Joshua B. Tenenbaum, Leslie Pack Kaelbling]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TANGOS: Regularizing Tabular Neural Networks through Gradient
  Orthogonalization and Specialization]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.05506</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.05506"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T07:15:52.084Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alan Jeffares, Tennison Liu, Jonathan Crabb\'e, Fergus Imrie, Mihaela
  van der Schaar]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Rational Subgoals from Demonstrations and Instructions]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.05487</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.05487"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T07:15:52.064Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zhezheng Luo, Jiayuan Mao, Jiajun Wu, Tom\'as Lozano-P\'erez, Joshua
  B. Tenenbaum, Leslie Pack Kaelbling]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Agnostic PAC Learning of k-juntas Using L2-Polynomial Regression]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.04859</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.04859"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T07:15:52.059Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mohsen Heidari, Wojciech Szpankowski]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continual Learning for Monolingual End-to-End Automatic Speech
  Recognition]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.09427</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.09427"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T07:15:52.029Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Steven Vander Eeckt, Hugo Van hamme]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running from China]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58175</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58175&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=running-from-china"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T03:05:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The following image is from a guest post on the Tangle newsletter (3/3/23) that comes from a Chinese dissident who recently fled to the U.S.: The political slogan on the sign glares: xǐ yíng èrshí dà wénmíng rùn wàn jiā 喜迎二十大 文明润万家 "Welcome to the20th National Congress [The Party's] civilized [policies] enrich a myriad families" The […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Effect [book review]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52414</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/10/the-effect-book-review/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T23:23:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While it sounds like the title of a science-fiction catastrophe novel or of a (of course) convoluted nouveau roman, this book by Nick Huntington-Klein is a massive initiation to econometrics and causality. As explained by the subtitle, An Introduction to Research Design and Causality. This is a hüûüge book, actually made of two parts that […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The reality of Happiness is Bitterness]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58160</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58160&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-reality-of-happiness-is-bitterness"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T19:55:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Kiewwoo Goh: The actual transcription and translation of the first two lines and their one line English mistranslation should be: Shénme dōu shì jiǎ de Zhǐyǒu kǔ shì zhēn de 什么都是假的 只有苦是真的 Everything is false Only suffering is real The next big, composite, quadripartite glyph consists of four "kǔ 苦" ("bitterness; suffering") stacked side by side and on top of each […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The BirdCLEF 2023 Challenge: Pushing the frontiers of biodiversity monitoring]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/the-birdclef-2023-challenge-pushing.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/the-birdclef-2023-challenge-pushing.html"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T19:27:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Tom Denton, Software Engineer, Google Research, Brain Team   
Worldwide bird populations are declining at an alarming rate, with approximately 48% of existing bird species known or suspected to be experiencing population declines. For instance, the U.S. and Canada have reported 29% fewer birds since 1970. 

Effective monitoring of bird populations is essential for the development of solutions that promote conservation. Monitoring allows researchers to better understand the severity of the problem for specific bird populations and evaluate whether existing interventions are working. To scale monitoring, bird researchers have started analyzing ecosystems remotely using bird sound recordings instead of physically in-person via passive acoustic monitoring. Researchers can gather thou…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Causal Representation Learning for Instantaneous and Temporal Effects in
  Interactive Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.06169</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.06169"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T07:15:59.019Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Phillip Lippe, Sara Magliacane, Sindy L\"owe, Yuki M. Asano, Taco
  Cohen, Efstratios Gavves]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Causal Dependence Plots for Interpretable Machine Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.04209</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.04209"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T07:15:58.985Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joshua R. Loftus, Lucius E. J. Bynum, Sakina Hansen]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Generalization Power of Overfitted Two-Layer Neural Tangent
  Kernel Models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.05243</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.05243"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T07:15:58.941Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peizhong Ju, Xiaojun Lin, Ness B. Shroff]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Message Passing Perspective on Learning Dynamics of Contrastive
  Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.04435</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.04435"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T07:15:58.936Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yifei Wang, Qi Zhang, Tianqi Du, Jiansheng Yang, Zhouchen Lin, Yisen
  Wang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Questions and answers, part 2 (a veritable juggernaut)]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58172</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58172&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=questions-and-answers-part-2-a-veritable-juggernaut"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T02:02:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my experience, folks have different approaches / attitudes to questions (and answers): 1. some people love to ask questions 2. some people like to answer questions 3. some people don't like to ask questions 4. some people don't like to be asked questions 5. some people like to ask a question as a prelude […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[the secret history of the Lord of Musashi [book review]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52404</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/09/the-secret-history-of-the-lord-of-musashi-book-review/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T23:23:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This 1931 book, The Secret History of the Lord of Musashi (武州公秘話) by Jun’ichirō Tanizaki, is a hilarious pastiche of Japanese historical novels. I saw it in a Paris bookstore near my son’s and bought it without realising how much of a gem it is! I actually thought it was connected with the famous swordsman […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interview about this blog in the Bulletin of the EATCS]]></title>
        <id>http://windowsontheory.org/?p=8582</id>
        <link href="https://windowsontheory.org/2023/03/08/interview-about-this-blog-in-the-bulletin-of-the-eatcs/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T14:13:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Luca Trevisan recently interviewed me for the Bulletin of the EATCS (see link for the full issue, including an interview with Alexandra Silva, and technical columns by Naama Ben-David, Ryan Williams, and Yuri Gurevich). With Luca’s permission, I am cross-posting it here. (I added some hyperlinks to relevant documents.) Q. Boaz, thanks for taking the … Continue reading Interview about this blog in the Bulletin of the EATCS]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Boaz Barak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interview about this blog in the Bulletin of the EATCS]]></title>
        <id>http://windowsontheory.org/?p=8582</id>
        <link href="https://windowsontheory.org/2023/03/08/interview-about-this-blog-in-the-bulletin-of-the-eatcs/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T14:13:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Luca Trevisan recently interviewed me for the Bulletin of the EATCS (see link for the full issue, including an interview with Alexandra Silva, and technical columns by Naama Ben-David, Ryan Williams, and Yuri Gurevich). With Luca’s permission, I am cross-posting it here. (I added some hyperlinks to relevant documents.) Q. Boaz, thanks for taking the … Continue reading Interview about this blog in the Bulletin of the EATCS]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Boaz Barak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning particle swarming models from data with Gaussian processes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2106.02735</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2106.02735"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T07:16:07.576Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jinchao Feng, Charles Kulick, Yunxiang Ren, Sui Tang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using multimodal learning and deep generative models for corporate
  bankruptcy prediction]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.08405</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.08405"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T07:16:07.571Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rogelio A. Mancisidor]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prior and Posterior Networks: A Survey on Evidential Deep Learning
  Methods For Uncertainty Estimation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.03051</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.03051"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T07:16:07.563Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dennis Ulmer, Christian Hardmeier, Jes Frellsen]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Free Lunch from the Noise: Provable and Practical Exploration for
  Representation Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.11485</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.11485"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T07:16:07.545Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tongzheng Ren, Tianjun Zhang, Csaba Szepesv\'ari, Bo Dai]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hanmoji, part 2]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58169</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58169&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=hanmoji-part-2"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T23:26:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Hanmoji" is a portmanteau consisting of the first syllable of hanzi ("Chinese character") and the second part of emoji. From Bob Bauer: Have you heard of or seen the book entitled The Hanmoji Handbook: Your Guide to the Chinese Language through Emoji, MITeen Press, published August 30, 2022? The day before yesterday (Thursday, 2 March […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[International Women’s Day 2023 [and how far from a fair society…]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52505</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/08/international-womens-day-2023-and-how-far-from-a-fair-society/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T23:23:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Kuperberg @ Tel Aviv University]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=23935</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/03/07/greg-kuperberg-tel-aviv-university/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T19:45:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Kuperberg is having a short visit in Israel and yesterday he gave a fantastic lecture on an improved bound for the Kitaev-Solovay theorem. Here is a videotaped lecture of Greg on the same topic in QIP2023. Kitaev-Solovay theorem from … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Kuperberg @ Tel Aviv University]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=23935</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/03/07/greg-kuperberg-tel-aviv-university/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T19:45:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Greg Kuperberg is having a short visit in Israel and yesterday he gave a fantastic lecture on an improved bound for the Kitaev-Solovay theorem. Here is a videotaped lecture of Greg on the same topic in QIP2023. Kitaev-Solovay theorem from … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing the ICDAR 2023 Competition on Hierarchical Text Detection and Recognition]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/announcing-icdar-2023-competition-on.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/announcing-icdar-2023-competition-on.html"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T18:10:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Shangbang Long, Software Engineer, Google Research   
The last few decades have witnessed the rapid development of Optical Character Recognition (OCR) technology, which has evolved from an academic benchmark task used in early breakthroughs of deep learning research to tangible products available in consumer devices and to third party developers for daily use. These OCR products digitize and democratize the valuable information that is stored in paper or image-based sources (e.g., books, magazines, newspapers, forms, street signs, restaurant menus) so that they can be indexed, searched, translated, and further processed by state-of-the-art natural language processing techniques.  
 
Research in scene text detection and recognition (or scene text spotting) has been the major drive…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning low-rank latent mesoscale structures in networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.06984</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2102.06984"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T07:14:49.194Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hanbaek Lyu, Yacoub H. Kureh, Joshua Vendrow, Mason A. Porter]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pre-trained Gaussian processes for Bayesian optimization]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.08215</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.08215"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T07:14:49.153Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zi Wang, George E. Dahl, Kevin Swersky, Chansoo Lee and
  Zachary Nado, Justin Gilmer, Jasper Snoek, Zoubin Ghahramani]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning High-Dimensional Single-Neuron ReLU Networks with Finite
  Samples]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.02255</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.02255"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T07:14:49.084Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jingfeng Wu, Difan Zou, Zixiang Chen, Vladimir Braverman and
  Quanquan Gu, Sham M. Kakade]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning k-Level Sparse Neural Networks Using a New Generalized Weighted
  Group Sparse Envelope Regularization]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.12921</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.12921"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T07:14:49.075Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yehonathan Refael, Iftach Arbel, Wasim Huleihel]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collaborative Learning with a Drone Orchestrator]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.02266</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.02266"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T07:14:48.956Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mahnoosh Mahdavimoghadam, Mahdi Boloursaz Mashhadi, Rahim Tafazolli,
  Walid Saad]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tiger：一个“抠”到极致的优化器]]></title>
        <id>https://kexue.fm/archives/9512</id>
        <link href="https://kexue.fm/archives/9512"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T02:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[这段时间笔者一直在实验《Google新搜出的优化器Lion：效率与效果兼得的“训练狮”》所介绍的Lion优化器。之所以对Lion饶有兴致，是因为它跟笔者之前的关于理想优化器的一些想法不谋而合，但...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>苏剑林</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-collision particle physics]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58156</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58156&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=anti-collision-particle-physics"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T01:13:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From the Temu website. They're the kind of bumper buttons you put on cabinet doors or sometimes on the bottoms of fragile things. IKEA furniture used to come with a couple of these. Just peel and stick in the corner so cabinet doors don't slam. Selected readings "'These can be aptly compared with the challenges, problems, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ABConic mean evidence approximation]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52370</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/07/abconic-mean-evidence-approximation/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-06T23:23:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following a question on X validated about evidence approximation in ABC settings, i.e., on returning an approximation of the evidence based on the outputs of parallel ABC runs for the models under comparison, I wondered at the relevance of an harmonic mean estimator in that context. Rather than using the original ABC algorithm that proposes […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Speech Model (USM): State-of-the-art speech AI for 100+ languages]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/universal-speech-model-usm-state-of-art.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/universal-speech-model-usm-state-of-art.html"/>
        <updated>2023-03-06T18:06:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Yu Zhang, Research Scientist, and James Qin, Software Engineer, Google Research  
Last November, we announced the 1,000 Languages Initiative, an ambitious commitment to build a machine learning (ML) model that would support the world’s one thousand most-spoken languages, bringing greater inclusion to billions of people around the globe. However, some of these languages are spoken by fewer than twenty million people, so a core challenge is how to support languages for which there are relatively few speakers or limited available data. 

Today, we are excited to share more about the Universal Speech Model (USM), a critical first step towards supporting 1,000 languages. USM is a family of state-of-the-art speech models with 2B parameters trained on 12 million hours of speech and 28 b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spectral learning of Bernoulli linear dynamical systems models for
  decision-making]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.02060</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.02060"/>
        <updated>2023-03-06T07:16:08.680Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Iris R. Stone, Yotam Sagiv, Il Memming Park, Jonathan W. Pillow]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continual Learning of Language Models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.03241</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.03241"/>
        <updated>2023-03-06T07:16:08.209Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zixuan Ke, Yijia Shao, Haowei Lin, Tatsuya Konishi, Gyuhak Kim, and
  Bing Liu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning on heterogeneous graphs using high-order relations]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.15532</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.15532"/>
        <updated>2023-03-06T07:16:08.165Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[See Hian Lee, Feng Ji, Wee Peng Tay]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't fear the unlabelled: safe semi-supervised learning via simple
  debiasing]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.07512</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.07512"/>
        <updated>2023-03-06T07:16:06.488Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hugo Schmutz, Olivier Humbert, Pierre-Alexandre Mattei]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncertainty Estimation by Fisher Information-based Evidential Deep
  Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.02045</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.02045"/>
        <updated>2023-03-06T07:16:06.482Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Danruo Deng, Guangyong Chen, Yang Yu, Furui Liu, Pheng-Ann Heng]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[slice samplers for nested sampling]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52350</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/06/slice-samplers-for-nested-sampling/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-05T23:23:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“…the likelihoods of discarded points have interesting properties. In particular, the fraction of prior mass below the likelihood threshold is approximately 1/K [number of particles].” I came across a newly arXived paper on nested sampling, written by Johannes Buchner, with a focus on sampling over the constrained space defined by the lower bound on the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The earliest horse riders]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58152</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58152&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-earliest-horse-riders"/>
        <updated>2023-03-05T15:40:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The implications of horse domestication — above all its consequent equine chariotry and horseback riding — for the spread of Indo-European are topics we have addressed on numerous occasions before.  A paper that was published just two days ago has made a stunning, convincing breakthrough concerning when and where humans began to ride horses: "First […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[47e cross de Sceaux [22:08, 31/226, 2/6 M5]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52356</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/05/47e-cross-de-sceaux-2208-31-226-2-6-m5/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-04T23:23:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lecture on the anatomical origins of language]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58141</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58141&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=lecture-on-the-anatomical-origins-of-language"/>
        <updated>2023-03-04T10:39:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[[Please read all the way to the bottom of this post.  There are some big surprises here, including references to a book and an article on linguistics by the novelist Tom Wolfe (1930-2018), who's clearly on the wrong side of the political fence.  Despite the spate of mostly unremittingly anti-Wolfe comments, many important issues about […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel AGT Day, Reichman University, March 5, 2023]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=23922</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/03/04/israel-agt-day-reichman-university-march-5-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-04T10:13:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are running tomorrow the annual Israeli workshop in algorithmic game theory. Where: Reichman University. The conference will take place in room EL03, Adelson building.  Program: here. Registration: here (free). Main speakers: Moshe Babaioff (Microsoft Research), Gil Kalai (Reichman University … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel AGT Day, Reichman University, March 5, 2023]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=23922</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/03/04/israel-agt-day-reichman-university-march-5-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-04T10:13:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are running tomorrow the annual Israeli workshop in algorithmic game theory. Where: Reichman University. The conference will take place in room EL03, Adelson building.  Program: here. Registration: here (free). Main speakers: Moshe Babaioff (Microsoft Research), Gil Kalai (Reichman University … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[extra layers for BayesComp]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52430</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/04/extra-layers-for-bayescomp/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-03T23:23:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just a reminder that Levi stands at 67.8⁰ North, which is way north of Iceland latitude-wise, and therefore prone to low temperatures, as shown by the above forecast. Hence bring extra layers! And, for the few remaining stragglers, register before the deadline, Monday 06 March.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Performer-MPC: Navigation via real-time, on-robot transformers]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/performer-mpc-navigation-via-real-time.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/performer-mpc-navigation-via-real-time.html"/>
        <updated>2023-03-03T18:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Krzysztof Choromanski, Staff Research Scientist, Robotics at Google, and Xuesu Xiao, Visiting Researcher, George Mason University   
Despite decades of research, we don’t see many mobile robots roaming our homes, offices, and streets. Real-world robot navigation in human-centric environments remains an unsolved problem. These challenging situations require safe and efficient navigation through tight spaces, such as squeezing between coffee tables and couches, maneuvering in tight corners, doorways, untidy rooms, and more. An equally critical requirement is to navigate in a manner that complies with unwritten social norms around people, for example, yielding at blind corners or staying at a comfortable distance. Google Research is committed to examining how advances in ML may enab…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Japanese arrow emojis]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58135</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58135&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=japanese-arrow-emojis"/>
        <updated>2023-03-03T15:05:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I often receive anguished inquiries about emojis, emoticons, hanzi, hangul, kana, and similar matters.  I try to answer as many of them as I can, and many of them have important implications for the nature of writing, the relationship between speech and script, cultural interactions and contexts, and so forth. Back in mid-January, there was […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In all LikelihoodS: How to Reliably Select Pseudo-Labeled Data for
  Self-Training in Semi-Supervised Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.01117</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.01117"/>
        <updated>2023-03-03T07:15:56.301Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Julian Rodemann, Christoph Jansen, Georg Schollmeyer, Thomas Augustin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NTS-NOTEARS: Learning Nonparametric DBNs With Prior Knowledge]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.04286</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.04286"/>
        <updated>2023-03-03T07:15:55.453Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Xiangyu Sun, Oliver Schulte, Guiliang Liu, Pascal Poupart]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weighted Ensemble Self-Supervised Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.09981</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.09981"/>
        <updated>2023-03-03T07:15:55.448Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yangjun Ruan, Saurabh Singh, Warren Morningstar, Alexander A. Alemi,
  Sergey Ioffe, Ian Fischer, Joshua V. Dillon]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Towards the Generalization of Contrastive Self-Supervised Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.00743</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.00743"/>
        <updated>2023-03-03T07:15:54.783Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weiran Huang, Mingyang Yi, Xuyang Zhao, Zihao Jiang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sparse-penalized deep neural networks estimator under weak dependence]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.01406</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.01406"/>
        <updated>2023-03-03T07:15:54.769Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[William Kengne, Modou Wade]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[sticker for birds]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52235</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/03/sticker-for-birds/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-02T23:23:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A moderately interesting article in the NYT on why birds crash into (my) windows and the limited efficiency of bird stickers, esp. those glued from the inside. Just like insects, who have difficulties understanding the concept of glass (!), birds fly into glass windows because they do not realise they are there. What I find […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distributed differential privacy for federated learning]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/distributed-differential-privacy-for.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/distributed-differential-privacy-for.html"/>
        <updated>2023-03-02T21:14:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Florian Hartmann, Software Engineer, and Peter Kairouz, Research Scientist, Google Research  
Federated learning is a distributed way of training machine learning (ML) models where data is locally processed and only focused model updates and metrics that are intended for immediate aggregation are shared with a server that orchestrates training. This allows the training of models on locally available signals without exposing raw data to servers, increasing user privacy. In 2021, we announced that we are using federated learning to train Smart Text Selection models, an Android feature that helps users select and copy text easily by predicting what text they want to select and then automatically expanding the selection for them. 
 
Since that launch, we have worked to improve the pr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning time-scales in two-layers neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.00055</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.00055"/>
        <updated>2023-03-02T07:15:44.567Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rapha\"el Berthier, Andrea Montanari, Kangjie Zhou]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greedy Actor-Critic: A New Conditional Cross-Entropy Method for Policy
  Improvement]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1810.09103</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1810.09103"/>
        <updated>2023-03-02T07:15:44.561Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Samuel Neumann, Sungsu Lim, Ajin Joseph, Yangchen Pan, Adam White,
  Martha White]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning curves for deep structured Gaussian feature models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.00564</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.00564"/>
        <updated>2023-03-02T07:15:44.542Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jacob A. Zavatone-Veth, Cengiz Pehlevan]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random Features Model with General Convex Regularization: A Fine Grained
  Analysis with Precise Asymptotic Learning Curves]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.02678</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.02678"/>
        <updated>2023-03-02T07:15:44.537Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[David Bosch, Ashkan Panahi, Ayca \"Ozcelikkale, Devdatt Dubhash]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Berkeley Working Papers in Middle Iranian Philology]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58116</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58116&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=berkeley-working-papers-in-middle-iranian-philology"/>
        <updated>2023-03-02T03:19:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meant to send this more than a month ago. Interesting new journal in Iranian Studies Berkeley Working Papers in Middle Iranian Philology is a new open access e-journal hosted by UC Berkeley’s Department of Middle Eastern Languages and Cultures and edited by Adam Benkato and Arash Zeini. It publishes short and longer articles or research […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[keep thunderbird alive!]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52316</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/02/52316/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-01T23:23:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding the attention mechanism in sequence models]]></title>
        <id>63f42411c79d98004d9f8686</id>
        <link href="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/attention/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-01T22:44:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog post, we'll discuss a key innovation in sequence-to-sequence model architectures: the attention mechanism. This architecture innovation dramatically improved model performance for sequence-to-sequence tasks such as machine translation and text summarization. 
Moreover, the success of this attention mechanism led to the seminal paper, "Attention Is]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching old labels new tricks in heterogeneous graphs]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/teaching-old-labels-new-tricks-in.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/03/teaching-old-labels-new-tricks-in.html"/>
        <updated>2023-03-01T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Minji Yoon, Research Intern, and Bryan Perozzi, Research Scientist, Google Research, Graph Mining Team  
Industrial applications of machine learning are commonly composed of various items that have differing data modalities or feature distributions. Heterogeneous graphs (HGs) offer a unified view of these multimodal data systems by defining multiple types of nodes (for each data type) and edges (for the relation between data items). For instance, e-commerce networks might have [user, product, review] nodes or video platforms might have [channel, user, video, comment] nodes. Heterogeneous graph neural networks (HGNNs) learn node embeddings summarizing each node’s relationships into a vector. However, in real world HGs, there is often a label imbalance issue between different node …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning ReLU networks to high uniform accuracy is intractable]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.13531</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.13531"/>
        <updated>2023-03-01T07:15:24.618Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Julius Berner, Philipp Grohs, Felix Voigtlaender]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Agent-based Graph Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.11010</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.11010"/>
        <updated>2023-03-01T07:15:24.573Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Karolis Martinkus, P\'al Andr\'as Papp, Benedikt Schesch, Roger
  Wattenhofer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How optimal transport can tackle gender biases in multi-class
  neural-network classifiers for job recommendations?]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.14063</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.14063"/>
        <updated>2023-03-01T07:15:24.513Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fanny Jourdan, Titon Tshiongo Kaninku, Nicholas Asher, Jean-Michel
  Loubes, Laurent Risser]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Hidden Markov Models Using Conditional Samples]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.14753</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.14753"/>
        <updated>2023-03-01T07:15:24.508Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sham M. Kakade, Akshay Krishnamurthy, Gaurav Mahajan, Cyril Zhang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding The Robustness of Self-supervised Learning Through Topic
  Modeling]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.03539</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.03539"/>
        <updated>2023-03-01T07:15:24.466Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zeping Luo, Shiyou Wu, Cindy Weng, Mo Zhou, Rong Ge]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[统计月读（2023 年 2 月）]]></title>
        <id>https://cosx.org/2023/03/monthly/</id>
        <link href="https://cosx.org/2023/03/monthly/"/>
        <updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[推荐语：Gurobi是由美国 Gurobi Optimization 公司开发新一代大规模优化器，能够处理很多优化问题，充分利用多核处理器优势，且支持并行计算。这篇博客提供了如何]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>统计之都</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[snapshot of Les Diablerets³ [jatp]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52249</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/03/01/snapshot-of-les-diablerets%c2%b3-jatp/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T23:23:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Datasets at your fingertips in Google Search]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/datasets-at-your-fingertips-in-google.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/datasets-at-your-fingertips-in-google.html"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T22:13:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Natasha Noy, Research Scientist, and Omar Benjelloun, Software Engineer, Google Research  
Access to datasets is critical to many of today's endeavors across verticals and industries, whether scientific research, business analysis, or public policy. In the scientific community and throughout various levels of the public sector, reproducibility and transparency are essential for progress, so sharing data is vital. For one example, in the United States a recent new policy requires free and equitable access to outcomes of all federally funded research, including data and statistical information along with publications. 

To facilitate discovery of content with this level of statistical detail and better distill this information from across the web, Google now makes it easier to sear…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Research, 2022 & beyond: Research community engagement]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/google-research-2022-beyond-research.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/google-research-2022-beyond-research.html"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T19:40:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Posted by Leslie Yeh, Director, University Relations    
    

(This is Part 9 in our series of posts covering different topical areas of research at Google. You can find other posts in the series here.)
   

Sharing knowledge is essential to Google’s research philosophy — it accelerates technological progress and expands capabilities community-wide. Solving complex problems requires bringing together diverse minds and resources collaboratively. This can be accomplished through building local and global connections with multidisciplinary experts and impacted communities. In partnership with these stakeholders, we bring our technical leadership, product footprint, and resources to make progress against some of society's greatest opportunities and challenges.   
 We at Google see i…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alef’s Corner: Democracy (Israel, 2023)]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=23914</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/02/28/alefs-corner-democracy-israel-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T16:27:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Democracy in Hebrew is דמוקרטיה represented by the letter “dalet” ד]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alef’s Corner: Democracy (Israel, 2023)]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=23914</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/02/28/alefs-corner-democracy-israel-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T16:27:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Democracy in Hebrew is דמוקרטיה represented by the letter “dalet” ד]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Syllable rhythm in English and Mandarin]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58120</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58120&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=syllable-rhythm-in-english-and-mandarin"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T16:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've always been skeptical of the distinction between "stress-timed" and "syllable-timed" languages, at least as a claim about the phonetic facts of speech timing as opposed to the psychological dimensions of speech production and perception. Syllable durations in all languages vary widely, due to differences in the intrinsic durations of different vowels and consonants, the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[生成扩散模型漫谈（十八）：得分匹配 = 条件得分匹配]]></title>
        <id>https://kexue.fm/archives/9509</id>
        <link href="https://kexue.fm/archives/9509"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T13:23:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[在前面的介绍中，我们多次提及“得分匹配”和“条件得分匹配”，它们是扩散模型、能量模型等经常出现的概念，特别是很多文章直接说扩散模型的训练目标是“得分匹配”，但事实上当前主流的扩散模型如DDPM的...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>苏剑林</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ChatGPT writes VHM]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58111</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58111&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=chatgpt-writes-vhm"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T10:47:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[[This is a guest post by ChatGPT] Write a Language Log blog post by Victor H. Mair Title: "The Wonders of the Chinese Language" As one of the world's oldest and most complex languages, Chinese has captivated linguists and language enthusiasts for centuries. From its unique writing system to its vast vocabulary and intricate grammar, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Empowering Graph Representation Learning with Test-Time Graph
  Transformation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.03561</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.03561"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T07:15:52.573Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wei Jin, Tong Zhao, Jiayuan Ding, Yozen Liu, Jiliang Tang, Neil Shah]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neural networks for learning personality traits from natural language]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.13782</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.13782"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T07:15:52.566Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Giorgia Adorni]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Principled and Efficient Transfer Learning of Deep Models via Neural
  Collapse]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.12206</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.12206"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T07:15:52.526Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Xiao Li, Sheng Liu, Jinxin Zhou, Xinyu Lu, Carlos Fernandez-Granda,
  Zhihui Zhu, Qing Qu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One-Pixel Shortcut: on the Learning Preference of Deep Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.12141</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.12141"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T07:15:52.516Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shutong Wu, Sizhe Chen, Cihang Xie, Xiaolin Huang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[a journal of the plague, sword, and famine year [with avocados]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52168</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/02/28/a-journal-of-the-plague-sword-and-famine-year-with-avocados/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T23:23:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read two books by Alix E. Harrow, A Spindle Splintered and A Mirror Mended, which are modern takes on Sleeping Beauty and Snow White. Rather hilarious for their tone and dry humour, if rather YAs… And Undercover, a novella by Tasmyn Muir. Rather well-build steampunk around a moving city and… zombies. Plus a new volume […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iteration marks and repeaters in ancient Chinese texts]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58102</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58102&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=iteration-marks-and-repeaters-in-ancient-chinese-texts"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T17:49:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let us begin this post with a brief introduction to the 16th-century Hokkien (Minnan) drama, Tale of the Lychee Mirror: The Tale of the Lychee Mirror (traditional Chinese: 荔鏡記; simplified Chinese: 荔镜记; pinyin: Lì jìng jì; Pe̍h-ōe-jī: Nāi-kèng-kì, Lē-kèng-kì) is a play written by an unknown author in the Ming dynasty. Tân Saⁿ and Gō͘-niû […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sample Extraction from RLWE to LWE]]></title>
        <id>https://jeremykun.com/?p=118643</id>
        <link href="https://jeremykun.com/2023/02/27/sample-extraction-from-rlwe-to-lwe/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article I’ll derive a trick used in FHE called sample extraction. In brief, it allows one to partially convert a ciphertext in the Ring Learning With Errors (RLWE) scheme to the Learning With Errors (LWE) scheme. Here are some other articles I’ve written about other FHE building blocks, though they are not prerequisites […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>j2kun</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variational Linearized Laplace Approximation for Bayesian Deep Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12565</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12565"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T07:15:52.156Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Luis A. Ortega, Sim\'on Rodr\'iguez Santana, Daniel Hern\'andez-Lobato]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beyond Moments: Robustly Learning Affine Transformations with
  Asymptotically Optimal Error]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12289</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12289"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T07:15:52.139Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[He Jia, Pravesh K . Kothari, Santosh S. Vempala]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reward Learning as Doubly Nonparametric Bandits: Optimal Design and
  Scaling Laws]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12349</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12349"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T07:15:52.115Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kush Bhatia, Wenshuo Guo, Jacob Steinhardt]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lower Bounds on the Depth of Integral ReLU Neural Networks via Lattice
  Polytopes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12553</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12553"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T07:15:52.109Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Christian Haase, Christoph Hertrich, Georg Loho]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncertainty Injection: A Deep Learning Method for Robust Optimization]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12304</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.12304"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T07:15:52.100Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wei Cui, Wei Yu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diophantine riddle]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52260</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/02/27/diophantine-riddle/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-26T23:23:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The weekly riddle from The Riddler is to find solutions to the Diophantine equation c³-c=b²+4 (when b and c are positive integers). First, forget about ChatGPT since it states this is a Pell equation. With a wrong argument. Second, when running a basic R code, using as.double to handle larger integers, the only solution less […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taiwan Navy recruitment ad language puzzle]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58094</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58094&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=taiwan-navy-recruitment-ad-language-puzzle"/>
        <updated>2023-02-26T20:50:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photo of a Taiwan Naval Academy recruitment ad in the Taipei MRT which references the One Piece ワンピース manga series from Japan: First some basic information about One Piece, then I'll explain what the Chinese says: One Piece (stylized in all caps) is a Japanese manga series written and illustrated by Eiichiro Oda. It has been serialized in Shueisha's shōnen manga magazine […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diversification of Proto-Austronesian]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58099</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58099&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=diversification-of-proto-austronesian"/>
        <updated>2023-02-26T19:53:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Important archeological news from Tainan: South Taiwan park renovation project paused after archaeological artifacts unearthed  Artifact pieces belonging to neolithic Niuchouzi Culture discovered, date back to 3000-4500 years ago. By Stephanie Chiang, Taiwan News (2/26/23) Finds include "orange-colored pottery made of fine sand-bearing rope patterns, polished hoe-axes, polished adze-chisels, and shell mounds." The nature of […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[surveying homelessness]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52284</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/02/26/surveying-homelessness/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-25T23:23:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A recent NYT article, entitled “582,462 and Counting“, is describing how the USA Federal Administation is running a yearly survey of homeless people. By sending agents and volunteers in the streets and shelters to get an idea of the magnitude of the problem. The figure of 582,462 was the one produced by HUD (the US […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transcription vs. transliteration vs. translation in cartography]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58088</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58088&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=transcription-vs-transliteration-vs-translation-in-cartography"/>
        <updated>2023-02-25T03:49:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this post, I wanted to do something that I thought would be fairly simple, viz., address the question of the "rectification" of Russian place names in areas proximate to populations speaking Sinitic languages.  This sort of rectification is also a hot topic where Russia borders on Ukraine.  There, however, the task is simpler, because […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bernard l’Hermite [jatp]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52272</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/02/25/bernard-lhermite-jatp/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T23:23:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A vision-language approach for foundational UI understanding]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/a-vision-language-approach-for.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/a-vision-language-approach-for.html"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T20:21:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Yang Li, Research Scientist, and Gang Li, Software Engineer, Google Research   
The computational understanding of user interfaces (UI) is a key step towards achieving intelligent UI behaviors. Previously, we investigated various UI modeling tasks, including widget captioning, screen summarization, and command grounding, that address diverse interaction scenarios such as automation and accessibility. We also demonstrated how machine learning can help user experience practitioners improve UI quality by diagnosing tappability confusion and providing insights for improving UI design. These works along with those developed by others in the field have showcased how deep neural networks can potentially transform end user experiences and the interaction design practice.  

With these su…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chelsea Finn - Neural networks make stuff up. What should we do about it?]]></title>
        <id>https://mlfoundations.org/talk/finn/</id>
        <link href="https://mlfoundations.org/talk/finn/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When machine learning models are deployed into the world, they inevitably encounter scenarios that differ from their training data, either novel contexts where the appropriate answers may differ or scenarios with new out-of-distribution inputs. Unfortunately, in such situations, deep neural network models make up answers or misunderstand the context, making the models unreliable. Even if a model makes useful predictions for many examples, such unreliability poses considerable risks when these models are interacting with real people and ultimately precludes models from being useful in safety-critical applications. In this talk, I’ll discuss some ways that we might cope with and address the unreliability of neural network models. As an initial coping strategy, I will first discuss a technique for detecting whether some content was generated by a machine learning model, leveraging the probability distribution that the model assigns to different content. Next, I will describe an approach for enabling neural network models to better estimate what they don’t know, such that they can abstain from making predictions on such inputs (i.e. selective classification). I will lastly describe methods for adapting models with small amounts of data to improve their accuracy under distribution shift.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harvard ML Foundations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Words are all you need? Language as an approximation for human
  similarity judgments]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.04105</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.04105"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T07:15:17.364Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Raja Marjieh, Pol van Rijn, Ilia Sucholutsky, Theodore R. Sumers,
  Harin Lee, Thomas L. Griffiths, Nori Jacoby]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bayes meets Bernstein at the Meta Level: an Analysis of Fast Rates in
  Meta-Learning with PAC-Bayes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.11709</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.11709"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T07:15:17.358Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Charles Riou, Pierre Alquier, Badr-Eddine Ch\'erief-Abdellatif]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Find a witness or shatter: the landscape of computable PAC learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.04731</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.04731"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T07:15:17.353Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valentino Delle Rose, Alexander Kozachinskiy, Cristobal Rojas, Tomasz
  Steifer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling Laws For Deep Learning Based Image Reconstruction]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.13435</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.13435"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T07:15:17.347Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tobit Klug, Reinhard Heckel]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Manifold Dimensions with Conditional Variational Autoencoders]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.11756</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.11756"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T07:15:17.265Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yijia Zheng, Tong He, Yixuan Qiu, David Wipf]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Crisis" mentality infects China]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58083</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58083&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=crisis-mentality-infects-china"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T06:52:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From the recent meeting between Putin and Wang Yi (Director of the Office of the Central Foreign Affairs Commission of the Chinese Communist Party): Here is the writing in yellow: Pǔqīn huì Wáng Yì yāo Xí fǎng É, lù pāo “zhèngzhì jiějué wéijī”, Měi bù lè jiàn? 普欽會王毅邀習訪俄，陸拋“政治解決危機”， 美不樂見？ "When Putin met Wang Yi and invited Xi […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[地震越来越频繁了吗？]]></title>
        <id>https://cosx.org/2023/02/earthquake/</id>
        <link href="https://cosx.org/2023/02/earthquake/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[1 写作背景 2 本文结构 3 地震背景信息 4 1973-2022 年全球地震变化 4.1 数据准备 4.2 震次趋势（年度） 4.3 震级分布（总体情况） 4.4 震级分布（按年分组） 4.4.1 抖动图 4.4.2 岭线图]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>统计之都</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The impenetrability of cursive for students from the PRC]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58079</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58079&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-impenetrability-of-cursive-for-students-from-the-prc"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T23:35:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I had a revelation about my handwriting on the blackboard. By far the majority of students in all of my classes come from mainland China.  They are by nature reticent to speak up, but when it comes to engaging in discussion about material that I have written on the board, they are essentially deadly […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[one year of Russian terror]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52311</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/02/24/one-year-under-russian-aggression/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T23:23:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pre-training generalist agents using offline reinforcement learning]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/pre-training-generalist-agents-using.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/pre-training-generalist-agents-using.html"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T21:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Aviral Kumar, Student Researcher, and Sergey Levine, Research Scientist, Google Research    
Reinforcement learning (RL) algorithms can learn skills to solve decision-making tasks like playing games, enabling robots to pick up objects, or even optimizing microchip designs. However, running RL algorithms in the real world requires expensive active data collection. Pre-training on diverse datasets has proven to enable data-efficient fine-tuning for individual downstream tasks in natural language processing (NLP) and vision problems. In the same way that BERT or GPT-3 models provide general-purpose initialization for NLP, large RL–pre-trained models could provide general-purpose initialization for decision-making. So, we ask the question: Can we enable similar pre-training to accele…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Research, 2022 & beyond: Health]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/google-research-2022-beyond-health.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/google-research-2022-beyond-health.html"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T19:01:00.006Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Greg Corrado, Distinguished Scientist, and Yossi Matias, VP Engineering and Research, Google Research    
    

(This is Part 8 in our series of posts covering different topical areas of research at Google. You can find other posts in the series here.)
   

Google’s focus on AI stems from the conviction that this transformational technology will benefit society through its capacity to assist, complement, and empower people in almost every field and sector.  In no area is the magnitude of this opportunity greater than in the spheres of healthcare and medicine.  Commensurate with our mission to demonstrate these societal benefits, Google Research’s programs in applied machine learning (ML) have helped place Alphabet among the top five most impactful corporate research institutions …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vignettes of quality data impoverishment in the world of PRC AI]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58068</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58068&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=vignettes-of-quality-data-impoverishment-in-the-world-of-prc-ai"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T13:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some snippets: Limited data sets a hurdle as China plays catch-up to ChatGPT Lack of high-quality Chinese texts on Internet a barrier to training AI models. Ryan McMorrow, Nian Liu, Eleanor Olcott, and Madhumita Murgia, FT, Ars Technica (2/21/23) … Baidu struggled with its previous attempt at a chatbot, known as Plato, which analysts said […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[生成扩散模型漫谈（十七）：构建ODE的一般步骤（下）]]></title>
        <id>https://kexue.fm/archives/9497</id>
        <link href="https://kexue.fm/archives/9497"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T12:54:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[历史总是惊人地相似。当初笔者在写《生成扩散模型漫谈（十四）：构建ODE的一般步骤（上）》（当时还没有“上”这个后缀）时，以为自己已经搞清楚了构建ODE式扩散的一般步骤，结果读者 @gaohuaz...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>苏剑林</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning nonparametric ordinary differential equations from noisy data]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.15215</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.15215"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T07:15:16.966Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kamel Lahouel, Michael Wells, Victor Rielly, Ethan Lew, David Lovitz,
 , Bruno M. Jedynak]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning from Multiple Sources for Data-to-Text and Text-to-Data]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.11269</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.11269"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T07:15:16.956Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Song Duong, Alberto Lumbreras, Mike Gartrell, Patrick Gallinari]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SGD learning on neural networks: leap complexity and saddle-to-saddle
  dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.11055</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.11055"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T07:15:16.951Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emmanuel Abbe, Enric Boix-Adsera, Theodor Misiakiewicz]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimizing Pessimism in Dynamic Treatment Regimes: A Bayesian Learning
  Approach]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.14420</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.14420"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T07:15:16.921Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yunzhe Zhou, Zhengling Qi, Chengchun Shi, Lexin Li]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drop Edges and Adapt: a Fairness Enforcing Fine-tuning for Graph Neural
  Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.11479</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.11479"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T07:15:16.855Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Indro Spinelli, Riccardo Bianchini, Simone Scardapane]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spaceless pinyin]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58058</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58058&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=spaceless-pinyin"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T01:47:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From the importer's label, carefully placed to obscure the safety instructions (the "do"s and "do not"s) of an electronic gas igniter: I have a feeling that my friend, Mark Swofford, the doyen of rules governing pinyin, will not go for this. Selected readings "Pinyin in practice" (10/13/11) "Pure Pinyin" (10/15/16) "Words in Mandarin: twin kle twin […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multi-modal writing among Hong Kong teens]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58044</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58044&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=multi-modal-writing-among-hong-kong-teens"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T01:44:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Jenny Chu: Knowing your interest in multi-modal writing systems, I thought you might be amused by the attached screencap. It is from a WhatsApp group chat of S6 (final year) students in Hong Kong; one of them is asking the others what they would like to do on the afternoon of their last day […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A crook that protects your belongings]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58026</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58026&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=a-crook-that-protects-your-belongings"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T01:30:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Chinese notice says: Jǐngfāng tíshì:Qǐng tuǒshàn bǎoguǎn nín de xínglǐ wùpǐn, bìng shǐyòng běndiàn wèi nín tígōng de ānquán gōu. 警方提示：请妥善保管您的行李物品，并使用本店为您提供的安全钩。 "A reminder from the police:Please take good care of your luggage and belongings, and use the safety hook provided for you by our store." About twenty years ago, at a table where I […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do not major in the changing room]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=57994</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=57994&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=do-not-major-in-the-changing-room"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T00:56:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Chinese notice says: qǐng wù zài gēngyī shì dà, xiǎobiàn 请勿在更衣室大，小便 "Please do not defecate or urinate in the locker / changing room." Selected readings "Pull!" (11/11/21) — with a lengthy, essential bibliography of posts on urination "Pee straight" (9/5/13) If you do a search on "defecate", "micturate", "poo", and related verbs and nouns, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[snapshot of Les Diablerets² [jatp]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52245</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/02/23/snapshot-of-les-diablerets%c2%b2-jatp/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T23:23:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suppressing quantum errors by scaling a surface code logical qubit]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/suppressing-quantum-errors-by-scaling.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/suppressing-quantum-errors-by-scaling.html"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T16:05:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Hartmut Neven, VP of Engineering, and Julian Kelly, Director of Quantum Hardware, on behalf of the Google Quantum AI Team  
Many years from today, scientists will be able to use fault-tolerant quantum computers for large-scale computations with applications across science and industry. These quantum computers will be much bigger than today, consisting of millions of coherent quantum bits, or qubits. But there’s a catch — these basic building blocks must be good enough or the systems will be overrun with errors. 

Currently, the error rates of the qubits on our 3rd generation Sycamore processor are typically between 1 in 10,000 to 1 in 100. Through our work and that of others, we understand that developing large-scale quantum computers will require far lower error rates. We will n…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valid Inference for Machine Learning Model Parameters]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10840</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10840"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T07:15:27.871Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neil Dey, Jonathan P. Williams]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Local Norms in Exp-concave Statistical Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10726</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10726"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T07:15:27.850Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nikita Puchkin, Nikita Zhivotovskiy]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GDBN: a Graph Neural Network Approach to Dynamic Bayesian Network]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10804</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10804"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T07:15:27.844Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yang Sun, Yifan Xie]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scalable Infomin Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10701</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10701"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T07:15:27.532Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yanzhi Chen, Weihao Sun, Yingzhen Li, Adrian Weller]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep Transformers without Shortcuts: Modifying Self-attention for
  Faithful Signal Propagation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10322</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10322"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T07:15:27.486Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bobby He, James Martens, Guodong Zhang, Aleksandar Botev, Andrew
  Brock, Samuel L Smith, Yee Whye Teh]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Provable Copyright Protection for Generative Models]]></title>
        <id>http://windowsontheory.org/?p=8548</id>
        <link href="https://windowsontheory.org/2023/02/21/provable-copyright-protection-for-generative-models/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T02:22:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[See arxiv link for paper by Nikhil Vyas, Sham Kakade, and me. Conditional generative models hold much promise for novel content creation. Whether it is generating a snippet of code, piece of text, or image, such models can potentially save substantial human effort and unlock new capabilities. But there is a fly in this ointment. … Continue reading Provable Copyright Protection for Generative Models]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Boaz Barak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Provable Copyright Protection for Generative Models]]></title>
        <id>http://windowsontheory.org/?p=8548</id>
        <link href="https://windowsontheory.org/2023/02/21/provable-copyright-protection-for-generative-models/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T02:22:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[See arxiv link for paper by Nikhil Vyas, Sham Kakade, and me. Conditional generative models hold much promise for novel content creation. Whether it is generating a snippet of code, piece of text, or image, such models can potentially save substantial human effort and unlock new capabilities. But there is a fly in this ointment. … Continue reading Provable Copyright Protection for Generative Models]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Boaz Barak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[统计之都访谈第47期：斯坦福大学青椒--雷理骅访谈]]></title>
        <id>https://cosx.org/2023/02/interview-of-lihua-lei/</id>
        <link href="https://cosx.org/2023/02/interview-of-lihua-lei/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[统计之都访谈第47期。2022年8月初，正是北美一年一届的 Joint Statistical Meetings。统计之都在会议间隔对雷理骅进行了采访。在本文发布之际，雷理骅]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>统计之都</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[stops making sense [cover]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52253</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/02/22/stops-making-sense-cover/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-21T23:23:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Research, 2022 & beyond: Natural sciences]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/google-research-2022-beyond-natural.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/google-research-2022-beyond-natural.html"/>
        <updated>2023-02-21T22:16:00.006Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by John Platt, Distinguished Scientist, Google Research    
    

(This is Part 7 in our series of posts covering different topical areas of research at Google. You can find other posts in the series here.)
   

It's an incredibly exciting time to be a scientist. With the amazing advances in machine learning (ML) and quantum computing, we now have powerful new tools that enable us to act on our curiosity, collaborate in new ways, and radically accelerate progress toward breakthrough scientific discoveries. 
Since joining Google Research eight years ago, I’ve had the privilege of being part of a community of talented researchers fascinated by applying cutting-edge computing to push the boundaries of what is possible in applied science. Our teams are exploring topics across the physic…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hardness of Agnostically Learning Halfspaces from Worst-Case Lattice
  Problems]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.14030</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.14030"/>
        <updated>2023-02-21T07:15:27.434Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stefan Tiegel]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do Bayesian Neural Networks Need To Be Fully Stochastic?]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.06291</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.06291"/>
        <updated>2023-02-21T07:15:27.410Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mrinank Sharma, Sebastian Farquhar, Eric Nalisnick, Tom Rainforth]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharp analysis of EM for learning mixtures of pairwise differences]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10066</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.10066"/>
        <updated>2023-02-21T07:15:27.396Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abhishek Dhawan, Cheng Mao, Ashwin Pananjady]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Novel Collaborative Self-Supervised Learning Method for Radiomic Data]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.09807</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.09807"/>
        <updated>2023-02-21T07:15:27.343Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zhiyuan Li, Hailong Li, Anca L. Ralescu, Jonathan R. Dillman, Nehal A.
  Parikh, Lili He]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep learning for inverse problems with unknown operator]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.02744</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.02744"/>
        <updated>2023-02-21T07:15:27.323Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Miguel del Alamo]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Research fellow chAIrs in Grenoble [reposted]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52301</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/02/21/research-fellow-chairs-in-grenoble-reposted/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-20T23:23:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MIAI, the Grenoble Multidisciplinary Institute in Artificial Intelligence , is opening three research fellow chairs in AI reserved to persons who have spent most of their research career outside France. To be eligible, candidates must hold a PhD from a non-French university obtained after January 2014 for male applicants and after 2014-n, where n is […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[03/05 1pm-2pm: CRiSM Seminar]]></title>
        <id>8a1785d88659e0df01866f1c32713ef9</id>
        <link href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/statistics/event_diary/?calendarItem=8a1785d88659e0df01866f1c32713ef8"/>
        <updated>2023-02-20T13:56:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When:
	
  		13:00
		-
		14:00, Wed, 03 May '23

	
Where: MB0.07]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Statistics</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Port-metriplectic neural networks: thermodynamics-informed machine
  learning of complex physical systems]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01873</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.01873"/>
        <updated>2023-02-20T07:15:42.760Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quercus Hern\'andez, Alberto Bad\'ias, Francisco Chinesta, El\'ias
  Cueto]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generative Causal Representation Learning for Out-of-Distribution Motion
  Forecasting]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08635</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08635"/>
        <updated>2023-02-20T07:15:42.717Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shayan Shirahmad Gale Bagi, Zahra Gharaee, Oliver Schulte, Mark
  Crowley]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intrinsic and extrinsic deep learning on manifolds]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08606</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08606"/>
        <updated>2023-02-20T07:15:42.712Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yihao Fang, Ilsang Ohn, Vijay Gupta, Lizhen Lin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PAC-Bayesian Generalization Bounds for Adversarial Generative Models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08942</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08942"/>
        <updated>2023-02-20T07:15:42.696Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sokhna Diarra Mbacke, Florence Clerc, Pascal Germain]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[snapshot of Les Diablerets¹ [jatp]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52240</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/02/20/snapshot-of-les-diablerets-jatp/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-19T23:23:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FRMT: A benchmark for few-shot region-aware machine translation]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/frmt-benchmark-for-few-shot-region.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/frmt-benchmark-for-few-shot-region.html"/>
        <updated>2023-02-17T18:20:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Parker Riley, Software Engineer, and Jan Botha, Research Scientist, Google Research  
Many languages spoken worldwide cover numerous regional varieties (sometimes called dialects), such as Brazilian and European Portuguese or Mainland and Taiwan Mandarin Chinese. Although such varieties are often mutually intelligible to their speakers, there are still important differences. For example, the Brazilian Portuguese word for “bus” is ônibus, while the European Portuguese word is autocarro. Yet, today’s machine translation (MT) systems typically do not allow users to specify which variety of a language to translate into. This may lead to confusion if the system outputs the “wrong” variety or mixes varieties in an unnatural way. Also, region-unaware MT systems tend to favor whichever v…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chatting with Claude]]></title>
        <id>http://windowsontheory.org/?p=8529</id>
        <link href="https://windowsontheory.org/2023/02/17/chatting-with-claude/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-17T16:04:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my previous post I discussed how large language models can be thoughts of as the hero of the movie “memento” – their long-term memory is intact but they have limited context, which can be an issue in retrieving not just facts that happened after the training, but also the relevant facts that did appear … Continue reading Chatting with Claude]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Boaz Barak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chatting with Claude]]></title>
        <id>http://windowsontheory.org/?p=8529</id>
        <link href="https://windowsontheory.org/2023/02/17/chatting-with-claude/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-17T16:04:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my previous post I discussed how large language models can be thoughts of as the hero of the movie “memento” – their long-term memory is intact but they have limited context, which can be an issue in retrieving not just facts that happened after the training, but also the relevant facts that did appear … Continue reading Chatting with Claude]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Boaz Barak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scalable Batch Acquisition for Deep Bayesian Active Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2301.05490</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2301.05490"/>
        <updated>2023-02-17T07:15:20.289Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aleksandr Rubashevskii, Daria Kotova, Maxim Panov]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Learning Theory Beyond Batch Binary Classification]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07409</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07409"/>
        <updated>2023-02-17T07:15:20.246Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Preetham Mohan, Ambuj Tewari]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interpretable Deep Learning Methods for Multiview Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07930</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07930"/>
        <updated>2023-02-17T07:15:19.926Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hengkang Wang, Han Lu, Ju Sun, Sandra E Safo]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aligning Language Models with Preferences through f-divergence
  Minimization]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08215</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08215"/>
        <updated>2023-02-17T07:15:19.920Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dongyoung Go, Tomasz Korbak, Germ\'an Kruszewski, Jos Rozen, Nahyeon
  Ryu, Marc Dymetman]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python's multiprocessing performance problem]]></title>
        <id>https://pythonspeed.com/articles/faster-multiprocessing-pickle/</id>
        <link href="https://pythonspeed.com/articles/faster-multiprocessing-pickle/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Because Python has limited parallelism when using threads, using worker processes is a common way to take advantage of multiple CPU cores.
The multiprocessing module is built-in to the standard library, so it’s frequently used for this purpose.
But while multiple processes let you take advantage of multiple CPUs, moving data between processes can be very slow.
And that can reduce some of the performance benefits of using worker processes.
Let’s see:
Why processes can have performance problems that threads don’t.
A number of ways to work around or deal with this performance overhead.
A bad solution you don’t want to us.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Python⇒Speed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google新搜出的优化器Lion：效率与效果兼得的“训练狮”]]></title>
        <id>https://kexue.fm/archives/9473</id>
        <link href="https://kexue.fm/archives/9473"/>
        <updated>2023-02-16T14:38:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[昨天在Arixv上发现了Google新发的一篇论文《Symbolic Discovery of Optimization Algorithms》，主要是讲自动搜索优化器的，咋看上去没啥意思，因为...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>苏剑林</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficiently Learning Neural Networks: What Assumptions May Suffice?]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07426</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07426"/>
        <updated>2023-02-16T08:21:41.214Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amit Daniely, Nathan Srebro, Gal Vardi]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spatially heterogeneous learning by a deep student machine]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07419</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07419"/>
        <updated>2023-02-16T07:15:32.227Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hajime Yoshino]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cliff-Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07348</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07348"/>
        <updated>2023-02-16T07:15:32.187Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tony T. Wang, Igor Zablotchi, Nir Shavit, Jonathan S. Rosenfeld]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Towards Understanding Ensemble, Knowledge Distillation and
  Self-Distillation in Deep Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.09816</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2012.09816"/>
        <updated>2023-02-16T07:15:32.180Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zeyuan Allen-Zhu, Yuanzhi Li]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved Online Conformal Prediction via Strongly Adaptive Online
  Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07869</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07869"/>
        <updated>2023-02-16T07:15:32.107Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aadyot Bhatnagar, Huan Wang, Caiming Xiong, Yu Bai]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continuous PDE Dynamics Forecasting with Implicit Neural Representations]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.14855</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.14855"/>
        <updated>2023-02-16T07:15:32.079Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yuan Yin, Matthieu Kirchmeyer, Jean-Yves Franceschi, Alain
  Rakotomamonjy, Patrick Gallinari]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FriendlyCore: A novel differentially private aggregation framework]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/friendlycore-novel-differentially.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/friendlycore-novel-differentially.html"/>
        <updated>2023-02-15T18:52:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Haim Kaplan and Yishay Mansour, Research Scientists, Google Research   
Differential privacy (DP) machine learning algorithms protect user data by limiting the effect of each data point on an aggregated output with a mathematical guarantee. Intuitively the guarantee implies that changing a single user’s contribution should not significantly change the output distribution of the DP algorithm. 

However, DP algorithms tend to be less accurate than their non-private counterparts because satisfying DP is a worst-case requirement: one has to add noise to “hide” changes in any potential input point, including "unlikely points’’ that have a significant impact on the aggregation. For example, suppose we want to privately estimate the average of a dataset, and we know that a sphere of dia…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scalable Bayesian optimization with high-dimensional outputs using
  randomized prior networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07260</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07260"/>
        <updated>2023-02-15T07:15:22.508Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mohamed Aziz Bhouri, Michael Joly, Robert Yu, Soumalya Sarkar
 , Paris Perdikaris]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Near-optimal learning with average H\"older smoothness]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.06005</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.06005"/>
        <updated>2023-02-15T07:15:22.492Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Hanneke, Aryeh Kontorovich, Guy Kornowski]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easy Learning from Label Proportions]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.03115</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.03115"/>
        <updated>2023-02-15T07:15:22.482Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Robert Istvan Busa-Fekete, Heejin Choi, Travis Dick, Claudio Gentile,
  Andres Munoz medina]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interpolation Learning With Minimum Description Length]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07263</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07263"/>
        <updated>2023-02-15T07:15:22.474Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Naren Sarayu Manoj, Nathan Srebro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-stationary Contextual Bandits and Universal Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07186</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07186"/>
        <updated>2023-02-15T07:15:22.450Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moise Blanchard, Steve Hanneke, Patrick Jaillet]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Research, 2022 & beyond: Robotics]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/google-research-2022-beyond-robotics.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/02/google-research-2022-beyond-robotics.html"/>
        <updated>2023-02-14T20:48:00.005Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Kendra Byrne, Senior Product Manager, and Jie Tan, Staff Research Scientist, Robotics at Google    
    

(This is Part 6 in our series of posts covering different topical areas of research at Google. You can find other posts in the series here.)
   

Within our lifetimes, we will see robotic technologies that can help with everyday activities, enhancing human productivity and quality of life. Before robotics can be broadly useful in helping with practical day-to-day tasks in people-centered spaces — spaces designed for people, not machines — they need to be able to safely & competently provide assistance to people. 
 In 2022, we focused on challenges that come with enabling robots to be more helpful to people: 1) allowing robots and humans to communicate more efficiently and nat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Democratizing AI with PyTorch Foundation and ROCm™ support for PyTorch]]></title>
        <id>https://pytorch.org/blog/democratizing-ai-with-pytorch/</id>
        <link href="https://pytorch.org/blog/democratizing-ai-with-pytorch/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-14T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div type="html"/>]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PyTorch Website</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Absolutely Sensational Morning News – Zander Kelley and Raghua Meka proved Behrend-type bounds for 3APs]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=23866</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/02/14/absolutely-sensational-morning-news-zander-kelley-and-raghua-meka-proved-behrend-type-bounds-for-3aps/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-14T07:42:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is the density of a subset of that guarantees that contains a 3-term arithmetic progression? And, more generally, if the density of is what is the minimum number of 3-terms AP that contains? These problems and the more general … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Absolutely Sensational Morning News – Zander Kelley and Raghua Meka proved Behrend-type bounds for 3APs]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=23866</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/02/14/absolutely-sensational-morning-news-zander-kelley-and-raghua-meka-proved-behrend-type-bounds-for-3aps/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-14T07:42:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is the density of a subset of that guarantees that contains a 3-term arithmetic progression? And, more generally, if the density of is what is the minimum number of 3-terms AP that contains? These problems and the more general … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[生成扩散模型漫谈（十六）：W距离 ≤ 得分匹配]]></title>
        <id>https://kexue.fm/archives/9467</id>
        <link href="https://kexue.fm/archives/9467"/>
        <updated>2023-02-14T07:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wasserstein距离（下面简称“W距离”），是基于最优传输思想来度量两个概率分布差异程度的距离函数，笔者之前在《从Wasserstein距离、对偶理论到WGAN》等博文中也做过介绍。对于很...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>苏剑林</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DAG Learning on the Permutahedron]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2301.11898</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2301.11898"/>
        <updated>2023-02-14T07:15:42.457Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valentina Zantedeschi, Luca Franceschi, Jean Kaddour, Matt J. Kusner,
  Vlad Niculae]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variational Bayesian Neural Networks via Resolution of Singularities]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.06035</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.06035"/>
        <updated>2023-02-14T07:15:42.449Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Susan Wei, Edmund Lau]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graph Neural Network-Inspired Kernels for Gaussian Processes in
  Semi-Supervised Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.05828</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.05828"/>
        <updated>2023-02-14T07:15:42.429Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zehao Niu, Mihai Anitescu, Jie Chen]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Rigorous Framework for the Mean Field Limit of Multilayer Neural
  Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.11443</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.11443"/>
        <updated>2023-02-14T07:15:42.400Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Phan-Minh Nguyen, Huy Tuan Pham]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google’s Fully Homomorphic Encryption Compiler — A Primer]]></title>
        <id>https://jeremykun.com/?p=119079</id>
        <link href="https://jeremykun.com/2023/02/13/googles-fully-homomorphic-encryption-compiler-a-primer/"/>
        <updated>2023-02-13T19:34:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in May of 2022 I transferred teams at Google to work on Fully Homomorphic Encryption (newsletter announcement). Since then I’ve been working on a variety of projects in the space, including being the primary maintainer on github.com/google/fully-homomorphic-encryption, which is an open source FHE compiler for C++. This article will be an introduction to how […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>j2kun</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-Resolution Peak Demand Estimation Using Generalized Additive Models
  and Deep Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.03342</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.03342"/>
        <updated>2023-02-13T07:15:35.979Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jonathan Berrisch, Micha{\l} Narajewski, Florian Ziel]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MoreauGrad: Sparse and Robust Interpretation of Neural Networks via
  Moreau Envelope]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.05294</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.05294"/>
        <updated>2023-02-13T07:15:35.565Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jingwei Zhang, Farzan Farnia]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interventional Causal Representation Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.11924</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.11924"/>
        <updated>2023-02-13T07:15:35.551Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kartik Ahuja, Divyat Mahajan, Yixin Wang, Yoshua Bengio]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DNArch: Learning Convolutional Neural Architectures by Backpropagation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.05400</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.05400"/>
        <updated>2023-02-13T07:15:35.538Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[David W. Romero, Neil Zeghidour]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>