<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://Furyton.github.io/misc-feed/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-05-17T05:14:16.821Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://Furyton.github.io/misc-feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://Furyton.github.io/misc-feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Festschift for Sylvia]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=53043</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/17/53043/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-16T22:23:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Sylvia Richardson’s career celebration last Friday, I gave a talk on How many components in a mixture? which was most relevant given Sylvia’s contributions to mixture inference over the years, including her highly influential 1997 Read Paper with Peter Green. The other talks highlighted the many facets of Sylvia to the field and the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using reinforcement learning for dynamic planning in open-ended conversations]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/using-reinforcement-learning-for.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/using-reinforcement-learning-for.html"/>
        <updated>2023-05-16T19:22:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Deborah Cohen, Staff Research Scientist, and Craig Boutilier, Principal Scientist, Google Research




As virtual assistants become ubiquitous, users increasingly interact with them to learn about new topics or obtain recommendations and expect them to deliver capabilities beyond narrow dialogues of one or two turns. Dynamic planning, namely the capability to look ahead and replan based on the flow of the conversation, is an essential ingredient for the making of engaging conversations with the deeper, open-ended interactions that users expect.
 

While large language models (LLMs) are now beating state-of-the-art approaches in many natural language processing benchmarks, they are typically trained to output the next best response, rather than planning ahead, which is required fo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Quid pro crow"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58724</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58724&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=quid-pro-crow"/>
        <updated>2023-05-16T13:42:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In Maria Bartiromo's recent interview with James Comer (R-KY), there's an interesting speech error — "quid pro crow" for "quid pro quo": This being Language Log rather than Making Fun Of Politicians Log, I'm going to start by assuming that this was a slip of the tongue rather than an inadequate command of legal Latin […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CCP scamming with a Taiwanese-like accent]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58702</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58702&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ccp-scamming-with-a-taiwanese-like-accent"/>
        <updated>2023-05-16T11:40:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Topolects matter: Taiwanese buys anti-CCP book, gets scam call from Chinese propagandist: Caller posing as Eslite Bookstore’s ‘marketing department’ tells consumer book content inappropriate By Stephanie Chiang, Taiwan News, Staff Reporter (5/14/23) Before delving into the substance of this report, I should mention that Eslite is a huge, and hugely influential, bookstore in Taiwan. AntC, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guided Deep Kernel Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.09574</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.09574"/>
        <updated>2023-05-16T07:14:20.124Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Idan Achituve, Gal Chechik, Ethan Fetaya]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evaluating Self-Supervised Learning via Risk Decomposition]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.03068</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.03068"/>
        <updated>2023-05-16T07:14:20.117Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yann Dubois, Tatsunori Hashimoto, Percy Liang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Differentiable Neural Networks with RePU Activation: with Applications
  to Score Estimation and Isotonic Regression]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.00608</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.00608"/>
        <updated>2023-05-16T07:14:20.110Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guohao Shen, Yuling Jiao, Yuanyuan Lin, Jian Huang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological Interpretability for Deep-Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.08642</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.08642"/>
        <updated>2023-05-16T07:14:20.072Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adam Spannaus, Heidi A.Hanson, Lynne Penberthy, Georgia Tourassi]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PyTorch Conference 2023: Join us in San Francisco October 16-17]]></title>
        <id>https://pytorch.org/blog/pytorch-conference-2023/</id>
        <link href="https://pytorch.org/blog/pytorch-conference-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-16T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div type="html"/>]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PyTorch Website</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[more [grass]hope]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=53063</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/16/more-grasshope/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-15T22:23:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following my earlier post on the terrible performances of ChatGPT for a grasshopping riddle, Bob Carpenter sent me his interaction with GPT4, using the same entry. Here is the outcome he obtained. The answer is correct, but the reasoning is wrong. GPT4: This is a classic problem of infinite series and expected values in probability […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Larger language models do in-context learning differently]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/larger-language-models-do-in-context.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/larger-language-models-do-in-context.html"/>
        <updated>2023-05-15T20:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Jerry Wei, Student Researcher, and Denny Zhou, Principal Scientist, Google Research




There have recently been tremendous advances in language models, partly because they can perform tasks with strong performance via in-context learning (ICL), a process whereby models are prompted with a few examples of input-label pairs before performing the task on an unseen evaluation example. In general, models’ success at in-context learning is enabled by:
 


Their use of semantic prior knowledge from pre-training to predict labels while following the format of in-context examples (e.g., seeing examples of movie reviews with “positive sentiment” and “negative sentiment” as labels and performing sentiment analysis using prior knowledge).


Learning the input-label mappings in context from …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Consensus and subjectivity of skin tone annotation for ML fairness]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/consensus-and-subjectivity-of-skin-tone_15.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/consensus-and-subjectivity-of-skin-tone_15.html"/>
        <updated>2023-05-15T17:16:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Candice Schumann, Software Engineer, and Gbolahan O. Olanubi, User Experience Researcher, Google Research




Skin tone is an observable characteristic that is subjective, perceived differently by individuals (e.g., depending on their location or culture) and thus is complicated to annotate. That said, the ability to reliably and accurately annotate skin tone is highly important in computer vision. This became apparent in 2018, when the Gender Shades study highlighted that computer vision systems struggled to detect people with darker skin tones, and performed particularly poorly for women with darker skin tones. The study highlights the importance for computer researchers and practitioners to evaluate their technologies across the full range of skin tones and at intersections of…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI Anchorman "@EdisonGPT"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58706</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58706&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ai-anchorman-edisongpt"/>
        <updated>2023-05-15T11:52:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The future of news? 🚨 BREAKING!!! Just when we thought we'd defeated the #CensorshipIndustrialComplex and @TuckerCarlson rose again on @Twitter, @elonmusk appoints #LindaYaccarino as new #TwitterCEO. Can an Executive Chair from the #WEF lead the revolution?#BreakingNews #EdisonThrustwell #WTF pic.twitter.com/uHt7NjCiO6 — Edison Thrustwell (@EdisonGPT) May 12, 2023 That's the first "Edison Thrustwell" tweet that I saw. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sperm whale talk]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58687</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58687&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=sperm-whale-talk"/>
        <updated>2023-05-15T09:04:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Animal communication is not a favorite topic here at Language Log, but according to the following account, one project concerning it seems serious and is being conducted by credible scientists.  Although their claims for its ultimate significance may be inflated, I believe the research they are undertaking is worth considering, especially after hearing the clicks […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scalable Coupling of Deep Learning with Logical Reasoning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.07617</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.07617"/>
        <updated>2023-05-15T07:15:23.838Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marianne Defresne, Sophie Barbe, Thomas Schiex]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aleatoric uncertainty for Errors-in-Variables models in deep regression]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09095</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.09095"/>
        <updated>2023-05-15T07:15:21.022Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[J\"org Martin, Clemens Elster]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[COVID-19 diagnosis by routine blood tests using machine learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.03476</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.03476"/>
        <updated>2023-05-15T07:15:20.992Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matja\v{z} Kukar, Gregor Gun\v{c}ar, Toma\v{z} Vovko, Simon Podnar,
  Peter \v{C}ernel\v{c}, Miran Brvar, Mateja Zalaznik, Mateja Notar, Sa\v{s}o
  Mo\v{s}kon, Marko Notar]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chez Guy**(*)]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52858</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/15/chez-guy/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-14T22:23:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While I rarely enter company sweepstakes and lotteries (and correlatively never win!), I answered a contest from my credit card company around the 2022 Beijing Winter Olympics, and won the prize of having a Chinese dinner cooked at home by a chef, news that I first treated as a spam for being so improbable. The […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Mama ŠČ!"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58691</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58691&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=mama-sc"/>
        <updated>2023-05-14T13:37:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Among the entries in the  2023 Eurovision Song Contest,  there's one of particular linguistic and political interest — from Croatia, Let 3's Mama ŠČ!: [The video of the song's final Eurovision performance is blocked (at least for now) in the U.S. …] The Croatian lyrics and an English translation are available on genius.com, and the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mathematical parking]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58671</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58671&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=mathematical-parking"/>
        <updated>2023-05-14T03:36:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sign on the campus of Zhōngguó kēxué jìshù dàxué 中国科学技术大学 (University of Science and Technology of China) telling people how to park: tíng hǎo chēliàng de hánglièshì 停好车辆的行列式* ("park your vehicles well according to rows and columns")*matrix determinant zuò hǎo xiūyǎng de wéijīfēn 做好修养的微积分* ("cultivate yourself well to gradually accumulate points [i.e., merit]")*calculus Parking according to one's profession. Selected […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[grass hopping on the wrong fgpt]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52986</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/14/grass-hopping-on-the-wrong-fgpt/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-13T22:23:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Checking the R coding abilities of ChatGPT, I entered the latest Riddler puzzle that asks for the expected value of the stationary distribution of a slowing-down random walk over the real line when the N-th jump from x is to x±2-N. Which is ½ since the limiting distribution is uniform over (-1,1). The first proposed […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iowa town names]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58680</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58680&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=iowa-town-names"/>
        <updated>2023-05-13T14:04:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm in Ames, home of Iowa State University.  The next town down the road is Nevada.  What?  Yes, but it's /nəˈveɪdə/ nə-VAY-də, not /nɪˈvædə/ nih-VAD-ə; Spanish: [neˈβaða], and the locals I've met know the difference.  The same thing holds for Madrid, which is on the other side of Ames; it is /ˈmædrɪd/, not /məˈdrɪd/ mə-DRID, Spanish: [maˈðɾið]. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zen again]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58677</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58677&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=zen-again"/>
        <updated>2023-05-13T11:31:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Nancy Friedman: I'm writing about "zen" in brand names and corporate lingo, having been amused by an email from Medium (where I'm a contributing writer) touting the platform's updates as "Project Zen"–a name chosen "because that's our goal: a zen-like reading experience."   I'm not sure I know what a "zen-like reading experience" is […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[operation precisely impossible]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52971</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/13/operation-precisely-impossible/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T22:23:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since the solution to the previous riddle from The Riddler on the maximum of  different terms in the composed operation a∅b∅c∅d∅e∅f depending on the bracketing ordering and the meaning of each ∅ among one of the six elementary operations got posted today as 974,860, I got back to my R code to understand why it […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[F-VLM: Open-vocabulary object detection upon frozen vision and language models]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/f-vlm-open-vocabulary-object-detection.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/f-vlm-open-vocabulary-object-detection.html"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T20:56:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Weicheng Kuo and Anelia Angelova, Research Scientists, Google Research






Detection is a fundamental vision task that aims to localize and recognize objects in an image. However, the data collection process of manually annotating bounding boxes or instance masks is tedious and costly, which limits the modern detection vocabulary size to roughly 1,000 object classes. This is orders of magnitude smaller than the vocabulary people use to describe the visual world and leaves out many categories. Recent vision and language models (VLMs), such as CLIP, have demonstrated improved open-vocabulary visual recognition capabilities through learning from Internet-scale image-text pairs. These VLMs are applied to zero-shot classification using frozen model weights without the need for fine-…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enabling conversational interaction on mobile with LLMs]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/enabling-conversational-interaction-on.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/enabling-conversational-interaction-on.html"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T17:03:00.003Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Bryan Wang, Student Researcher, and Yang Li, Research Scientist, Google Research





Intelligent assistants on mobile devices have significantly advanced language-based interactions for performing simple daily tasks, such as setting a timer or turning on a flashlight. Despite the progress, these assistants still face limitations in supporting conversational interactions in mobile user interfaces (UIs), where many user tasks are performed. For example, they cannot answer a user's question about specific information displayed on a screen. An agent would need to have a computational understanding of graphical user interfaces (GUIs) to achieve such capabilities. 



Prior research has investigated several important technical building blocks to enable conversational interaction with …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yejin Choi - Common Sense: the Dark Matter of Language and Intelligence]]></title>
        <id>https://mlfoundations.org/talk/choi/</id>
        <link href="https://mlfoundations.org/talk/choi/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T14:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scale appears to be the winning recipe in today's leaderboards. And yet, extreme-scale neural models are (un)surprisingly brittle and make errors that are often nonsensical and even counterintuitive. In this talk, I will argue for the importance of knowledge, especially commonsense knowledge, as well as inference-time reasoning algorithms, and demonstrate how smaller models developed in academia can still have an edge over larger industry-scale models, if powered with knowledge and/or reasoning algorithms.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harvard ML Foundations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[-tucky]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58650</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58650&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tucky"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T10:15:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last weekend, I was in Omaha for the annual Berkshire-Hathaway Shareholders Meeting.  Not that I am a shareholder of Berkshire-Hathaway, but simply because I was curious to see two nonagenarian financial wizards hold forth in front of 20,000 enthusiastic fans for a whole day.  I wasn't disappointed, though I must confess that I didn't understand […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transformer升级之路：9、一种全局长度外推的新思路]]></title>
        <id>https://kexue.fm/archives/9603</id>
        <link href="https://kexue.fm/archives/9603"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T09:11:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[说到Transformer无法处理超长序列的原因，大家的第一反应通常都是Self Attention的二次复杂度。但事实上，即便忽略算力限制，常规的Transformer也无法处理超长序列，因为...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>苏剑林</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Risk-limiting Financial Audits via Weighted Sampling without Replacement]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06884</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06884"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T07:13:34.006Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shubhanshu Shekhar, Ziyu Xu, Zachary C. Lipton, Pierre J. Liang,
  Aaditya Ramdas]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Convergence Rates for Learning Linear Operators from Noisy Data]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.12515</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.12515"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T07:13:33.665Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maarten V. de Hoop, Nikola B. Kovachki, Nicholas H. Nelsen, Andrew M.
  Stuart]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neural Fine-Gray: Monotonic neural networks for competing risks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06703</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06703"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T07:13:33.622Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vincent Jeanselme, Chang Ho Yoon, Brian Tom, Jessica Barrett]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalization bounds for neural ordinary differential equations and
  deep residual networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06648</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06648"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T07:13:33.615Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pierre Marion]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Provable Guarantees for Nonlinear Feature Learning in Three-Layer Neural
  Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06986</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06986"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T07:13:33.598Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eshaan Nichani, Alex Damian, Jason D. Lee]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Language Identification: Building an End-to-End AI Solution using PyTorch]]></title>
        <id>https://pytorch.org/blog/language-identification/</id>
        <link href="https://pytorch.org/blog/language-identification/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-12T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Language Identification is the process of identifying the primary language from multiple audio input samples. In natural language processing (NLP), language identification is an important problem and a challenging issue. There are many language-related tasks such as entering text on your phone, finding news articles you enjoy, or discovering answers to questions that you may have. All these tasks are powered by NLP models. To decide which model to invoke at a particular point in time, we must perform language identification.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PyTorch Website</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CIRM, Luminy, 1995]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=53001</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/12/cirm-luminy-1995/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-11T22:23:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mechanism of feature learning in deep fully connected networks and
  kernel machines that recursively learn features]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.13881</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.13881"/>
        <updated>2023-05-11T07:13:57.402Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adityanarayanan Radhakrishnan, Daniel Beaglehole, Parthe Pandit,
  Mikhail Belkin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Penalized deep neural networks estimator with general loss functions
  under weak dependence]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06230</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06230"/>
        <updated>2023-05-11T07:13:57.396Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[William Kengne, Modou Wade]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Modern CNNs to Vision Transformers: Assessing the Performance,
  Robustness, and Classification Strategies of Deep Learning Models in
  Histopathology]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.05044</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2204.05044"/>
        <updated>2023-05-11T07:13:56.982Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maximilian Springenberg, Annika Frommholz, Markus Wenzel, Eva Weicken,
  Jackie Ma, Nils Strodthoff]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Arm Identification in Bandits with Limited Precision Sampling]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06082</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06082"/>
        <updated>2023-05-11T07:13:56.946Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kota Srinivas Reddy, P. N. Karthik, Nikhil Karamchandani and
  Jayakrishnan Nair]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amnon Shashua’s lecture at Reichman University: A Deep Dive into LLMs and their Future Impact.]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=24235</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/05/11/amnon-shashuas-lecture-at-reichman-university-a-deep-dive-into-llms-and-their-future-impact/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-11T05:31:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LLM is the acronym for “large language model” like GPT-3, ChatGPT, GPT-4 etc. Amnon Shashua gave an enlightening clear lecture about the repeated recent breakthroughs for LLM’s and where we stand. Here is the You-Tube link for the lecture (in … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amnon Shashua’s lecture at Reichman University: A Deep Dive into LLMs and their Future Impact.]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=24235</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/05/11/amnon-shashuas-lecture-at-reichman-university-a-deep-dive-into-llms-and-their-future-impact/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-11T05:31:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LLM is the acronym for “large language model” like GPT-3, ChatGPT, GPT-4 etc. Amnon Shashua gave an enlightening clear lecture about the repeated recent breakthroughs for LLM’s and where we stand. Here is the You-Tube link for the lecture (in … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Signs of the phonetics of Moroccan French]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58647</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58647&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=signs-of-the-phonetics-of-moroccan-french"/>
        <updated>2023-05-11T02:36:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[[This is a guest post by Scott Mauldin] I recently visited Marrakesh and was fascinated by the signs that I submit in the attached photographs. Ostensibly these were originally a kind of business sign that artisans and professionals could hang on their businesses or homes to advertise their profession, but they have evolved into something […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clean Up After Your Dog]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58636</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58636&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=clean-up-after-your-dog"/>
        <updated>2023-05-11T02:26:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sign in Hong Kong: fàng gǒu hòu qǐng lìjí qīnglǐ 放狗後請立即清理 "Please clean up immediately after letting your dog out" This is a case where the English and the Chinese both make sense, and the one is a rough approximation of the other, but the English is not an exact translation of the Chinese. Selected […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retraction Watch: Swamp Man Thing]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58652</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58652&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=retraction-watch-swamp-man-thing"/>
        <updated>2023-05-10T23:33:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A recent Dinosaur Comic features a passionate investigation into alleged philosophical plagiarism: The mouseover title: "For my next thought experiment, suppose a man, a super man, gets turned into energy and is widely considered to be the same man, but then one day splits into two energy guys: one red and one blue. WHICH IS […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[back to a correction of the harmonic mean estimator]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52956</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/11/back-to-a-correction-of-the-harmonic-mean-estimator/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-10T22:23:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a 2009 JCGS paper, Peter Lenk proposed a bias correction of the harmonic mean estimator, which is somewhat surprising given that the estimator usually has no variance and hence that its consistency is purely formal, since no speed of convergence can be taken for granted. In particular, the conjugate Normal model serving as a […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building better pangenomes to improve the equity of genomics]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/building-better-pangenomes-to-improve.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/building-better-pangenomes-to-improve.html"/>
        <updated>2023-05-10T15:03:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Andrew Carroll, Product Lead, and Kishwar Shafin, Research Scientist, Genomics






For decades, researchers worked together to assemble a complete copy of the molecular instructions for a human — a map of the human genome. The first draft was finished in 2000, but with several missing pieces.  Even when a complete reference genome was achieved in 2022, their work was not finished. A single reference genome can’t incorporate known genetic variations, such as the variants for the gene determining whether a person has a blood type A, B, AB or O. Furthermore, the reference genome didn’t represent the vast diversity of human ancestries, making it less useful for detecting disease or finding cures for people from some backgrounds than others. For the past three years, we have been pa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scalable Bayesian optimization with high-dimensional outputs using
  randomized prior networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07260</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.07260"/>
        <updated>2023-05-10T07:13:51.801Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mohamed Aziz Bhouri, Michael Joly, Robert Yu, Soumalya Sarkar
 , Paris Perdikaris]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Prospective Approach for Human-to-Human Interaction Recognition from
  Wi-Fi Channel Data using Attention Bidirectional Gated Recurrent Neural
  Network with GUI Application Implementation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.08146</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.08146"/>
        <updated>2023-05-10T07:13:51.796Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Md. Mohi Uddin Khan, Abdullah Bin Shams, Md. Mohsin Sarker Raihan]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A duality framework for generalization analysis of random feature models
  and two-layer neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.05642</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.05642"/>
        <updated>2023-05-10T07:13:51.688Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hongrui Chen, Jihao Long, Lei Wu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proportional Fairness in Federated Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.01666</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.01666"/>
        <updated>2023-05-10T07:13:51.665Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guojun Zhang, Saber Malekmohammadi, Xi Chen, Yaoliang Yu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Development of a Risk-Free COVID-19 Screening Algorithm from Routine
  Blood Tests Using Ensemble Machine Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.05660</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.05660"/>
        <updated>2023-05-10T07:13:51.474Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Md. Mohsin Sarker Raihan, Md. Mohi Uddin Khan, Laboni Akter and
  Abdullah Bin Shams]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[mean simulations]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52944</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/10/mean-simulations/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-09T22:23:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A rather intriguing question on X validated, namely a simulation approach to sampling a bivariate distribution fully specified by one conditional p(x|y) and the symmetric conditional expectation IE[Y|X=x]. The book Conditional Specification of Statistical Models, by Arnold, Castillo and Sarabia, as referenced by and in the question, contains (§7.7) illustrations of such cases. As for […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online Federated Learning via Non-Stationary Detection and Adaptation
  amidst Concept Drift]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.12578</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.12578"/>
        <updated>2023-05-09T07:13:44.771Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bhargav Ganguly, Vaneet Aggarwal]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TabPFN: A Transformer That Solves Small Tabular Classification Problems
  in a Second]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.01848</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.01848"/>
        <updated>2023-05-09T07:13:44.764Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Noah Hollmann, Samuel M\"uller, Katharina Eggensperger, Frank Hutter]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Stochastic Dynamical System via Flow Map Operator]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.03874</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.03874"/>
        <updated>2023-05-09T07:13:44.742Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yuan Chen, Dongbin Xiu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning-Augmented Private Algorithms for Multiple Quantile Release]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.11222</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.11222"/>
        <updated>2023-05-09T07:13:44.735Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mikhail Khodak, Kareem Amin, Travis Dick, Sergei Vassilvitskii]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast parameter estimation of Generalized Extreme Value distribution
  using Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.04341</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.04341"/>
        <updated>2023-05-09T07:13:44.719Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sweta Rai, Alexis Hoffman, Soumendra Lahiri, Douglas W. Nychka,
  Stephan R. Sain, Soutir Bandyopadhyay]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generative AI and AI Product Moats]]></title>
        <id>http://jalammar.github.io/generative-ai-and-ai-product-moats/</id>
        <link href="http://jalammar.github.io/generative-ai-and-ai-product-moats/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here are eight observations I’ve shared recently on the Cohere blog and videos that go over them.: Article: What’s the big deal with Generative AI? Is it the future or the present? Article: AI is Eating The World]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jay Alammar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Europe Day]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52998</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/09/europe-day/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-08T22:23:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Node Representations against Perturbations]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2008.11416</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2008.11416"/>
        <updated>2023-05-08T07:14:23.586Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Xu Chen, Yuangang Pan, Ivor Tsang, Ya Zhang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random Smoothing Regularization in Kernel Gradient Descent Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.03531</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.03531"/>
        <updated>2023-05-08T07:14:23.581Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liang Ding, Tianyang Hu, Jiahang Jiang, Donghao Li, Wenjia Wang, Yuan
  Yao]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recipes for when Physics Fails: Recovering Robust Learning of Physics
  Informed Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.13330</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.13330"/>
        <updated>2023-05-08T07:14:23.576Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chandrajit Bajaj, Luke McLennan, Timothy Andeen, Avik Roy]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sparsifying Bayesian neural networks with latent binary variables and
  normalizing flows]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.03395</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.03395"/>
        <updated>2023-05-08T07:14:23.361Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lars Skaaret-Lund, Geir Storvik, Aliaksandr Hubin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mathematics (mainly combinatorics) related matters: A lot of activity.]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=24215</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/05/08/mathematics-mainly-combinatorics-related-matters-a-lot-of-activity/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-08T06:50:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plan for next weeks blogging There are various things to blog about and let me give a quick preview for the plan for the next few posts. The purpose of this post is to give an impression about the hectic … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mathematics (mainly combinatorics) related matters: A lot of activity.]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=24215</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2023/05/08/mathematics-mainly-combinatorics-related-matters-a-lot-of-activity/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-08T06:50:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plan for next weeks blogging There are various things to blog about and let me give a quick preview for the plan for the next few posts. The purpose of this post is to give an impression about the hectic … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crappy metaphor:  slippers that make you feel like you're stepping on shit]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58630</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58630&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=crappy-metaphor-slippers-that-make-you-feel-like-youre-stepping-on-shit"/>
        <updated>2023-05-08T02:41:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sign on the elevator doors of a Taipei department store: Here's the writing on the sign (romanized transcriptions and parenthetical English translations have been added by me [VHM]): One Boy Atmosphere / Function Jīnéng  qīng lǚ xié xìliè機能 輕旅鞋系列("Function    light travel slippers series") 2F Shèngdà kāimù盛大開幕("Grand Opening") New Opening Dàiyánrén GEmma Wú Yìngjié 代言人 GEmma 吳映潔("Spokesperson […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[book reviews]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52870</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/08/52870/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-07T22:23:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“I believe neither in luck nor in destiny, I trust only the science of probabilities. I have studied mathematical statistics, combinatorial analysis, mass functions, and random variables, and they never have held any surprise for me.” Over the past weeks, I read  both second and third volumes of The Mirror Visitor series, by Christelle Dabos, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TEAR here]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58633</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58633&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tear-here"/>
        <updated>2023-05-07T10:49:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The hotel where I'm staying in Morgantown, West Virginia kindly gave me a complimentary rectangular packet of freshmint toothpaste.  At the top right corner of the packet, there was a dotted, diagonal line with the words "TEAR HERE" printed above it.  Alas, no matter how hard I tried, I could not tear it open. Then […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The automatic computation for SUSY processes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/hep-ph/9503364</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/hep-ph/9503364"/>
        <updated>2023-05-07T07:13:04.429Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Masato Jimbo, Tadashi Kon, Minami-Tateya collaboration]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kimono exhibition]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52915</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/07/kimono-exhibition/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-06T22:23:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taking advantage of the 01 May break and a relatively low density of people in Paris, we went to the Musée du Quai Branly to see a soon to close exhibit on kimonos, with many pieces loaned from Japanese collections, through an exhibit designed by the Victoria and Albert Museum in London. The collection is […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding the Transformer architecture for neural networks]]></title>
        <id>64489047578bbf003dccd8e8</id>
        <link href="https://www.jeremyjordan.me/transformer-architecture/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-06T18:17:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The attention mechanism allows us to merge a variable-length sequence of vectors into a fixed-size context vector. What if we could use this mechanism to entirely replace recurrence for sequential modeling? This blog post covers the Transformer architecture which explores such an approach.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Move out of Missouri"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58624</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58624&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=move-out-of-missouri"/>
        <updated>2023-05-06T10:20:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here I am in the middle of Missouri, Macon, to be exact (not precisely the geographical center, but not very far from it either, and certainly not near the edges of the state), and I still don't know the origins of this authentic Doggyism:  "Move out of Missouri!" As I explained in "How to pronounce […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Napaljarri-wanu Jukurrpa]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52904</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/06/napaljarri-wanu-jukurrpa/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T22:23:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statistical Optimality of Deep Wide Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.02657</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.02657"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T07:13:30.015Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yicheng Li, Zixiong Yu, Guhan Chen, Qian Lin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-linear Functional Modeling using Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2104.09371</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2104.09371"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T07:13:30.009Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aniruddha Rajendra Rao, Matthew Reimherr]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sequential Training of Neural Networks with Gradient Boosting]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1909.12098</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1909.12098"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T07:13:30.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seyedsaman Emami, Gonzalo Mart\'inez-Mu\~noz]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joint Graph Learning and Model Fitting in Laplacian Regularized
  Stratified Models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.02573</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.02573"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T07:13:29.977Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ziheng Cheng, Junzi Zhang, Akshay Agrawal, Stephen Boyd]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AutoML-GPT: Automatic Machine Learning with GPT]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.02499</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.02499"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T07:13:29.971Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shujian Zhang, Chengyue Gong, Lemeng Wu, Xingchao Liu, Mingyuan Zhou]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10/05 11am-12pm: CRiSM Seminar]]></title>
        <id>8a17841b87bcdaa00187eaa431674bef</id>
        <link href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/statistics/event_diary/?calendarItem=8a17841b835b10a4018360b5677a44f9"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T06:40:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When:
	
  		11:00
		-
		12:00, Wed, 10 May '23

	
Where: MB0.07]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Statistics</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[24/05 11am-12pm: CRiSM Seminar]]></title>
        <id>8a17841b87bcdaa00187eaa431674bf0</id>
        <link href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/statistics/event_diary/?calendarItem=8a17841b835b10a4018360b5677a44f9"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T06:40:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When:
	
  		11:00
		-
		12:00, Wed, 24 May '23

	
Where: MB0.07]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Statistics</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[07/06 11am-12pm: CRiSM Seminar]]></title>
        <id>8a17841b87bcdaa00187eaa431674bf1</id>
        <link href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/statistics/event_diary/?calendarItem=8a17841b835b10a4018360b5677a44f9"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T06:40:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When:
	
  		11:00
		-
		12:00, Wed, 07 Jun '23

	
Where: MB0.07]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Statistics</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[21/06 11am-12pm: CRiSM Seminar]]></title>
        <id>8a17841b87bcdaa00187eaa431674bf2</id>
        <link href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/statistics/event_diary/?calendarItem=8a17841b835b10a4018360b5677a44f9"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T06:40:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When:
	
  		11:00
		-
		12:00, Wed, 21 Jun '23

	
Where: MB0.07]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Statistics</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["I don't think it exactly qualifies as language"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58621</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58621&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=i-dont-think-it-exactly-qualifies-as-language"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T04:20:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From 9 Chickweed Lane (4/28/23): (source) Question from Francois Lang, who sent this in:   "Don't agonized screams have semantic or pragmatic content?" Selected readings "More 'screaming and spluttering' from Matthew Engel" (7/21/11) "The emerging science of gendered yelling" (9/5/06)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[如何度量数据的稀疏程度？]]></title>
        <id>https://kexue.fm/archives/9595</id>
        <link href="https://kexue.fm/archives/9595"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T03:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[在机器学习中，我们经常会谈到稀疏性，比如我们经常说注意力矩阵通常是很稀疏的。然而，不知道大家发现没有，我们似乎从没有给出过度量稀疏程度的标准方法。也就是说，以往我们关于稀疏性的讨论，仅仅是直观层...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>苏剑林</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Externally managed environments": when PEP 668 breaks pip]]></title>
        <id>https://pythonspeed.com/articles/externally-managed-environment-pep-668/</id>
        <link href="https://pythonspeed.com/articles/externally-managed-environment-pep-668/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’re on a new version of Linux, you try a pip install, and it errors out, talking about “externally managed environments” and “PEP 668”.
What’s going on?
How do you solve this?
Let’s see:
What the problem looks like, and what causes it.
The places you are likely to encounter it.
A variety of solutions, depending on your use case.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Python⇒Speed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Balto’s genome]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52894</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/05/baltos-genome/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-04T22:23:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MaMMUT: A simple vision-encoder text-decoder architecture for multimodal tasks]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/mammut-simple-vision-encoder-text.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/mammut-simple-vision-encoder-text.html"/>
        <updated>2023-05-04T21:59:00.004Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by AJ Piergiovanni and Anelia Angelova, Research Scientists, Google Research




Vision-language foundational models are built on the premise of a single pre-training followed by subsequent adaptation to multiple downstream tasks. Two main and disjoint training scenarios are popular: a CLIP-style contrastive learning and next-token prediction. Contrastive learning trains the model to predict if image-text pairs correctly match, effectively building visual and text representations for the corresponding image and text inputs, whereas next-token prediction predicts the most likely next text token in a sequence, thus learning to generate text, according to the required task. Contrastive learning enables image-text and text-image retrieval tasks, such as finding the image that best match…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bayesian learning]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52879</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/04/bayesian-learning/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-04T16:01:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“…many well-known learning-algorithms, such as those used in optimization, deep learning, and machine learning in general, can now be derived directly following the above scheme using a single algorithm” The One World ABC webinar today was delivered by Emtiyaz Khan (RIKEN), about the Bayesian Learning Rule, following Khan and Rue 2021 arXival on Bayesian learning. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A survey on online active learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08893</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08893"/>
        <updated>2023-05-04T07:14:32.958Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Davide Cacciarelli, Murat Kulahci]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transferablility of coVariance Neural Networks and Application to
  Interpretable Brain Age Prediction using Anatomical Features]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.01807</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.01807"/>
        <updated>2023-05-04T07:14:32.172Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Saurabh Sihag, Gonzalo Mateos, Corey T. McMillan, Alejandro Ribeiro]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cheap and Deterministic Inference for Deep State-Space Models of
  Interacting Dynamical Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.01773</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.01773"/>
        <updated>2023-05-04T07:14:31.666Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andreas Look, Melih Kandemir, Barbara Rakitsch, Jan Peters]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probabilistic Contrastive Learning Recovers the Correct Aleatoric
  Uncertainty of Ambiguous Inputs]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.02865</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.02865"/>
        <updated>2023-05-04T07:14:31.419Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Kirchhof, Enkelejda Kasneci, Seong Joon Oh]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[fairml: A Statistician's Take on Fair Machine Learning Modelling]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.02009</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.02009"/>
        <updated>2023-05-04T07:14:31.413Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marco Scutari]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Shribe" in Mongolian historiography]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58615</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58615&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=shribe-in-mongolian-historiography"/>
        <updated>2023-05-04T03:58:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A couple of days ago, I was having a conversation with one of my former students at a tea/coffee shop (that's what I call 'em because I don't drink coffee very often, almost never). We were talking about a controversy in Mongolian historiography.  It was a question of whether it is ever suitable to use […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IndoorSim-to-OutdoorReal: Learning to navigate outdoors without any outdoor experience]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/indoorsim-to-outdoorreal-learning-to.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/05/indoorsim-to-outdoorreal-learning-to.html"/>
        <updated>2023-05-03T17:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Joanne Truong, Student Researcher, and Wenhao Yu, Research Scientist, Robotics at Google





Teaching mobile robots to navigate in complex outdoor environments is critical to real-world applications, such as delivery or search and rescue. However, this is also a challenging problem as the robot needs to perceive its surroundings, and then explore to identify feasible paths towards the goal. Another common challenge is that the robot needs to overcome uneven terrains, such as stairs, curbs, or rockbed on a trail, while avoiding obstacles and pedestrians. In our prior work, we investigated the second challenge by teaching a quadruped robot to tackle challenging uneven obstacles and various outdoor terrains. 



In “IndoorSim-to-OutdoorReal: Learning to Navigate Outdoors without an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding the Generalization Ability of Deep Learning Algorithms: A
  Kernelized Renyi's Entropy Perspective]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.01143</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.01143"/>
        <updated>2023-05-03T07:15:02.721Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yuxin Dong, Tieliang Gong, Hong Chen, Chen Li]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-asymptotic estimates for TUSLA algorithm for non-convex learning
  with applications to neural networks with ReLU activation function]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.08649</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.08649"/>
        <updated>2023-05-03T07:15:02.715Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dong-Young Lim, Ariel Neufeld, Sotirios Sabanis, Ying Zhang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Physics between Digital Twins with Low-Fidelity Models and
  Physics-Informed Gaussian Processes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.08201</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.08201"/>
        <updated>2023-05-03T07:15:01.356Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michail Spitieris, Ingelin Steinsland]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noise Injection Node Regularization for Robust Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.15764</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.15764"/>
        <updated>2023-05-03T07:15:01.340Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Noam Levi, Itay M. Bloch, Marat Freytsis, Tomer Volansky]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noise Injection as a Probe of Deep Learning Dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13599</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.13599"/>
        <updated>2023-05-03T07:15:01.333Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Noam Levi, Itay Bloch, Marat Freytsis, Tomer Volansky]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing PyTorch Docathon 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://pytorch.org/blog/announcing-docathon/</id>
        <link href="https://pytorch.org/blog/announcing-docathon/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div type="html"/>]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PyTorch Website</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No paddling]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58604</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58604&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=no-paddling"/>
        <updated>2023-05-03T03:45:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And no dabbling either (see "Selected readings"). Qǐng wù xī shuǐ 請勿嬉水 "Please don't play in the water" The anonymous contributor who took this photograph in Hong Kong and sent it to me remarked:  "I believe it is correct English though." You will also see signs that translate xī shuǐ 嬉水 ("play in the water") as ("frolicking") […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AIxcuse me?!]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52923</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/03/aixcuse-me/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-02T22:23:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The geometric mean rate of return]]></title>
        <id>https://parsiad.ca/blog/2023/the_geometric_mean_rate_of_return/</id>
        <link href="https://parsiad.ca/blog/2023/the_geometric_mean_rate_of_return/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-02T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Consider a horizon of disjoint periods labelled $1$ through $N$. On the entire horizon, an asset with a rate of return $r_n$ on the $n$-th period has a geometric mean rate of return of \begin{equation} \overline{r} = \left( \prod_{n = 1}^N \left(1 + r_n\right) \right)^{1 / N} - 1. \end{equation} Note in particular that \begin{equation} \left(1 + \overline{r}\right)^N = \prod_{n = 1}^N \left(1 + r_n\right). \end{equation} In other words, a hypothetical asset whose rate of return is equal to $\overline{r}$ on all $N$ periods yields the same return (over the horizon) as the original asset.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Parsiad Azimzadeh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncorrelated coordinates in PCA]]></title>
        <id>https://parsiad.ca/blog/2023/uncorrelated_coordinates_in_pca/</id>
        <link href="https://parsiad.ca/blog/2023/uncorrelated_coordinates_in_pca/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-02T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let $X$ be an $N\times p$ real matrix. Let $D$ be a real diagonal matrix, $w$ be a vector of nonnegative weights that sum to one, and \begin{equation} Y=\left(X-\frac{1}{N}ee^{\intercal}X\right)D^{-1}. \end{equation} $Y$ is a demeaned and rescaled version of $X$.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Parsiad Azimzadeh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LAVA: Data Valuation without Pre-Specified Learning Algorithms]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.00054</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.00054"/>
        <updated>2023-05-02T07:13:48.931Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hoang Anh Just, Feiyang Kang, Jiachen T. Wang, Yi Zeng, Myeongseob Ko,
  Ming Jin, Ruoxi Jia]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[POUF: Prompt-oriented unsupervised fine-tuning for large pre-trained
  models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.00350</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.00350"/>
        <updated>2023-05-02T07:13:48.900Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Korawat Tanwisuth, Shujian Zhang, Huangjie Zheng, Pengcheng He,
  Mingyuan Zhou]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Byzantines can also Learn from History: Fall of Centered Clipping in
  Federated Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.09894</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.09894"/>
        <updated>2023-05-02T07:13:48.895Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kerem Ozfatura, Emre Ozfatura, Alptekin Kupcu, Deniz Gunduz]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variational Inference for Bayesian Neural Networks under Model and
  Parameter Uncertainty]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.00934</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.00934"/>
        <updated>2023-05-02T07:13:48.877Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aliaksandr Hubin, Geir Storvik]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accelerated Image Segmentation using PyTorch]]></title>
        <id>https://pytorch.org/blog/accelerated-image-seg/</id>
        <link href="https://pytorch.org/blog/accelerated-image-seg/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-02T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using Intel® Extension for PyTorch to Boost Image Processing Performance]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PyTorch Website</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[a journal of the plague, sword, and famine year]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52802</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/02/a-journal-of-the-plague-sword-and-famine-year-5/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-01T22:23:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read Brent Weeks’ The Way of Shadows, a rather traditional tale of an orphan boy learning assassin’s skills from a master, within a crime guild organisation tolerated by a feudal structure itself ruled by a below-par king, with the usual dilemma between dedication to the (gory and amoral) job and love+friendship+loyalty constraints. Both collide when […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LLMs in education: the historical view]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58613</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58613&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=llms-in-education-the-historical-view"/>
        <updated>2023-05-01T11:37:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Frazz for 4/25/2023: Let's not forget Plato's argument against the use of written language in education (From Phaedrus, in the voice of Socrates quoting Thamus): SOCRATES: At the Egyptian city of Naucratis, there was a famous old god, whose name was Theuth; the bird which is called the Ibis is sacred to him, and he […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A feature selection method based on Shapley values robust to concept
  shift in regression]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.14774</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.14774"/>
        <updated>2023-05-01T07:14:17.709Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Carlos Sebasti\'an, Carlos E. Gonz\'alez-Guill\'en]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minimalistic Unsupervised Learning with the Sparse Manifold Transform]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.15261</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.15261"/>
        <updated>2023-05-01T07:14:17.666Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yubei Chen, Zeyu Yun, Yi Ma, Bruno Olshausen, Yann LeCun]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Learning of Large-Scale Neural Networks Behaves Like Convex
  Optimization]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1903.02140</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1903.02140"/>
        <updated>2023-05-01T07:14:17.661Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hui Jiang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Stable and Scalable Method for Solving Initial Value PDEs with Neural
  Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.14994</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.14994"/>
        <updated>2023-05-01T07:14:17.647Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marc Finzi, Andres Potapczynski, Matthew Choptuik, Andrew Gordon
  Wilson]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Training Neural Networks for Sequential Change-point Detection]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.17312</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.17312"/>
        <updated>2023-05-01T07:14:17.642Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Junghwan Lee, Tingnan Gong, Xiuyuan Cheng, Yao Xie]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google at ICLR 2023]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/google-at-iclr-2023.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/google-at-iclr-2023.html"/>
        <updated>2023-05-01T06:37:00.002Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Catherine Armato, Program Manager, Google




The Eleventh International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR 2023) is being held this week as a hybrid event in Kigali, Rwanda. We are proud to be a Diamond Sponsor of ICLR 2023, a premier conference on deep learning, where Google researchers contribute at all levels. This year we are presenting over 100 papers and are actively involved in organizing and hosting a number of different events, including workshops and interactive sessions.

 

If you’re registered for ICLR 2023, we hope you’ll visit the Google booth to learn more about the exciting work we’re doing across topics spanning representation and reinforcement learning, theory and optimization, social impact, safety and privacy, and applications from generative AI to…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goodbye to Flake8 and PyLint: faster linting with Ruff]]></title>
        <id>https://pythonspeed.com/articles/pylint-flake8-ruff/</id>
        <link href="https://pythonspeed.com/articles/pylint-flake8-ruff/"/>
        <updated>2023-05-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flake8 and PyLint are commonly used, and very useful, linting tools: they can help you find potential bugs and other problems with your code, aka “lints”.
But they can also be slow.
And even if they’re fast on your computer, they may still be slow in your CI system (GitHub Actions, GitLab, or whatever else.)
Happily, there’s a new linter available, Ruff, which is much faster.
And it supports many of the same lints, including those from many of Flake8’s plugins.
In this article we’ll get a sense of why Ruff’s extra linting speed is so useful compared to the alternatives.
Specifically, we’ll cover:
A useful lint that isn’t in standard Flake8.
A speed comparison to Ruff’s implementation (preview: it’s much faster!).
Why seemingly fast linting on your computer might still be slow in CI.
The worst case for Ruff (preview: it’s ridiculously fast).
Why Ruff may not work for you.
A bonus speed-up for linting by changing tox’s configuration.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Python⇒Speed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["The age of Socratic AI"?]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58607</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58607&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-age-of-socratic-ai"/>
        <updated>2023-04-30T23:20:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Or should we call it "Delphic AI"? Alexy Khrabrov suggested both possibilities a few days ago, in "Reasonable AI — the Golden Age of AI Programming": The emerging techniques are all around the way you construct the prompts and also chain them. Effectively, we’re plotting dialogues. I call it the Age of Socratic AI, or […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[a particularly unhelpful graph [about UN Water Conferences]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52648</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/05/01/a-particularly-unhelpful-graph-about-un-water-conferences/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-30T22:23:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 worlds of AI]]></title>
        <id>http://windowsontheory.org/?p=8605</id>
        <link href="https://windowsontheory.org/2023/04/30/5-worlds-of-ai/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-30T21:39:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scott Aaronson and I wrote a post about 5 possible worlds for (the progress of) Artificial Intelligence. See Scott’s blog for the post itself and discussions. The post was, of course, inspired by the classic essay on the 5 worlds of computational complexity by Russell Impagliazzo who will be turning 60 soon – Happy birthday!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Boaz Barak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 worlds of AI]]></title>
        <id>http://windowsontheory.org/?p=8605</id>
        <link href="https://windowsontheory.org/2023/04/30/5-worlds-of-ai/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-30T21:39:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scott Aaronson and I wrote a post about 5 possible worlds for (the progress of) Artificial Intelligence. See Scott’s blog for the post itself and discussions. The post was, of course, inspired by the classic essay on the 5 worlds of computational complexity by Russell Impagliazzo who will be turning 60 soon – Happy birthday!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Boaz Barak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The interplay between Cantonese and Mandarin as an index of sociopolitical tensions in Hong Kong]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58594</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58594&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-interplay-between-cantonese-and-mandarin-as-an-index-of-sociopolitical-tensions-in-hong-kong"/>
        <updated>2023-04-30T11:22:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First it was the British from afar, and now it is the Chinese from the north who are imposing themselves on the people of Hong Kong.  In both cases, the imposition has been not merely political and economic, but has had important cultural and linguistic implications.  Language-wise, under which master have the Hongkongers (also known […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[operation impossible]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52850</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/30/operation-impossible/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-29T22:23:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A riddle from The Riddler on how many different numbers one could at most produce from six initial values and the four basic operations. In other words, how many values could the terms in a∅(b∅{c∅[d∅(e∅f)]}) could take? (With each ∅ being one of the four operations and a,…,f the initial values or a permutation of […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calling Benjamin Lee Whorf]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58597</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58597&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=calling-benjamin-lee-whorf"/>
        <updated>2023-04-29T14:56:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What do a baker, a shepherd, and a drummer have in common? You can add an orchestra conductor, Harry Potter, and a drill sergeant. Hint: this is in French. Answer: A central focus of their lives is one or more baguettes — which in English variously translates as "stick", "wand", "rod", "baton", "staff", "chopstick", "drumstick", […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diabolo:  devil / yo-yo]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58591</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58591&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=diabolo-devil-yo-yo"/>
        <updated>2023-04-29T09:10:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The diabolo, sometimes called a Chinese yo-yo, is a two-headed top controlled by a string manipulated by two sticks, one attached to each end.  It is popular among jugglers. Diabolo, commonly misspelled as diablo, was formerly also known as "the devil on two sticks" (Juggling Wiki). In this post, I am concerned primarily with language […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[jeune fille à la perle [street art]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52487</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/29/jeune-fille-a-la-perle-street-art/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-28T22:23:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Test if the sample mean is statistically significantly different from zero]]></title>
        <id>https://parsiad.ca/blog/2023/test_if_the_sample_mean_is_statistically_significantly_different_from_zero/</id>
        <link href="https://parsiad.ca/blog/2023/test_if_the_sample_mean_is_statistically_significantly_different_from_zero/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-28T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let $X_{1},\ldots,X_{N}$ be IID. The plug-in estimator for the mean is the sample mean $\bar{X}=(X_{1}+\cdots+X_{N})/N$. The standard error of this estimator is $\sqrt{\operatorname{Var}(X_{1})/N}$. Therefore, a normal confidence interval for the mean is $$ \bar{X}\pm c\sqrt{\frac{\operatorname{Var}(X_{1})}{N}}. $$ In short, if we want to test if the mean is statistically significantly different from zero, the number of samples needs to satisfy $$ N&gt;\frac{c^{2}\operatorname{Var}(X_{1})}{\left|\bar{X}\right|^{2}}. $$]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Parsiad Azimzadeh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statistical Learning Theory for Control: A Finite Sample Perspective]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.05423</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.05423"/>
        <updated>2023-04-28T07:14:00.845Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anastasios Tsiamis, Ingvar Ziemann, Nikolai Matni, George J. Pappas]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beyond calibration: estimating the grouping loss of modern neural
  networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16315</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.16315"/>
        <updated>2023-04-28T07:13:54.882Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alexandre Perez-Lebel (SODA), Marine Le Morvan (SODA), Ga\"el
  Varoquaux (SODA)]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interpretable Neural-Symbolic Concept Reasoning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.14068</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.14068"/>
        <updated>2023-04-28T07:13:54.803Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pietro Barbiero, Gabriele Ciravegna, Francesco Giannini, Mateo
  Espinosa Zarlenga, Lucie Charlotte Magister, Alberto Tonda, Pietro Lio',
  Frederic Precioso, Mateja Jamnik, Giuseppe Marra]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DORA: Exploring outlier representations in Deep Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.04530</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.04530"/>
        <updated>2023-04-28T07:13:54.797Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kirill Bykov, Mayukh Deb, Dennis Grinwald, Klaus-Robert M\"uller,
  Marina M.-C. H\"ohne]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Over-Squashing in Message Passing Neural Networks: The Impact of
  Width, Depth, and Topology]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.02941</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.02941"/>
        <updated>2023-04-28T07:13:54.779Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Francesco Di Giovanni, Lorenzo Giusti, Federico Barbero, Giulia Luise,
  Pietro Lio', Michael Bronstein]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[新浪张俊林：大语言模型的涌现能力——现象与解释]]></title>
        <id>https://www.52nlp.cn/?p=13467</id>
        <link href="https://www.52nlp.cn/%e6%96%b0%e6%b5%aa%e5%bc%a0%e4%bf%8a%e6%9e%97%ef%bc%9a%e5%a4%a7%e8%af%ad%e8%a8%80%e6%a8%a1%e5%9e%8b%e7%9a%84%e6%b6%8c%e7%8e%b0%e8%83%bd%e5%8a%9b-%e7%8e%b0%e8%b1%a1%e4%b8%8e%e8%a7%a3"/>
        <updated>2023-04-28T06:22:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[内容来源：ChatGPT 及大模型专题研讨会  分享嘉宾：新浪新技术研发负责人、中国中文信息学会理事 […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>达观数据</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[validated by rigorous peer review with the author’s benefit]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52838</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/28/52838/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-27T22:23:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The other day my co-authors and I received an email addressed to Dear Prof. Hugo Mariva (sic), offering to publish our importance Markov chain paper in the Journal of Pure and Applied Mathematics which is very much likely a predatory journal, given the approximate English of the email, the journal acceptance window, its editorial board, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An ML-based approach to better characterize lung diseases]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/an-ml-based-approach-to-better.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/an-ml-based-approach-to-better.html"/>
        <updated>2023-04-27T20:24:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Babak Behsaz, Software Engineer, and Andrew Carroll, Product Lead, Genomics




The combination of the environment an individual experiences and their genetic predispositions determines the majority of their risk for various diseases. Large national efforts, such as the UK Biobank, have created large, public resources to better understand the links between environment, genetics, and disease. This has the potential to help individuals better understand how to stay healthy, clinicians to treat illnesses, and scientists to develop new medicines.


One challenge in this process is how we make sense of the vast amount of clinical measurements — the UK Biobank has many petabytes of imaging, metabolic tests, and medical records spanning 500,000 individuals. To best use this data, we nee…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laowai (the Old Furriner) trolls the CCP]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58578</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58578&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=laowai-the-old-furriner-trolls-the-ccp"/>
        <updated>2023-04-27T19:47:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Laowai is "an informal term or slang for 'foreigner' and/or non-Chinese national".  One of the tens of thousands of commenters on the above video is the renowned SerpentZA, who teamed up with his partner, the dry, wry Laowhy86, to form the quintessential Laowai China travel and commentarial vloggers of the second decade of the 21st […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generative Causal Representation Learning for Out-of-Distribution Motion
  Forecasting]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08635</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.08635"/>
        <updated>2023-04-27T07:14:20.356Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shayan Shirahmad Gale Bagi, Zahra Gharaee, Oliver Schulte, Mark
  Crowley]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integration of Radiomics and Tumor Biomarkers in Interpretable Machine
  Learning Models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.11177</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.11177"/>
        <updated>2023-04-27T07:14:19.960Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lennart Brocki, Neo Christopher Chung]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plasticity Neural Network Based on Memory Generation, Memory
  Consolidation and Synaptic Strength Rebalance by Current and Memory Brain
  Plasticity and Synapse Formation-to simulate Artificial Brain]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.11740</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.11740"/>
        <updated>2023-04-27T07:14:19.960Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jun-Bo Tao, Bai-Qing Sun, Wei-Dong Zhu, Shi-You Qu, Ling-Kun Chen,
  Jia-Qiang Li, Guo-Qi Li, Chong Wu, Yu Xiong, Jiaxuan Zhou]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One-vs-the-Rest Loss to Focus on Important Samples in Adversarial
  Training]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.10283</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.10283"/>
        <updated>2023-04-27T07:14:19.960Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sekitoshi Kanai, Shin'ya Yamaguchi, Masanori Yamada, Hiroshi
  Takahashi, Kentaro Ohno, Yasutoshi Ida]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kernel Methods are Competitive for Operator Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.13202</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.13202"/>
        <updated>2023-04-27T07:14:19.959Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pau Batlle, Matthieu Darcy, Bamdad Hosseini, Houman Owhadi]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Hidet: A Deep Learning Compiler for Efficient Model Serving]]></title>
        <id>https://pytorch.org/blog/introducing-hidet/</id>
        <link href="https://pytorch.org/blog/introducing-hidet/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-27T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hidet is a powerful deep learning compiler that simplifies the process of implementing high-performing deep learning operators on modern accelerators (e.g., NVIDIA GPUs). With the new feature of torch.compile(...) in PyTorch 2.0, integrating a novel compiler into PyTorch is easier than ever - Hidet now can be used as a torch.compile(...) backend to accelerate PyTorch models, making it an attractive option for PyTorch users who want to improve the inference performance of their models, especially for those who also need to implement extremely optimized custom operators.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PyTorch Website</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DeepMind’s latest research at ICLR 2023]]></title>
        <id>https://www.deepmind.com/blog/deepminds-latest-research-at-iclr-2023</id>
        <link href="https://www.deepmind.com/blog/deepminds-latest-research-at-iclr-2023"/>
        <updated>2023-04-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next week marks the start of the 11th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), taking place 1-5 May in Kigali, Rwanda. This will be the first major artificial intelligence (AI) conference to be hosted in Africa and the first in-person event since the start of the pandemic. Researchers from around the world will gather to share their cutting-edge work in deep learning spanning the fields of AI, statistics and data science, and applications including machine vision, gaming and robotics. We’re proud to support the conference as a Diamond sponsor and DEI champion.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>DeepMind Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[postdoctoral research position]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52863</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/27/postdoctoral-research-position/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-26T22:23:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Through the ERC Synergy grant OCEAN (On intelligenCE And Networks: Synergistic research in Bayesian Statistics, Microeconomics and Computer Sciences), I am seeking one postdoctoral researcher with an interest in Bayesian federated learning, distributed MCMC, approximate Bayesian inference, and data privacy. The project is based at Université Paris Dauphine, on the new PariSanté Campus.  The postdoc will […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robust and efficient medical imaging with self-supervision]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/robust-and-efficient-medical-imaging.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/robust-and-efficient-medical-imaging.html"/>
        <updated>2023-04-26T20:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Shekoofeh Azizi, Senior Research Scientist, and Laura Culp, Senior Research Engineer, Google Research
  
  
  
Despite recent progress in the field of medical artificial intelligence (AI), most existing models are narrow, single-task systems that require large quantities of labeled data to train. Moreover, these models cannot be easily reused in new clinical contexts as they often require the collection, de-identification and annotation of site-specific data for every new deployment environment, which is both laborious and expensive. This problem of data-efficient generalization (a model’s ability to generalize to new settings using minimal new data) continues to be a key translational challenge for medical machine learning (ML) models and has in turn, prevented their broad uptak…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fake F*ck]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58574</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58574&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=fake-fck"/>
        <updated>2023-04-26T13:36:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is also linguistically fascinating because it shows ‘fuck’ being used as a loanword (fake 法克) in Mandarin! The loanword is so entrenched nowadays that it has it‘s own baidupedia entry… 😅 1/ https://t.co/TVxEmev6iA pic.twitter.com/UKBx3CiO26 — Egas Moniz-Bandeira ᠡᡤᠠᠰ ᠮᠣᠨᠢᠰ ᠪᠠᠨᡩ᠋ᠠᠶᠢᠷᠠ (@egasmb) April 25, 2023 Usual LL romanization, transcription, and translation of the Chinese text: […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simplifying Momentum-based Positive-definite Submanifold Optimization
  with Applications to Deep Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.09738</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.09738"/>
        <updated>2023-04-26T07:14:18.633Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wu Lin, Valentin Duruisseaux, Melvin Leok, Frank Nielsen, Mohammad
  Emtiyaz Khan, Mark Schmidt]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Ability of Graph Neural Networks to Model Interactions Between
  Vertices]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.16494</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.16494"/>
        <updated>2023-04-26T07:14:18.577Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Noam Razin, Tom Verbin, Nadav Cohen]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proto-Value Networks: Scaling Representation Learning with Auxiliary
  Tasks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.12567</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.12567"/>
        <updated>2023-04-26T07:14:18.550Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jesse Farebrother, Joshua Greaves, Rishabh Agarwal, Charline Le Lan,
  Ross Goroshin, Pablo Samuel Castro, Marc G. Bellemare]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comparing BERT against traditional machine learning text classification]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2005.13012</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2005.13012"/>
        <updated>2023-04-26T07:14:18.544Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Santiago Gonz\'alez-Carvajal, Eduardo C. Garrido-Merch\'an]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Probability for predicting the performance of feed-forward fully
  connected neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.00841</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2111.00841"/>
        <updated>2023-04-26T07:14:18.539Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reda Chhaibi, Tariq Daouda, Ezechiel Kahn]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[simulated annealing and logistic regression to the max]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52791</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/26/simulated-annealing-and-logistic-regression-to-the-max/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-25T22:23:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Riddler puzzle on the three binary and sequential questions one should ask three players hiding their respective U(0,1) realisation, U, V, and W, to best guess which player holds the largest number, max{U,V,W}. Assuming questions of the type Is U<b¹, &tc., the challenge boils down to selecting seven bounds (one for U, two for […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LayerNAS: Neural Architecture Search in Polynomial Complexity]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/layernas-neural-architecture-search-in.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/layernas-neural-architecture-search-in.html"/>
        <updated>2023-04-25T17:20:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Yicheng Fan and Dana Alon, Software Engineers, Google Research




Every byte and every operation matters when trying to build a faster model, especially if the model is to run on-device. Neural architecture search (NAS) algorithms design sophisticated model architectures by searching through a larger model-space than what is possible manually. Different NAS algorithms, such as MNasNet and TuNAS, have been proposed and have discovered several efficient model architectures, including MobileNetV3, EfficientNet. 

 


Here we present LayerNAS, an approach that reformulates the multi-objective NAS problem within the framework of combinatorial optimization to greatly reduce the complexity, which results in an order of magnitude reduction in the number of model candidates that must be …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comparative dialectology and romanizations for North and South Korea]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58561</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58561&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=comparative-dialectology-and-romanizations-for-north-and-south-korea"/>
        <updated>2023-04-25T10:49:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[[This is a guest post by S. Robert Ramsey] Your Language Log coverage of the North Korean news item was chilling, but pretty much what we've come to expect of that outrageous regime. If ever there was a clearer contrast between the two worlds in conflict, I've never heard of it. South Korea is now […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[注意力和Softmax的两点有趣发现：鲁棒性和信息量]]></title>
        <id>https://kexue.fm/archives/9593</id>
        <link href="https://kexue.fm/archives/9593"/>
        <updated>2023-04-25T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[最近几周笔者一直都在思考注意力机制的相关性质，在这个过程中对注意力及Softmax有了更深刻的理解。在这篇文章中，笔者简单分享其中的两点：1、Softmax注意力天然能够抵御一定的噪声扰动；2、...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>苏剑林</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A theory of representation learning in deep neural networks gives a deep
  generalisation of kernel methods]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.13097</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2108.13097"/>
        <updated>2023-04-25T07:14:05.616Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adam X. Yang, Maxime Robeyns, Edward Milsom, Nandi Schoots, Laurence
  Aitchison]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robust Model Selection and Nearly-Proper Learning for GMMs]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2106.02774</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2106.02774"/>
        <updated>2023-04-25T07:14:05.603Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jerry Li, Allen Liu, Ankur Moitra]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conformal Risk Control]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.02814</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.02814"/>
        <updated>2023-04-25T07:14:05.597Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anastasios N. Angelopoulos, Stephen Bates, Adam Fisch, Lihua
  Lei, Tal Schuster]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Segmentation and Optimal Region Selection of Physiological Signals using
  Deep Neural Networks and Combinatorial Optimization]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.07981</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.07981"/>
        <updated>2023-04-25T07:14:05.592Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jorge Oliveira, Margarida Carvalho, Diogo Marcelo Nogueira, Miguel
  Coimbra]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implicit Bias of Gradient Descent for Mean Squared Error Regression with
  Two-Layer Wide Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.07356</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.07356"/>
        <updated>2023-04-25T07:14:05.568Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hui Jin, Guido Mont\'ufar]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[top off…]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52717</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/25/top-off/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-24T22:23:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Correcting Bayesian Optimization through Bayesian Active Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.11005</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.11005"/>
        <updated>2023-04-24T07:14:24.151Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Carl Hvarfner, Erik Hellsten, Frank Hutter, Luigi Nardi]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implications of sparsity and high triangle density for graph
  representation learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.15277</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.15277"/>
        <updated>2023-04-24T07:14:24.146Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hannah Sansford, Alexander Modell, Nick Whiteley, Patrick
  Rubin-Delanchy]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interpolation property of shallow neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.10552</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.10552"/>
        <updated>2023-04-24T07:14:23.797Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vlad-Raul Constantinescu, Ionel Popescu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Convergence of Message Passing Graph Neural Networks with Generic
  Aggregation On Large Random Graphs]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.11140</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.11140"/>
        <updated>2023-04-24T07:14:23.510Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matthieu Cordonnier, Nicolas Keriven, Nicolas Tremblay, Samuel Vaiter]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Common Misassumption in Online Experiments with Machine Learning
  Models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.10900</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.10900"/>
        <updated>2023-04-24T07:14:23.454Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Olivier Jeunen]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[上海首个大模型产业发展研讨会圆满落幕，众顶尖专家共探大模型产业]]></title>
        <id>https://www.52nlp.cn/?p=13461</id>
        <link href="https://www.52nlp.cn/%e4%b8%8a%e6%b5%b7%e9%a6%96%e4%b8%aa%e5%a4%a7%e6%a8%a1%e5%9e%8b%e4%ba%a7%e4%b8%9a%e5%8f%91%e5%b1%95%e7%a0%94%e8%ae%a8%e4%bc%9a%e5%9c%86%e6%bb%a1%e8%90%bd%e5%b9%95%ef%bc%8c%e4%bc%97%e9%a1%b6%e5%b0%96"/>
        <updated>2023-04-24T06:32:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[4月21日，由上海市数据科学重点实验室携手达观数据、上海浦东软件园联合举办的“大模型产业发展研讨会”圆满落幕。 […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>达观数据</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ChatGPT及大模型专题研讨会在蓉成功举办共探前沿技术与产业发展]]></title>
        <id>https://www.52nlp.cn/?p=13459</id>
        <link href="https://www.52nlp.cn/chatgpt%e5%8f%8a%e5%a4%a7%e6%a8%a1%e5%9e%8b%e4%b8%93%e9%a2%98%e7%a0%94%e8%ae%a8%e4%bc%9a%e5%9c%a8%e8%93%89%e6%88%90%e5%8a%9f%e4%b8%be%e5%8a%9e%e5%85%b1%e6%8e%a2%e5%89%8d%e6%b2%bf%e6%8a%80%e6%9c%af"/>
        <updated>2023-04-24T06:06:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[4月14日，由成都市新经济发展委员会指导，成都市人工智能产业生态联盟主办，达观数据承办，智慧蓉城研究院与趋动科 […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>达观数据</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google at CHI 2023]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/google-at-chi-2023.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/google-at-chi-2023.html"/>
        <updated>2023-04-24T02:26:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Malaya Jules, Program Manager, Google




This week, the Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2023) is being held in Hamburg, Germany. We are proud to be a Hero Sponsor of CHI 2023, a premier conference on human-computer interaction, where Google researchers contribute at all levels. This year we are presenting over 30 papers and are actively involved in organizing and hosting a number of different events across workshops, courses, and interactive sessions.


 


If you’re registered for CHI 2023, we hope you’ll visit the Google booth to learn more about the exciting work across various topics, including language interactions, causal inference, question answering and more. Take a look below to learn more about the Google research being presented at CHI 2023 (Goog…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Japanese book formats]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58534</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58534&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=japanese-book-formats"/>
        <updated>2023-04-24T01:29:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two days ago, a Penn freshman from China gifted me with a small format edition of the Guǐgǔzi 鬼谷子 (Master of Ghost Valley), a text that has long intrigued me. Guiguzi (鬼谷子) is a collection of ancient Chinese texts compiled between the late Warring States period and the end of the Han Dynasty. The work, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How can we build human values into AI?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.deepmind.com/blog/how-can-we-build-human-values-into-ai</id>
        <link href="https://www.deepmind.com/blog/how-can-we-build-human-values-into-ai"/>
        <updated>2023-04-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As artificial intelligence (AI) becomes more powerful and more deeply integrated into our lives, the questions of how it is used and deployed are all the more important. What values guide AI? Whose values are they? And how are they selected?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>DeepMind Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[the Bayesian learning rule [One World ABC’minar, 27 April]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52845</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/24/the-bayesian-learning-rule-one-world-abcminar-27-april/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-23T22:23:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The next One World ABC seminar is taking place (on-line, requiring pre-registration) on 27 April, 9:30am UK time, with Mohammad Emtiyaz Khan (RIKEN-AIP, Tokyo) speaking about the Bayesian learning rule: We show that many machine-learning algorithms are specific instances of a single algorithm called the Bayesian learning rule. The rule, derived from Bayesian principles, yields […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Combinatorial Algorithms for Matching Markets via Nash Bargaining:
  One-Sided, Two-Sided and Non-Bipartite]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2106.02024</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2106.02024"/>
        <updated>2023-04-23T07:12:54.411Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ioannis Panageas, Thorben Tr\"obst, Vijay V. Vazirani]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new kanji for tapioca]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58524</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58524&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=a-new-kanji-for-tapioca"/>
        <updated>2023-04-23T03:33:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Remixed meme: The concocted kanji is 姏 (Unicode U+59CF) with the punctuation marks /。superimposed upon it. I haven't met anyone who knows the underlying character, so it might as well have been made up by the memer. It is composed of nǚ 女 ("female"), Kangxi radical #38, as presumed semantophore on the left and gān 甘 ("sweet"), Kangxi radical #99, as presumed […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[art brut]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52774</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/23/art-brut-89/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-22T22:23:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Seacuterie"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58540</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58540&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=seacuterie"/>
        <updated>2023-04-22T13:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Although Google now has "about 27,700 results" for seacuterie, this word doesn't seem to have made it into any of the standard dictionaries yet. But already in 2017, Fine Dining Lovers announced ("Seacuterie, When Salami Rhymes with 'Sea-lami'") that "today’s latest craze is 'seacuterie'", and went on to survey the gastronomical metaphors involved at greater […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10th international Purdue symposium on Statistics]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52779</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/22/10th-international-purdue-symposium-on-statistics/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-21T22:23:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thrice alas, I was dearly hoping to join the 10th international Purdue symposium on Statistics next June, but due to too many work- and home-front constraints in this period, I had to cancel my participation to this meeting and hence miss a rare opportunity to return for the first time since 1993 to a place […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visual Blocks for ML: Accelerating machine learning prototyping with interactive tools]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/visual-blocks-for-ml-accelerating.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/visual-blocks-for-ml-accelerating.html"/>
        <updated>2023-04-21T19:01:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Ruofei Du, Interactive Perception & Graphics Lead, Google Augmented Reality, and Na Li, Tech Lead Manager, Google CoreML

  


Recent deep learning advances have enabled a plethora of high-performance, real-time multimedia applications based on machine learning (ML), such as human body segmentation for video and teleconferencing, depth estimation for 3D reconstruction, hand and body tracking for interaction, and audio processing for remote communication.



However, developing and iterating on these ML-based multimedia prototypes can be challenging and costly. It usually involves a cross-functional team of ML practitioners who fine-tune the models, evaluate robustness, characterize strengths and weaknesses, inspect performance in the end-use context, and develop the applications.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jamie Morgenstern - Shifts in Distributions and Preferences in Response to Learning]]></title>
        <id>https://mlfoundations.org/talk/morgenstern/</id>
        <link href="https://mlfoundations.org/talk/morgenstern/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-21T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this talk, I'll describe some recent work outlining how distribution shifts are fundamental to working with human-centric data. Some of these shifts come from attempting to "join" datasets gathered in different contexts,  others may be the result of people's preferences affecting which data they provide to which systems, and even more can arise when peoples' preferences themselves are shaped by ML systems' recommendations. Each of these types of shift require different modeling and analysis to more accurately predict the behavior of ML pipelines deployed in a way where they interact repeatedly with people who care about their predictions.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harvard ML Foundations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In North Korea, it's a dire crime to speak like a South Korean]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58531</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58531&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=in-north-korea-its-a-dire-crime-to-speak-like-a-south-korean"/>
        <updated>2023-04-21T12:25:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[But almost everybody does it.  You can barely avoid it.  Especially if you're an athlete. "North Korea sentences 20 young athletes for ‘speaking like South Koreans’" Skaters and skiers were caught on video using banned words while playing a game during training. Jieun Kim, RFA (4/13/23) The first two paragraphs of the article: About 20 […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boundary Graph Neural Networks for 3D Simulations]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2106.11299</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2106.11299"/>
        <updated>2023-04-21T07:14:22.400Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andreas Mayr, Sebastian Lehner, Arno Mayrhofer, Christoph Kloss, Sepp
  Hochreiter, Johannes Brandstetter]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Communication-Efficient Adaptive Federated Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02719</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02719"/>
        <updated>2023-04-21T07:14:22.395Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yujia Wang, Lu Lin, Jinghui Chen]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Narrow One-Hidden-Layer ReLU Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.10524</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.10524"/>
        <updated>2023-04-21T07:14:22.390Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sitan Chen, Zehao Dou, Surbhi Goel, Adam R Klivans, Raghu Meka]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Deep Learning Approach to Analyzing Continuous-Time Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.12128</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.12128"/>
        <updated>2023-04-21T07:14:21.826Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cory Shain, William Schuler]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Manifold Two-Sample Test Study: Integral Probability Metric with
  Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02043</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.02043"/>
        <updated>2023-04-21T07:14:21.821Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jie Wang, Minshuo Chen, Tuo Zhao, Wenjing Liao, Yao Xie]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[powering a probability [a Bernoulli factory tale]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52763</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/21/powering-a-probability-a-bernoulli-factory-tale/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T22:23:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting from an X validated question on finding an unbiased estimator of an integral raised to a non-integer power, I came across a somewhat interesting Bernoulli factory solution! Thanks to Peter Occil’s encyclopedic record of cases, pointing out to Mendo’s (2019) solution for functions of ρ that can be expressed as power series. Like ργ […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recent advances in deep long-horizon forecasting]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/recent-advances-in-deep-long-horizon.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/recent-advances-in-deep-long-horizon.html"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T20:26:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Rajat Sen and Abhimanyu Das, Research Scientists, Google Research




Time-series forecasting is an important research area that is critical to several scientific and industrial applications, like retail supply chain optimization, energy and traffic prediction, and weather forecasting. In retail use cases, for example, it has been observed that improving demand forecasting accuracy can meaningfully reduce inventory costs and increase revenue. 
 

Modern time-series applications can involve forecasting hundreds of thousands of correlated time-series (e.g., demands of different products for a retailer) over long horizons (e.g., a quarter or year away at daily granularity). As such, time-series forecasting models need to satisfy the following key criterias:



Ability to handle auxi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Domaine La [Nouvelle] France]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52440</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/20/domaine-la-nouvelle-france/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T18:20:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shanghainese under attack]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58515</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58515&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=shanghainese-under-attack"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T13:46:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Headline in a Hong Kong Chinese newspaper, Bastille Post 巴士的報 (4/15/23): Shànghǎi Xújiāhuì shūyuàn yìmíng zhī zhēng shìfǒu gǎi yòng Hànyǔ Pīnyīn zhuānjiā hándié 上海徐家匯書院譯名之爭 是否改用漢語拼音專家咁䏲 "Controversy over the transcription of the name of the Xujiahui Library in Shanghai:  should it be changed to Hanyu Pinyin? Expert opinions" Currently the name of this library at […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speech error of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58519</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58519&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=speech-error-of-the-week-2"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T12:53:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rep. Steube (R-Fla.) announces he’s supporting Trump pic.twitter.com/3bL2cBl9z2 — Acyn (@Acyn) April 17, 2023 The context: Your browser does not support the audio element. yeah Rob I wanna thank you for giving me the opportunity to talk about this on your show and I'm happy and honored to endorse Donald J Chump uh for president […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some recent news and posts from Pinyin.info]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58509</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58509&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=some-recent-news-and-posts-from-pinyin-info"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T10:45:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OMG, it’s nougat (4/15/23) — "OMG" borrowed into Mandarin A long post on puns, multiscriptal writing, and the difficulties of Hanzi. Puns piled upon puns. Microsoft Translator and Pinyin (4/15/23) Microsoft's not very good character-to-Pinyin conversion. They have the resources and could surely do better. Japan likely to regulate pronunciations of personal names (4/14/23) — […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Data Driven Sequential Learning Framework to Accelerate and Optimize
  Multi-Objective Manufacturing Decisions]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09278</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09278"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T07:14:16.082Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hamed Khosravi, Taofeeq Olajire, Ahmed Shoyeb Raihan, Imtiaz Ahmed]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalization and Estimation Error Bounds for Model-based Neural
  Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09802</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09802"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T07:14:16.060Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Avner Shultzman, Eyar Azar, Miguel R. D. Rodrigues, Yonina C. Eldar]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statistical inference for transfer learning with high-dimensional
  quantile regression]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.14578</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.14578"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T07:14:15.185Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jiayu Huang, Mingqiu Wang, Yuanshan Wu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loss minimization yields multicalibration for large neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09424</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09424"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T07:14:15.174Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jaros{\l}aw B{\l}asiok, Parikshit Gopalan, Lunjia Hu, Adam Tauman
  Kalai, Preetum Nakkiran]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Convergence of stochastic gradient descent under a local Lajasiewicz
  condition for deep neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09221</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09221"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T07:14:15.163Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jing An, Jianfeng Lu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing Google DeepMind]]></title>
        <id>https://www.deepmind.com/blog/announcing-google-deepmind</id>
        <link href="https://www.deepmind.com/blog/announcing-google-deepmind"/>
        <updated>2023-04-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DeepMind and the Brain team from Google Research will join forces to accelerate progress towards a world in which AI helps solve the biggest challenges facing humanity.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>DeepMind Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Responsible AI at Google Research: Technology, AI, Society and Culture]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/responsible-ai-at-google-research.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/responsible-ai-at-google-research.html"/>
        <updated>2023-04-19T18:12:00.001Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Lauren Wilcox, Senior Staff Research Scientist, on behalf of the Technology, AI, Society and Culture Team




Google sees AI as a foundational and transformational technology, with recent advances in generative AI technologies, such as LaMDA, PaLM, Imagen, Parti, MusicLM, and similar machine learning (ML) models, some of which are now being incorporated into our products. This transformative potential requires us to be responsible not only in how we advance our technology, but also in how we envision which technologies to build, and how we assess the social impact AI and ML-enabled technologies have on the world. This endeavor necessitates fundamental and applied research with an interdisciplinary lens that engages with — and accounts for — the social, cultural, economic, and oth…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The verbal and visual in traditional prosimetric literature]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58483</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58483&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-verbal-and-visual-in-traditional-prosimetric-literature"/>
        <updated>2023-04-19T12:43:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my trilogy of books and dozens of articles about medieval picture storytelling in South, Central, East, and Southeast Asia, I stressed the alternation of sung and spoken passages as performed by the narrator: Tun-huang Popular Narratives (Cambridge University Press, 1983) Painting and Performance:  Chinese Picture Recitation and Its Indian Genesis (University of Hawai'i Press, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interpretable Learning in Multivariate Big Data Analysis for Network
  Monitoring]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1907.02677</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1907.02677"/>
        <updated>2023-04-19T07:14:19.589Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jos\'e Camacho, Katarzyna Wasielewska, Rasmus Bro, David Kotz]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impossibility of Characterizing Distribution Learning -- a simple
  solution to a long-standing problem]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.08712</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.08712"/>
        <updated>2023-04-19T07:14:19.571Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tosca Lechner, Shai-Ben-David]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maximum Likelihood Learning of Unnormalized Models for Simulation-Based
  Inference]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.14756</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.14756"/>
        <updated>2023-04-19T07:14:19.516Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pierre Glaser, Michael Arbel, Samo Hromadka, Arnaud Doucet, Arthur
  Gretton]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neural networks for geospatial data]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09157</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09157"/>
        <updated>2023-04-19T07:14:19.487Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wentao Zhan, Abhirup Datta]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accelerating Large Language Models with Accelerated Transformers]]></title>
        <id>https://pytorch.org/blog/accelerating-large-language-models/</id>
        <link href="https://pytorch.org/blog/accelerating-large-language-models/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-19T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TL;DR. We show how to use Accelerated PyTorch 2.0 Transformers and the newly introduced torch.compile() method to accelerate Large Language Models on the example of nanoGPT, a compact open-source implementation of the GPT model from Andrej Karpathy. Using the new scaled dot product attention operator introduced with Accelerated PT2 Transformers, we select the flash_attention custom kernel and achieve faster training time per batch (measured with Nvidia A100 GPUs), going from a ~143ms/batch baseline to ~113 ms/batch. In addition, the enhanced implementation using the SDPA operator offers better numerical stability. Finally, further optimizations are achieved using padded inputs, which when combined with flash attention lead to ~87ms/batch.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PyTorch Website</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mike Titterington [in memoriam²]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52832</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/19/mike-titterington-in-memoriam%c2%b2/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-18T22:23:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Differentially private heatmaps]]></title>
        <id>http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/differentially-private-heatmaps.html</id>
        <link href="http://ai.googleblog.com/2023/04/differentially-private-heatmaps.html"/>
        <updated>2023-04-18T20:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Badih Ghazi, Staff Research Scientist, and Nachiappan Valliappan, Staff Software Engineer, Google Research






Recently, differential privacy (DP) has emerged as a mathematically robust notion of user privacy for data aggregation and machine learning (ML), with practical deployments including the 2022 US Census and in industry. Over the last few years, we have open-sourced libraries for privacy-preserving analytics and ML and have been constantly enhancing their capabilities. Meanwhile, new algorithms have been developed by the research community for several analytic tasks involving private aggregation of data. 
 

One such important data aggregation method is the heatmap. Heatmaps are popular for visualizing aggregated data in two or more dimensions. They are widely used in ma…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good bad]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58488</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58488&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=good-bad"/>
        <updated>2023-04-18T14:05:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Benito Antonio Martínez Ocasio, known as Bad Bunny, has been big in the media recently, from the first-ever Spanish cover of Time Magazine, to headlining Coachella — against the background of literally millions of pages featuring his fashion choices and his sayings. According to a 2019 All Things Considered piece ("How Bad Bunny Skipped Categories […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open-set learning with augmented category by exploiting unlabeled data
  (Open-LACU)]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2002.01368</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2002.01368"/>
        <updated>2023-04-18T07:14:03.275Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emile R. Engelbrecht, Johan A. du Preez]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zero-Shot Compositional Policy Learning via Language Grounding]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2004.07200</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2004.07200"/>
        <updated>2023-04-18T07:14:03.263Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tianshi Cao, Jingkang Wang, Yining Zhang, Sivabalan Manivasagam]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proof-of-Learning is Currently More Broken Than You Think]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.03567</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.03567"/>
        <updated>2023-04-18T07:14:03.258Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congyu Fang, Hengrui Jia, Anvith Thudi, Mohammad Yaghini, Christopher
  A. Choquette-Choo, Natalie Dullerud, Varun Chandrasekaran, Nicolas Papernot]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Empirical Bregman Divergence for Uncertain Distance
  Representation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.07689</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.07689"/>
        <updated>2023-04-18T07:14:03.253Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zhiyuan Li, Ziru Liu, Anna Zou, Anca L. Ralescu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Active Learning in Bayesian Neural Networks with Balanced Entropy
  Learning Principle]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.14559</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.14559"/>
        <updated>2023-04-18T07:14:03.248Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jae Oh Woo]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fatality-Free Dill Sauce]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58480</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=58480&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=fatality-free-dill-sauce"/>
        <updated>2023-04-18T02:15:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon screenshot from an anonymous contributor: Remarks by the anonymous contributor: I accidentally reached Amazon's USA website when looking for a source for this excellent dill sauce other than visiting Ikea, 35 miles from here. How could this have arisen? Is it random, or is it something to do with the the pot being made of […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ABC with privacy]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=52746</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2023/04/18/abc-with-privacy/"/>
        <updated>2023-04-17T22:23:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I very recently read a  2021 paper by Mijung Park, Margarita Vinaroz, and Wittawat Jitkrittum on running ABC while ensuring data privacy (published in Entropy). “…adding noise to the distance computed on the real observations and pseudo-data suffices the privacy guarantee of the resulting  posterior samples” For ABC tolerance, they use maximum mean discrepancy (MMD) […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>