<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://Furyton.github.io/misc-feed/index.html</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2024-03-10T18:16:29.648Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://Furyton.github.io/misc-feed/index.html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://Furyton.github.io/misc-feed/feed.atom"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[La francophonie triomphe]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=63008</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=63008&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=la-francophonie-triomphe"/>
        <updated>2024-03-10T18:01:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[…by virtue of the global spread of English. At least, that's what we can conclude from the click-bait title of a book recently published in France, "La langue anglaise n'existe pas". C'est du français mal prononcé (= "The English language doesn't exist". It's badly-pronounced French). The author, Bernard Cerquiglini, has some serious credentials, to which […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["There's no T in Scranton"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62989</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62989&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=theres-no-t-in-scranton"/>
        <updated>2024-03-10T13:55:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[According to Jennifer Bendery, "At 81, Joe Biden Is Still The Last Guy To Leave The Party", Huffington Post 3/8/2024: After his State of the Union speech, the president was so eager to keep talking to people he didn't care that the lights went down or that hot mics picked him up. […] “Thank you, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Famous authors asking you out"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62982</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62982&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=famous-authors-asking-you-out"/>
        <updated>2024-03-10T11:30:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post links to three shorts by @ellecordova — "This is what I think it would be like if famous authors asked you out". The first one features Kurt Vonnegut, Emily Dickinson, Dr. Seuss, Jane Austen, James Joyce, Virginia Woolf, and Ernest Hemingway: In the second one, we get we get Edgar Allen Poe, Agatha […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plastered and potted:  a steinful of drunkonyms]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62973</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62973&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=plastered-and-potted-a-steinful-of-drunkonyms"/>
        <updated>2024-03-10T03:55:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've often wondered why we use such seemingly random, yet colorful, terms to describe a state of drunkenness.  The list of words for drunkenness goes on and on and on: stoned; tipsy; bashed; befuddled; buzzed; crocked; flushed; flying; fuddled; glazed; high; inebriate; inebriated; laced; lit; muddled; plastered; potted; sloshed; stewed; tanked; totaled; wasted; boozed up; […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[computing Bayes, with some approximations]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55234</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/03/10/computing-bayes-with-some-approximations/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-09T23:24:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tabletop Games Based on Math Problems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.jeremykun.com/2024/03/08/tabletop-games-based-on-math-problems/</id>
        <link href="https://www.jeremykun.com/2024/03/08/tabletop-games-based-on-math-problems/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-09T04:06:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a family of tabletop games that are based directly on a nontrivial mathematics problem. As a casual and fun way to inaugurate my new blog (migrated from Wordpress to Hugo, after my work on getting better LaTeX mathmode support in Hugo), I thought I’d write a short listicle about them, so that I have a place to add more as I find them, as well as give the shortest canonical description of the associated math problem.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Math ∩ Programming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[oceanographers in Les Houches]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55485</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/03/09/oceanographers-in-les-houches/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T23:24:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Þe first internal research workshop of our ERC Synergy project OCEAN is taking place in Les Houches, French Alps, this coming week with 15 researchers gathering for brain-storming on some of the themes at the core of the project, like algorithmic tools for multiple decision-making agents, along with Bayesian uncertainty quantification and Bayesian learning under […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health-specific embedding tools for dermatology and pathology]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.research.google/2024/03/health-specific-embedding-tools-for.html</id>
        <link href="http://blog.research.google/2024/03/health-specific-embedding-tools-for.html"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T19:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Dave Steiner, Clinical Research Scientist, Google Health, and Rory Pilgrim, Product Manager Google Research




There’s a worldwide shortage of access to medical imaging expert interpretation across specialties including radiology, dermatology and pathology. Machine learning (ML) technology can help ease this burden by powering tools that enable doctors to interpret these images more accurately and efficiently. However, the development and implementation of such ML tools are often limited by the availability of high-quality data, ML expertise, and computational resources. 



One way to catalyze the use of ML for medical imaging is via domain-specific models that utilize deep learning (DL) to capture the information in medical images as compressed numerical vectors (called embedd…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unnatural audibles]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62905</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62905&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=unnatural-audibles"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T19:21:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm so far behind the times with gadgets and trinkets and services that I have never listened to a single audiobook, and I never even heard of Audible until yesterday when Gene Hill told me that his wife, Marri, listens to tons of Audibles because she writes reviews, and as a result they give her […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Respect the Unstable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/respect-the-unstable</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/respect-the-unstable"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T15:03:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gunter Stein's timeless lessons on the design of decision systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Respect the Unstable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/respect-the-unstable</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/respect-the-unstable"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T15:03:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gunter Stein's timeless lessons on the design of decision systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[English allophonies of the day]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62930</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62930&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=english-allophonies-of-the-day"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T14:37:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My original interest in the conversation behind yesterday's post "Our digital god is a CSV file?" was a sociophonetic one. As often noted, spontaneous speech often strays far from dictionary pronunciations, and Elon Musk's side of that conversation is full of interesting examples. A few are documented below. Let's start with an aspect of this […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[International Women’s Day 2024]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55478</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/03/08/international-womens-day-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T23:24:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Our digital god is a CSV file?"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62887</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62887&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=our-digital-god-is-a-csv-file"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T19:02:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Barry Collins, "The 5 Weirdest Things Elon Musk Told Britain’s Prime Minister About AI", Forbes 11/3/2023: 5. Our New Digital Gods Are Giant Spreadsheets Musk and Sunak spent some time discussing the difficulties of regulating AI and how it differs from other branches of technology. And that led to a rather strange discussion about the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social learning: Collaborative learning with large language models]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.research.google/2024/03/social-learning-collaborative-learning.html</id>
        <link href="http://blog.research.google/2024/03/social-learning-collaborative-learning.html"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Amirkeivan Mohtashami, Research Intern, and Florian Hartmann, Software Engineer, Google Research




Large language models (LLMs) have significantly improved the state of the art for solving tasks specified using natural language, often reaching performance close to that of people. As these models increasingly enable assistive agents, it could be beneficial for them to learn effectively from each other, much like people do in social settings, which would allow LLM-based agents to improve each other’s performance. 

 


To discuss the learning processes of humans, Bandura and Walters described the concept of social learning in 1977, outlining different models of observational learning used by people. One common method of learning from others is through a verbal instruction (e.g., …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pinyin resurgent]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62886</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62886&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pinyin-resurgent"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T17:23:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hopefully. Some exciting news. A member of the PRC's National Committee of the Chinese People's Political Consultative Conference (the yearly meeting of which is taking place in Beijing right now) is urging schools to increase the time spent teaching Pinyin (currently 4-6 weeks) to a semester or even longer to help ensure more students have […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Auto-translated subtitles from auto-generated subtitles]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62874</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62874&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=auto-translated-subtitles-from-auto-generated-subtitles"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T12:08:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mark Metcalf learned something new this Monday morning: YouTube not only provides subtitles, but if the subtitles haven't been created in English, it can generate/translate them on the fly – at least for German. Doesn't seem to be available for Chinese yet. Select 'CC' at the bottom left of the right side of the video […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[用傅立叶级数拟合一维概率密度函数]]></title>
        <id>https://kexue.fm/archives/10007</id>
        <link href="https://kexue.fm/archives/10007"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T04:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[在《“闭门造车”之多模态模型方案浅谈》中我们曾提到，图像生成的本质困难是没有一个连续型概率密度的万能拟合器。当然，也不能说完全没有，比如高斯混合模型（GMM）理论上就是可以拟合任意概率密度，就连...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>苏剑林</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[postdoctoral research positions at PariSanté]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55449</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/03/07/postdoctoral-research-positions/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T23:24:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thanks to the 2023-2029 ERC Synergy grant OCEAN (On intelligenCE And Networks: Synergistic research in Bayesian Statistics, Microeconomics and Computer Sciences), I am seeking one or two postdoctoral researchers with an interest in Bayesian federated learning, distributed MCMC, approximate Bayesian inference and computing, and data privacy. The project is based at Université Paris Dauphine, on the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Croissant: a metadata format for ML-ready datasets]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.research.google/2024/03/croissant-metadata-format-for-ml-ready.html</id>
        <link href="http://blog.research.google/2024/03/croissant-metadata-format-for-ml-ready.html"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T18:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Omar Benjelloun, Software Engineer, Google Research, and Peter Mattson, Software Engineer, Google Core ML and President, MLCommons Association






Machine learning (ML) practitioners looking to reuse existing datasets to train an ML model often spend a lot of time understanding the data, making sense of its organization, or figuring out what subset to use as features. So much time, in fact, that progress in the field of ML is hampered by a fundamental obstacle: the wide variety of data representations. 





ML datasets cover a broad range of content types, from text and structured data to images, audio, and video. Even within datasets that cover the same types of content, every dataset has a unique ad hoc arrangement of files and data formats. This challenge reduces productivi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Past Futures]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62879</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62879&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=past-futures"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T16:10:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From "Lost Futures: A 19th-Century Vision of the Year 2000", The Public Domain Review, 6/30/2012: What did the year 2000 look like in 1900? Originally commissioned by Armand Gervais, a French toy manufacturer in Lyon, for the 1900 World exhibition in Paris, the first fifty of these paper cards were produced by Jean-Marc Côté, designed […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complex Sensitivity Analysis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/complex-sensitivity-analysis</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/complex-sensitivity-analysis"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T15:27:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How frequency domain control highlights robustness and uncertainty quantification.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complex Sensitivity Analysis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/complex-sensitivity-analysis</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/complex-sensitivity-analysis"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T15:27:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How frequency domain control highlights robustness and uncertainty quantification.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unknown language #17]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62844</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62844&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=unknown-language-17"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T14:58:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[https://twitter.com/schrift_sprache/status/1547990826201976834?s=20 I see plenty of kanji and kana, but there are a lot of other things mixed in.  Judging from what the Tweeter / Xer says in the parenthetical remark at the end of his introduction, it probably isn't Japanese.   Selected readings "Reading kanji in cursive script is devilishly difficult" (10/18/22) "'Collapsed' calligraphy, part […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Concoction and elaboration]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62831</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62831&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=concoction-and-elaboration"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T02:53:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Notice in a men's room at National Central University (NCU) in Taoyuan, Taiwan: (source) First of all, let me say that I don't believe this notice gives a true account of something that really happened at NCU, namely, that the male students were peeing upward toward the ceiling.  Below I'll explain what I think really happened. Here […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unknown language #16]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62813</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62813&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=unknown-language-16"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T02:27:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Beverly Kahn: Here's a puzzle that I hope you (or fellow linguists) might solve. My neighbor showed me a wood carving of what is likely an American Indian. It is dated 1907. On the back one finds markings that are like a language. Can you determine what the language is and perhaps what it […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[approximate inference in theory & practice, IHP, Paris, 10-11 June 2024]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55282</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/03/06/approximate-inference-in-theory-practice-ihp-paris-10-11-june-2024/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T23:24:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers from ESSEC and ENSAE are organising a workshop at Institut Henri Poincaré, next June. This workshop will focus on exploring the latest advancements in Approximate Inference methods, with an emphasis on techniques such as Variational Inference and its related approaches. We aim to explore recent breakthroughs in computer science and statistics that enable inference […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lamenting the Laplace transform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/lamenting-the-laplace-transform</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/lamenting-the-laplace-transform"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T15:59:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can we explain feedback well without complex numbers?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lamenting the Laplace transform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/lamenting-the-laplace-transform</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/lamenting-the-laplace-transform"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T15:59:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can we explain feedback well without complex numbers?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The valence of husky voices]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62837</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62837&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-valence-of-husky-voices"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T13:23:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Vocal Fry" has been in the media yet again, thanks to the recent flurry of interest over "TikTalk" (2/16/2024). As mentioned there, and in my 2011 post "Vocal fry: 'creeping in' or 'still here'?", this speaking style (and media interest in it) has always been with us, with a famous fry influencer from olden days […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[IIAS 2024 conference in Kochi [27-31 Dec]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55401</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/03/05/iias-2024-conference-in-kochi-27-31-dec/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T23:24:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The same but different]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/the-same-but-different</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/the-same-but-different"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T15:29:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yet another example of where good predictions still lead to bad outcomes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The same but different]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/the-same-but-different</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/the-same-but-different"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T15:29:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yet another example of where good predictions still lead to bad outcomes.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google at APS 2024]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.research.google/2024/03/google-at-aps-2024.html</id>
        <link href="http://blog.research.google/2024/03/google-at-aps-2024.html"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T15:06:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Kate Weber and Shannon Leon, Google Research, Quantum AI Team




Today the 2024 March Meeting of the American Physical Society (APS) kicks off in Minneapolis, MN. A premier conference on topics ranging across physics and related fields, APS 2024 brings together researchers, students, and industry professionals to share their discoveries and build partnerships with the goal of realizing fundamental advances in physics-related sciences and technology. 



This year, Google has a strong presence at APS with a booth hosted by the Google Quantum AI team, 50+ talks throughout the conference, and participation in conference organizing activities, special sessions and events. Attending APS 2024 in person? Come visit Google’s Quantum AI booth to learn more about the exciting work we’re d…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Major romanization change coming in Japan]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62827</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62827&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=major-romanization-change-coming-in-japan"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T13:10:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Pinyin News (3/4/24):   "Japan to switch official romanization from Kunrei-shiki to Hepburn" Japanese newspapers are reporting that Japan will officially switch from Kunrei-shiki romanization to Hepburn romanization. In a front-page column last week, the Asahi Shimbun said, “A draft report recently published by the Council of Cultural Affairs pointed out that the Hepburn system […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[30,000 deads and counting]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55407</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/03/04/30000-deads-and-counting/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-03T23:24:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boroughing into our subconscious]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62820</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62820&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=boroughing-into-our-subconscious"/>
        <updated>2024-03-03T23:24:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From "Why Does Everyone Hate Nickelback?", Medium 4/15/2021: This was before Netflix, or even taping shows to watch later, so people were being repeatedly told that Nickelback is awful for three years, which boroughed its way into many people’s subconscious. A quick web search didn't turn up any other examples of burrowed spelled "boroughed" — […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artificially unintelligent phishing?]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62816</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62816&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=artificially-unintelligent-phishing"/>
        <updated>2024-03-03T16:27:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have something to add to The Economist's list of "How businesses are actually using generative AI", namely creating phishing messages that are even more implausible than those generated by rooms full of non-native hirelings. A few days ago, I got an email from ParceITrks@intimidatingthebook.com, informing me that "A package awaits your action for rescheduling": […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[That mystifying, baffling Mid-Atlantic / TransAtlantic Accent]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62768</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62768&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=that-mystifying-baffling-mid-atlantic-transatlantic-accent"/>
        <updated>2024-03-03T02:24:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The same as Gideon, the legendary LetThemTalkTV presenter of this edifying video, as a child I too was deeply puzzled by how some of these famous American actors sounded so British. Learn the Transatlantic Accent | Half British, Half American 100% Wonderful Summary The Transatlantic or mid-Atlantic accent is half British half American. It was […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[insufficient Gibbs sampling bridges as well!]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55381</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/03/03/insufficient-gibbs-sampling-bridges-as-well/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-02T23:24:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Antoine Luciano, Robin Ryder and I posted a revised version of our insufficient Gibbs sampler on arXiv last week (along with three other revisions or new deposits of mine’s!), following comments and suggestions from referees. Thanks to this revision, we realised that the evidence based on an (insufficient) statistic was also available for approximation by […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ICYMI: Aptos replaces Calibri]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62796</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62796&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=icymi-aptos-replaces-calibri"/>
        <updated>2024-03-02T18:49:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Victor Mather, "Microsoft Word’s Subtle Typeface Change Affected Millions. Did You Notice?", NYT 2/28/2024: When you read — a book, a traffic sign, a billboard, this article — how much do you really notice the letters? If you’re like most people, the answer is probably not at all. I'm mostly like most people, though there […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spontaneous SCOTUS]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62740</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62740&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=spontaneous-scotus"/>
        <updated>2024-03-02T13:35:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Years ago, Jerry Goldman (then at Northwestern) created the oyez.org website as  a multimedia archive devoted to making the Supreme Court of the United States accessible to everyone. It is the most complete and authoritative source for all of the Court’s audio since the installation of a recording system in October 1955. Oyez offers transcript-synchronized […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Language extinction and language creation]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62737</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62737&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=language-extinction-and-language-creation"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T23:57:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just thought of a (not so) funny phenomenon that amounts to a linguistic paradox.  Namely, as languages die out, one after another, so do they arise at a steady rate. This has been a verity throughout human history.  So inexorable are these trajectories that a clever mathematician might be able to work out an […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[safe Bayes & e-values & least favourable priors]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=54936</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/03/02/safe-bayes-e-values-least-favourable-priors/"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T23:24:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The paper by Peter Grünwald, Rianne de Heide and Wouter Koolen on safe testing was read before The Royal Statistical Society at a meeting organized by the Research Section on Wednesday, 24th January, 2024, after many years in the making, to the point that several papers based on this initial one have appeared in the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Languages nobody speaks"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62746</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62746&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=languages-nobody-speaks"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T13:33:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This recent Donald Trump speech has prompted a lot of discussion on both traditional and social media: Trump: People who don't speak languages. We have languages coming in to our country, nobody that speaks those languages. They're truly foreign languages. Nobody speaks them pic.twitter.com/IzRKM5TOue — Acyn (@Acyn) February 29, 2024 The audio clip, and a […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The voices of GPS and Siri:  not what you think they are]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62704</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62704&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-voices-of-gps-and-siri-not-what-you-think-they-are"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T01:13:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["Meet the Voice Behind Your GPS" 2:40   2/17/23 Meet Karen Jacobsen, a voiceover artist from Queensland Australia, who has one of the most recognisable voices in the world. As the original voice of GPS, she’s helped billions of us to reach our destination. Back in 2002, she recorded more than 50 hours of audio for […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[and it only gets worse [the return?!]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55276</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/03/01/and-it-only-gets-worse-the-return/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T23:24:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“We have to win in November, or we’re not going to have Pennsylvania. They’ll change the name. They’re going to change the name of Pennsylvania,” – DT, 09 Feb “One of the presidents of a big country stood up and said, ‘Well, sir, if we don’t pay, and we’re attacked by Russia, will you protect […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Who's for POONSH?"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62732</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62732&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=whos-for-poonsh"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T22:18:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Samuel Johnson's anti-Scots prejudices are well know, as Wikipedia notes: Although Boswell, a Scotsman, was his close companion and friend, Johnson, like many of his fellow Englishmen, had a reputation for despising Scotland and its people. Even during their journey together through Scotland, Johnson "exhibited prejudice and a narrow nationalism". Hester Thrale, in summarising Johnson's […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Soothing Warmth of Vacuum Tubes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/the-soothing-warmth-of-vacuum-tubes</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/the-soothing-warmth-of-vacuum-tubes"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T16:01:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Going back to the very beginning of feedback to understand its future.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Soothing Warmth of Vacuum Tubes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/the-soothing-warmth-of-vacuum-tubes</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/the-soothing-warmth-of-vacuum-tubes"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T16:01:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Going back to the very beginning of feedback to understand its future.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Emote Portrait Alive"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62710</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62710&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=emote-portrait-alive"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T11:40:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[EMO, by Linrui Tian, Qi Wang, Bang Zhang, and Liefeng Bo from Alibaba's Institute for Intelligent Computing, is "an expressive audio-driven portrait-video generation framework. Input a single reference image and the vocal audio, e.g. talking and singing, our method can generate vocal avatar videos with expressive facial expressions, and various head poses". As far as […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[telescope on evidence for graphical models]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55210</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/29/telescope-on-evidence-for-graphical-models/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T23:24:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A recent paper on evidence by Anindya Bhadra, Ksheera Sagar, Sayantan Banerjee (whom I met during Rito’s seminar, since he was also visiting Ismael in Paris, and who mentioned this work), and Jyotishka Datta, on computing the evidence for graphical models. Obtaining an approximation of the evidence attached with a model and a prior on […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Video Game Decoding Ancient Languages]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62698</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62698&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=a-video-game-decoding-ancient-languages"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T01:12:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Xinyi Ye, who sent this to me, thought the idea of multiple languages and the Tower of Babel in a game would be quite cliché, but this one is actually good.  You will be surprised at what you see and hear. This is the official trailer:    This is a full game video (spoiler alert!).  […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The paradox of diffusion distillation]]></title>
        <id>https://sander.ai/2024/02/28/paradox.html</id>
        <link href="https://sander.ai/2024/02/28/paradox.html"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on the tension between iterative refinement as the thing that makes diffusion models work, and our continual attempts to make it _less_ iterative.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sander Dieleman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[a journal of the conquest, war, famine, death, and chaos year]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55086</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/28/a-journal-of-the-conquest-war-famine-death-and-chaos-year-2/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T23:24:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read (in French) L’Anomalie (2020 Prix Goncourt) with difficulties as the time travel paradox behind the story is extremely shallow and uninteresting, with caricatures of mathematicians and of about any other category in guise of characters. Lazy writing at its worst, floors below a standard Paasilinna. On a whim, decided to read Le Grand Meaulnes […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An arg min mailbag?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/an-arg-min-mailbag</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/an-arg-min-mailbag"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T16:01:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I wanted to take a moment to surface some of the great feedback I’ve received on the current blog series. Though I’ve avoided writing too many equations, I’ve gotten in some academic weeds, and folks are sending me fascinating connections to other work I haven’t discussed yet. Let me pause regularly scheduled programming and share a few of these.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An arg min mailbag?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/an-arg-min-mailbag</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/an-arg-min-mailbag"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T16:01:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I wanted to take a moment to surface some of the great feedback I’ve received on the current blog series. Though I’ve avoided writing too many equations, I’ve gotten in some academic weeds, and folks are sending me fascinating connections to other work I haven’t discussed yet. Let me pause regularly scheduled programming and share a few of these.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Remarkable Quantum Events at the Simons Institute for the Theory of Computing in Berkeley]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=25655</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2024/02/27/three-remarkable-quantum-events-at-the-simons-institute-for-the-theory-of-computing-in-berkeley/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T12:56:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the picture (compare it to this picture in this  post) you can see David DiVincenzo’s famous 7-steps road map (from 2000) to quantum computers, with one additional step “quantum supremacy on NISQ computers” that has proposed around 2010. Step … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Remarkable Quantum Events at the Simons Institute for the Theory of Computing in Berkeley]]></title>
        <id>http://gilkalai.wordpress.com/?p=25655</id>
        <link href="https://gilkalai.wordpress.com/2024/02/27/three-remarkable-quantum-events-at-the-simons-institute-for-the-theory-of-computing-in-berkeley/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T12:56:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the picture (compare it to this picture in this  post) you can see David DiVincenzo’s famous 7-steps road map (from 2000) to quantum computers, with one additional step “quantum supremacy on NISQ computers” that has proposed around 2010. Step … Continue reading →]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gil Kalai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[配置不同的学习率，LoRA还能再涨一点？]]></title>
        <id>https://kexue.fm/archives/10001</id>
        <link href="https://kexue.fm/archives/10001"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T08:46:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LoRA（Low-Rank Adaptation）是当前LLM的参数高效微调手段之一，此前我们在《梯度视角下的LoRA：简介、分析、猜测及推广》也有过简单讨论。这篇文章我们来学习LoRA的一个新...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>苏剑林</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jevons Paradox doesn't always apply to software]]></title>
        <id>https://pythonspeed.com/articles/software-jevons-paradox/</id>
        <link href="https://pythonspeed.com/articles/software-jevons-paradox/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When it comes to fighting climate change, I strongly believe that getting involved in politics is one of the most useful things you can do.
But given how energy-intensive software is these days, writing more efficient software also seems worth doing, especially if your software is used at scale.
However, whenever efficiency is brought up, Jevons Paradox rears its head.
Writing in the 19th century, Jevons pointed out that increased efficiency in the use of coal didn’t decrease the amount of coal used, it actually increased it.
As it became more cost-effective and more useful, coal ended up being used in far more places.
So what about software: will faster software result in more usage, completely undoing the energy-consumption benefits of efficiency?
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Python⇒Speed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[mostly M[ar]C[h]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55368</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/27/mostly-march/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T23:24:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is this authentic Cantonese?]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62681</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62681&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=is-this-authentic-cantonese"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T19:08:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A decade or so ago, we often had discussions about whether or not what was alleged / claimed to be Cantonese writing really was.  Now it is good to see native speakers asking the same questions. From a post of Wan Chin, a controversial scholar/ cultural critic in Hong Kong. The photograph shows a multilingual […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unborn Alabama chickens]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62670</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62670&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=unborn-alabama-chickens"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T19:05:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photograph taken by François Lang at a farm stand run by Painted Hand Farm at the Sunday farm market in Bethesda MD (undoubtedly in response to the recent Alabama Supreme Court opinion that frozen embryos are unborn children). Is this silly? serious? somewhere in between? snide, snotty, satirical? sarcastic? (non)sensical? (in/non)sensitive? In this stream of sibilance, I detect layers of conflicting […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Overgrowin'" in San Francisco?]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62683</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62683&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=overgrowin-in-san-francisco"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T12:09:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From C.B., an exchange in S.F.: This week I heard an unusual usage from a random stranger on the street. I was questioning whether a stairway in the adjacent block – which was not visible from where I was without climbing a steep hill first – had been repaired and could once again be used […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[important and published [Markov chains]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55364</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/26/important-and-published-markov-chains/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-25T23:24:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our importance Markov chain paper (with Charly Andral (PhD, Paris Dauphine), Randal Douc, and Hugo Marival (PhD, Telecom SudParis) has been published (on-line) by stochastic processes and their applications (SPA). Incidentally, my first publication in this journal. To paraphrase its abstract, it sort of bridges the (unsuspected?) gap between rejection sampling and importance sampling, moving […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI writes sinoglyphs]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62610</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62610&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ai-writes-sinoglyphs"/>
        <updated>2024-02-25T18:50:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From Jeff DeMarco: A Chinese friend has been experimenting with AI, the result being guǐzi 鬼子 ("ghost characters"). We’ve seen something similar, but the hànzì 汉字 ("sinoglyph") manipulation is almost artistic. Have you encountered this before? Well, I see a dragon's head in there, appropriate to the season / year.  And I notice strokes and components that I'm familiar with […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AI humor of the day]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62674</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62674&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ai-humor-of-the-day"/>
        <updated>2024-02-25T15:47:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let's start with the last four panels of today's Doonesbury: Then today's Tank McNamara: And we'll close with @ellecordova on Inventions Hanging Out:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[merely fiddlin]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55176</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/25/merely-fiddlin/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-24T23:24:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For any positive, base-10 integer N, define f(N) as the number of times you have to add up its digits until you get a one-digit number. Find the smallest whole number N such that f(N) = 4. Fiddler on the Proof Although I first gave in to the R brute force attempt, it failed to […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thought panzers]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62638</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62638&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=thought-panzers"/>
        <updated>2024-02-24T16:36:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vacillating Chinese terminology for think tanks Mark Metcalf wrote to tell me: Global Times*just ran an article that might be of interest regarding PRC think tanks and a new book related to this topic: “Researchers, scholars explore methods to boost China’s influence of thoughts”. *an appendage of People's Daily I was caught up short by […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Legally binding hallucinations]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62661</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62661&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=legally-binding-hallucinations"/>
        <updated>2024-02-24T12:57:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I missed this story when it happened 10 days ago, and caught up with it yesterday because the BBC also got the word — Maria Yagoda, "Airline held liable for its chatbot giving passenger bad advice – what this means for travellers", BBC 2/23/2024: In 2022, Air Canada's chatbot promised a discount that wasn't available […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[two years of Ukrainian resistance [to be continued]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55217</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/24/two-years-of-ukrainian-resistance-to-be-continued/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T23:22:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All models are wrong, but some are dangerous]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/all-models-are-wrong-but-some-are</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/all-models-are-wrong-but-some-are"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T15:36:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doyle's counterexample and the paradox of prediction in optimal control.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All models are wrong, but some are dangerous]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/all-models-are-wrong-but-some-are</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/all-models-are-wrong-but-some-are"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T15:36:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Doyle's counterexample and the paradox of prediction in optimal control.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Larry Abbott - Modeling the Navigational Circuitry of the Fly]]></title>
        <id>https://mlfoundations.org/talk/abbott/</id>
        <link href="https://mlfoundations.org/talk/abbott/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Navigation requires orienting oneself relative to landmarks in the environment, evaluating relevant sensory data, remembering goals, and convert all this information into motor commands that direct locomotion. I will present models, highly constrained by connectomic, physiological and behavioral data, for how these functions are accomplished in the fly brain.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harvard ML Foundations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["It crosses the i's and dots the t's"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62643</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62643&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=it-crosses-the-is-and-dots-the-ts"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T12:44:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a YouTube video yesterday, Michael Popok explained the differences (in New York State law) among a "verdict", a "decision and order", and a "judgment", in the context of the latest stage of Donald Trump's civil fraud case. Those intricacies are an interesting aspect of the sociolinguistics of the law, but the topic of this […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modals, idiolects, garden-path sentences, and English translations of a ninth-century Chinese poem]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62634</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62634&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=modals-idiolects-garden-path-sentences-and-english-translations-of-a-ninth-century-chinese-poem"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T03:16:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here I present a digest of four scientific linguistics papers from the latter part of the month of January, 2024 to show that our field is very much alive in diverse subfields at the beginning of the new year. "The Semantics, Sociolinguistics, and Origins of Double Modals in American English: New Insights from Social Media." […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hugo[red] Awards 2023]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55026</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/23/hugo-awards-2023/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-22T23:23:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here are the 2023 awards [connected to my read smd to-read lists]. As the votes were made by participants to the 2023 Chengdu Worldcon, Chengdu, China, censorship later came to light, regarding authors critical of the Chinese government, like Kuang, Zhao, and Gaiman, who did not make it to the shortlist… Best Novel Nettle & […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VideoPrism: A foundational visual encoder for video understanding]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.research.google/2024/02/videoprism-foundational-visual-encoder.html</id>
        <link href="http://blog.research.google/2024/02/videoprism-foundational-visual-encoder.html"/>
        <updated>2024-02-22T20:05:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Long Zhao, Senior Research Scientist, and Ting Liu, Senior Staff Software Engineer, Google Research




An astounding number of videos are available on the Web, covering a variety of content from everyday moments people share to historical moments to scientific observations, each of which contains a unique record of the world. The right tools could help researchers analyze these videos, transforming how we understand the world around us.

 

Videos offer dynamic visual content far more rich than static images, capturing movement, changes, and dynamic relationships between entities. Analyzing this complexity, along with the immense diversity of publicly available video data, demands models that go beyond traditional image understanding. Consequently, many of the approaches that be…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What can you do about climate change?]]></title>
        <id>https://pythonspeed.com/articles/climate-change/</id>
        <link href="https://pythonspeed.com/articles/climate-change/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Climate change is impacting the whole planet, and getting worse every year.
So you want to do something—but you’re not sure what.
If you do some research you might encounter an essay by Bret Victor—What can a technologist do about climate change?
There’s a whole pile of good ideas in there, and it’s worth reading, but the short version is that you can use technology to “create options for policy-makers.”
And working on clean energy or efficiency is definitely a great way to spend your time.
Thing is, policy-makers are doing far less than they should.
As a result, this essay isn’t about technology, even though that’s what I mostly write about on this site, because I’m not so certain that technology is the bottleneck right now.
Instead, I’m writing about policy and politics, and what you can do about it.
Keep in mind that my perspective is heavily influenced by living in the US, but the big picture issues are likely universal.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Python⇒Speed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bayesian score calibration at One World ABC’minar [only comes every 1462 days]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55332</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/22/bayesian-score-calibration-at-one-world-abcminar-only-comes-every-1462-days/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T23:29:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ChatGPT having a stroke?]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62616</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62616&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=62616"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T20:35:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ICYMI — Maxwell Zeff, "ChatGPT Went Berserk, Giving Nonsensical Responses All Night", Gizmodo 2/21024: ChatGPT started throwing out “unexpected responses” on Tuesday night according to OpenAI’s status page. Users posted screenshots of their ChatGPT conversations full of wild, nonsensical answers from the AI chatbot. chatgpt is apparently going off the rails right now and no […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advances in private training for production on-device language models]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.research.google/2024/02/advances-in-private-training-for.html</id>
        <link href="http://blog.research.google/2024/02/advances-in-private-training-for.html"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T20:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Zheng Xu, Research Scientist, and Yanxiang Zhang, Software Engineer, Google




Language models (LMs) trained to predict the next word given input text are the key technology for many applications [1, 2]. In Gboard, LMs are used to improve users’ typing experience by supporting features like next word prediction (NWP), Smart Compose, smart completion and suggestion, slide to type, and proofread. Deploying models on users’ devices rather than enterprise servers has advantages like lower latency and better privacy for model usage. While training on-device models directly from user data effectively improves the utility performance for applications such as NWP and smart text selection, protecting the privacy of user data for model training is important. 









Gboard features powe…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Political aspects of teaching Classical Chinese at First Girls High School in Taipei]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62599</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62599&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=political-aspects-of-teaching-classical-chinese-at-first-girls-high-school-in-taipei"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T16:13:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This issue caused quite a hullabaloo more than a month ago and, during the runup to the national election that was going on at that time, it generated a lot of hot rhetoric.  It's important to note that First Girls High School is an elitist, influential institution that is very hard to get into. The debate over […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hurting the feelings of the Chinese people in Tokyo?]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62578</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62578&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=hurting-the-feelings-of-the-chinese-people-in-tokyo"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T16:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sign outside a Tokyo restaurant: (source) According to the Chinese subtitle, it says: Zhōngguó rén jìnzhǐ rùnèi 中國人禁止入内 "Chinese are prohibited from entering" But that's not exactly what the sign really says. According to Nathan Hopson, it reads: チャイナウィルス予防の為 (Chaina wirusu yobō no tame) "To prevent the China virus" 中国人不要㺄入 (Chūgokujin fuyō yunyū, I think) […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gemma: Introducing new state-of-the-art open models]]></title>
        <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/gemma-introducing-new-state-of-the-art-open-models/</id>
        <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/gemma-introducing-new-state-of-the-art-open-models/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T13:06:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gemma is built for responsible AI development from the same research and technology used to create Gemini models.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google DeepMind Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“闭门造车”之多模态模型方案浅谈]]></title>
        <id>https://kexue.fm/archives/9984</id>
        <link href="https://kexue.fm/archives/9984"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T08:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[这篇文章分享一下笔者关于多模态模型架构的一些闭门造车的想法，或者说一些猜测。最近Google的Gemini 1.5和OpenAI的Sora再次点燃了不少人对多模态的热情，只言片语的技术报告也引起...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>苏剑林</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jumbled pinyin]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62565</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62565&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=jumbled-pinyin"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T02:06:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I spotted this not-too-old post on Stephen Jones: a blog, "Interpreting pinyin" (10/9/17). Steve writes: Another irreverent exploration of the wonders of the Chinese language: At least until it caught on as an input method for texting, the pinyin system of transliteration was slow to catch on in China, at least in the countryside. I took this mystifying picture of […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More AI humor]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62557</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62557&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=more-ai-humor"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T01:51:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pearls Before Swine, Feb. 18, 2024:  Maybe AI has finally met its match / media. Can AI do humor / irony / satire / sarcasm? Selected readings "More AI shenanigans" (10/21/23) "ChatGPT has a sense of humor (sort of)" (6/10/23) "Don't joke the monkeys" (10/20/11) "Don't joke the monkeys" (10/20/11) "Chinese language jokes" (6/3/19) "Is irony universal?" (10/22/09) Xiang Li, "A Cross-Cultural Exploration of Situational […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entre ici Missak Manouchian avec ton terrible cortège]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55256</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/21/entre-ici-missak-manouchian-avec-ton-terrible-cortege/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-20T23:24:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Relative clause attachment of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62590</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62590&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=relative-clause-attachment-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2024-02-20T20:32:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fritzi Ritz for 2/19/1946: The Berkeley Neural Parser has the same problem that Sluggo does:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loup du Pic]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=54365</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/20/loup-du-pic/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-20T19:20:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bracing for impact]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/bracing-for-impact</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/bracing-for-impact"/>
        <updated>2024-02-20T15:04:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is the role of uncertainty quantification in feedback systems?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bracing for impact]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/bracing-for-impact</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/bracing-for-impact"/>
        <updated>2024-02-20T15:04:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is the role of uncertainty quantification in feedback systems?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LLM vs. a cat?]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62581</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62581&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=62581"/>
        <updated>2024-02-20T13:32:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A bit of AI anti-hype — Sissi Cao, "Meta’s A.I. Chief Yann LeCun Explains Why a House Cat Is Smarter Than The Best A.I.", Observer 2/15/2024: “The brain of a house cat has about 800 million neurons. You have to multiply that by 2,000 to get to the number of synapses, or the connections between […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Political drumbeat:  cultural confidence]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62560</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62560&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=political-drumbeat-cultural-confidence"/>
        <updated>2024-02-20T00:20:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday, the hypernationalistic CCP government propaganda organ, Global Times, published the following article: "China shows cultural confidence as world shares Spring Festival’s spirit, legacy, joy", by Ai Peng, Global Times (2/18/24) Mark Metcalf called the conspicuous expression "cultural confidence" to my attention: It's appeared in LL twice.  Apparently it has propaganda 'legs' and, of course, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bayesian wars of the canals]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=54974</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/19/bayesian-wars-of-the-canals/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-18T23:24:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pronominal sentiment]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62562</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62562&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pronominal-sentiment"/>
        <updated>2024-02-18T20:38:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's Frazz:]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Much ado: more about corporate jargon]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62542</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62542&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=much-ado-more-about-corporate-jargon"/>
        <updated>2024-02-18T13:21:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[View this post on Instagram A post shared by Chief Meme Officer (@humorous_resources) Never has so little been said in so many expostulatory words. Do people really talk this way? Empty verbiage.  Empty minds.   Selected readings "On-the-job jargon" (9/7/23) "A century of complaints about business jargon" (9/15/13) "May I ask you a question?" (6/12/17) […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Shift from Models to Compound AI Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://bair.berkeley.edu/blog/2024/02/18/compound-ai-systems/</id>
        <link href="http://bair.berkeley.edu/blog/2024/02/18/compound-ai-systems/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-18T09:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI caught everyone’s attention in 2023 with Large Language Models (LLMs) that can be instructed to perform general tasks, such as translation or coding, just by prompting. This naturally led to an intense focus on models as the primary ingredient in AI application development, with everyone wondering what capabilities new LLMs will bring.
As more developers begin to build using LLMs, however, we believe that this focus is rapidly changing: state-of-the-art AI results are increasingly obtained by compound systems with multiple components, not just monolithic models.
For example, Google’s AlphaCode 2 set state-of-the-art results in programming through a carefully engineered system that uses LLMs to generate up to 1 million possible solutions for a task and then filter down the set. AlphaGeom…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>The Berkeley Artificial Intelligence Research Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[mostly MC[bruary]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55120</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/18/mostly-mcbruary/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-17T23:24:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sumerian smooching:  amorous postplay]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62455</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62455&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=sumerian-smooching-amorous-postplay"/>
        <updated>2024-02-17T05:15:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[—for Valentine's Day (belatedly) The cuneiform tablet pictured below may include the first textual description of a kiss. The Barton Cylinder, excavated in the ancient Sumerian city of Nippur in 1899 and dating to around 2400 B.C. Credit: The University of Pennsylvania Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology In the second column of text, a male divinity, […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lunar New Year's greetings, part 2]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62535</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62535&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=lunar-new-years-greetings-part-2"/>
        <updated>2024-02-17T05:08:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can't really have a traditional Lunar New Year's celebration without posting spring couplets, as witness here. In recent years, though, these "spring couplets" (chūnlián 春聯 / 春联) — a special type of "antithetical couplet" (duìlián 對聯 / 对联) — have morphed into all sorts of different forms and formats, such as this set, which we studied back in February […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lunar New Year's greetings, part 1]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62489</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62489&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=lunar-new-years-greetings-part-1"/>
        <updated>2024-02-17T04:54:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A bit belated, but better late than never. Except for the first line, which is "lóngnián zhùfú 龙年祝福" ("blessings for the year of the dragon"), all the other lines (the quatrain that follows the titular greetings) come with pinyin phonetic annotation, which led me to believe that I could dispense with the obligatory LL romanization.  […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese YMCA dance]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62521</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62521&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=chinese-ymca-dance"/>
        <updated>2024-02-17T00:37:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I still remember clearly the first time I tried the Y.M.C.A. dance.  That was about twenty years ago in New Haven when we celebrated Valerie Hansen's ascension to tenure at Yale.  When it comes to ballroom / partner dancing, I'm a total klutz, but I hoof it with abandon when it's single swirling-twirling-whirling. There was […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gazaouis have nowhere to go!]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55322</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/17/gazaouis-have-nowhere-to-go/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T23:24:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TikTalk?]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62499</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62499&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tiktalk"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T18:39:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The recent flurry about "TikTalk" seems to have started with Rochelle Barrand, "TikTok: 'Influencer speak' on social media platforms is likely to be the future of the English accent – expert", NationalWorld 11/22/2023: A language expert said a "TikTok voice" which is often used by influencers on social media platforms is likely to be "the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You take away the context]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/you-take-away-the-context</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/you-take-away-the-context"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T15:36:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adding information should simplify decision-making, right?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You take away the context]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/you-take-away-the-context</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/you-take-away-the-context"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T15:36:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adding information should simplify decision-making, right?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rajesh Rao]]></title>
        <id>https://mlfoundations.org/talk/rao/</id>
        <link href="https://mlfoundations.org/talk/rao/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Harvard ML Foundations</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pinyin nomenclature as an instrument of diplomacy]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62515</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62515&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pinyin-nomenclature-as-an-instrument-of-diplomacy"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T12:53:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever since China began aggressively to assert territorial claims over the seas south of its southernmost border all the way to Indonesia, disregarding the arbitral ruling of the international tribunal in favor of the Philippines on July 12, 2016, it has increasingly resorted to Pinyin naming practices to stake its claims to specific geographical features. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A depressilarious take on deepfakes]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62512</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62512&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=a-depressilarious-take-on-deepfakes"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T12:41:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[From SMBC: The mouseover title: "The really sad part is when they start deepfaking themselves for affirmation." The aftercomic: One of the comments on this strip describes it as "depressilarious". A not-at-all-depressing real-world analogue is described in "Avatar therapy to reduce auditory hallucinations for people with schizophrenia", 11/24/2017. More information can be found in this […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[oops there it goes again]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=54712</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/16/oops-there-it-goes-again/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T23:24:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Independent research"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62491</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62491&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=independent-research"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T21:36:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The current xkcd: The mouseover title: "Focus of your research: EXTREME PETTINESS AND UNWILLINGNESS TO LET ANYTHING GO" The current SMBC is a bit more transparently linguistic: Mouseover title: "OK, if patreon is any indication, many of you are confused but four and a half of you are HOWLING." The aftercomic: (If you're among the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theories of recourse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/theories-of-recourse</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/theories-of-recourse"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T15:02:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the manifold of decision frameworks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theories of recourse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/theories-of-recourse</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/theories-of-recourse"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T15:02:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the manifold of decision frameworks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our next-generation model: Gemini 1.5]]></title>
        <id>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/our-next-generation-model-gemini-15/</id>
        <link href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/our-next-generation-model-gemini-15/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T15:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The model delivers dramatically enhanced performance, with a breakthrough in long-context understanding across modalities.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google DeepMind Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The cry of the cicada]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62485</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62485&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-cry-of-the-cicada"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T13:33:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get ready!  They're coming, and they will make a huge amount of shrill, raucous NOISE.  They are most prevalent in the eastern half of the United States on a rolling basis for different regions, but this year, they will be positively overwhelming in the corridor from Northern Illinois to Arkansas and thence along the Southeast mountainous […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[a journal of the conquest, war, famine, death, and chaos year]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=54990</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/15/a-journal-of-the-conquest-war-famine-death-and-chaos-year/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T23:24:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Had to find a fifth horseman of the Apocalypse for 2024, and figured out that Terry Pratchett was the ultimate expert on these characters, witness “The Four Horsemen whose Ride presages the end of the world are known to be Death, War, Famine, and Pestilence. But even less significant events have their own Horsemen. For […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Malaprop(er nouns)?]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62467</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62467&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=malaproper-nouns"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T19:49:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden recently said "the president of Mexico" when he meant "the president of Egypt". A couple of days earlier, he said "Mitterand" when he meant "Macron". Of course this fed into the flurry about his age, which was both-siderized by references to Donald Trump's calling Victor Orbán "the great leader of Turkey" when he […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning the importance of training data under concept drift]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.research.google/2024/02/learning-importance-of-training-data.html</id>
        <link href="http://blog.research.google/2024/02/learning-importance-of-training-data.html"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T18:32:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Nishant Jain, Pre-doctoral Researcher, and Pradeep Shenoy, Research Scientist, Google Research




The constantly changing nature of the world around us poses a significant challenge for the development of AI models. Often, models are trained on longitudinal data with the hope that the training data used will accurately represent inputs the model may receive in the future. More generally, the default assumption that all training data are equally relevant often breaks in practice. For example, the figure below shows images from the CLEAR nonstationary learning benchmark, and it illustrates how visual features of objects evolve significantly over a 10 year span (a phenomenon we refer to as slow concept drift), posing a challenge for object categorization models. 








Sample ima…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ask Language Log:  Manchu Blue Dragon]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62434</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62434&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ask-language-log-manchu-blue-dragon"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T04:11:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Continuing our series on dragons, this note and illustration come from Juha Janhunen, the Finnish linguist: Happy Blue Dragon Year to everybody! Below is the official flag (1889-1912) of the Manchu Empire (in the west misleadingly known as "China"), which happens to have a blue dragon on it. Manchu muduri 'dragon' still seems to lack an external etymology. […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not quite Chinglish]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62415</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62415&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=not-quite-chinglish"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T03:52:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Signs in a Chinese park: Because none of these signs (more to come) are flagrantly wrong, I will not do a usual LL-style explication cum word-for-word transcription, translation, and explication.  Nonetheless, by and large they are awkward and unidiomatic, though some are rather charming in their own way.. In recent months, I've noticed that the […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[another scam “conference”]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=54841</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/14/another-scam-conference/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T23:24:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DP-Auditorium: A flexible library for auditing differential privacy]]></title>
        <id>http://blog.research.google/2024/02/dp-auditorium-flexible-library-for.html</id>
        <link href="http://blog.research.google/2024/02/dp-auditorium-flexible-library-for.html"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T22:11:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Posted by Mónica Ribero Díaz, Research Scientist, Google Research





Differential privacy (DP) is a property of randomized mechanisms that limit the influence of any individual user’s information while processing and analyzing data. DP offers a robust solution to address growing concerns about data protection, enabling technologies across industries and government applications (e.g., the US census) without compromising individual user identities.  As its adoption increases, it’s important to identify the potential risks of developing mechanisms with faulty implementations. Researchers have recently found errors in the mathematical proofs of private mechanisms, and their implementations. For example, researchers compared six sparse vector technique (SVT) variations and found that only two…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Google AI Blog</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Predictions and actions redux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/predictions-and-actions-redux</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/predictions-and-actions-redux"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T15:38:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the complex interactions between uncertainty quantification and recourse.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Predictions and actions redux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.argmin.net/p/predictions-and-actions-redux</id>
        <link href="https://www.argmin.net/p/predictions-and-actions-redux"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T15:38:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On the complex interactions between uncertainty quantification and recourse.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Recht</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not just NVIDIA: GPU programming that runs everywhere]]></title>
        <id>https://pythonspeed.com/articles/gpu-without-cuda/</id>
        <link href="https://pythonspeed.com/articles/gpu-without-cuda/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re doing computations on a GPU, NVIDIA is the default, alongside its CUDA libraries.
Some libraries like PyTorch support do support AMD GPUs and Macs.
But from the re-implementations of NumPy, SciPy, and Pandas in the RAPIDS project, to Numba’s GPU support, NVIDIA has best software support in the Python world.
Sticking to NVIDIA-specific software has some downsides, however:
It won’t run on modern Mac laptops.
Testing in CI is more difficult: you need custom runners that have NVIDIA GPUs.
You can’t use any other GPUs you might have access to, like AMD GPUs.
What can you do if you want to use GPUs in a portable manner?
In this article we’ll cover one option, the wgpu-py library.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Python⇒Speed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[poor graph [and not so poor agribusiness]]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55051</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/13/poor-graph-and-not-so-poor-agribusiness/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-12T23:24:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goody-2 and the Luddite Bots]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62448</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62448&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=goody-2-and-the-luddite-bots"/>
        <updated>2024-02-12T18:52:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Will Knight, "Meet the Pranksters Behind Goody-2, the World’s ‘Most Responsible’ AI Chatbot", Wired 2/9/2024: A new chatbot called Goody-2 takes AI safety to the next level: It refuses every request, responding with an explanation of how doing so might cause harm or breach ethical boundaries. Goody-2 declined to generate an essay on the American […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Bowl rhoticism]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62439</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62439&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=super-bowl-rhoticism"/>
        <updated>2024-02-12T13:59:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The most linguistically focused of this year's Super Bowl commercials: The NYT critic was not impressed. Mike Hale ("The Super Bowl Ads, Ranked", 2/11/2024) listed it under the heading "Inoffensive but Forgettable: They tried. Nobody got hurt", with the specific comment As the movie hero Agent State Farm, Arnold Schwarzenegger sends up his film persona […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Liberman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[yet another conference scam]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55045</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/12/yet-another-conference-scam/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-11T23:24:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Within a few days of the online appearance of the programme of the Workshop on Functional Inference and Machine Intelligence (FIMI) at the University of Bristol, which I am attending, I received the following email about accommodation, which did not sound right despite the focus on the right conference at the right time. After contacting […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ask Language Log:  Syriac Christian tombstone inscription from Mongol period East Asia]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62431</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62431&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ask-language-log-syriac-christian-tombstone-inscription-from-mongol-period-east-asia"/>
        <updated>2024-02-11T17:51:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Christian tombstone with Syriac inscription from Quanzhou, Fujian, SE China, from the Mongol (Yuan) period. I’d be exceedingly grateful if anyone could decipher the text. pic.twitter.com/iN2oBCCMOp — Iskandar Ding (@iskdin) February 11, 2024 The photograph has to be rotated 90º counterclockwise to be read. Iskandar Ding describes himself as a PhD candidate in Yaghnbobi and […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[gaming with abortion rights?!]]></title>
        <id>http://xianblog.wordpress.com/?p=55038</id>
        <link href="https://xianblog.wordpress.com/2024/02/11/gaming-with-abortion-rights/"/>
        <updated>2024-02-10T23:24:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visit the post for more.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>xi'an</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unforeseen circumcisions:  dual misfirings]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62406</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62406&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=unforeseen-circumcisions-dual-misfirings"/>
        <updated>2024-02-10T14:03:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sign on the door of a Pizza Hut eatery in Timmins, Ontario: (source) Of course, it's easy to see how "circumstances" can morph into "circumcisions", but Chau Wu has taken the investigation one step further to propose the following as a contributing / initiating trigger for the error: My hypothesis for the misfiring of neural […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not quite "CLOTHING & SHOES"]]></title>
        <id>https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62409</id>
        <link href="https://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/nll/?p=62409&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=not-quite-clothing-shoes"/>
        <updated>2024-02-10T13:57:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Note from François Lang:  "This is not photoshopped. I took this photo this afternoon in Rockville MD." Until 2020, I did not know this word (except as a gardening / agricultural implement, but that is not what is meant here).  I still am not very familiar with it, but I've been hearing / seeing it […]]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Mair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can neural networks do arithmetic? A survey on the elementary numerical
  skills of state-of-the-art deep learning models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.07735</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.07735"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T04:17:54.327Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alberto Testolin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statistical Guarantees for Link Prediction using Graph Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02692</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.02692"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T04:17:54.104Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alan Chung, Amin Saberi, Morgane Austern]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning from Time Series under Temporal Label Noise]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04398</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04398"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T04:17:53.662Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sujay Nagaraj, Walter Gerych, Sana Tonekaboni, Anna Goldenberg, Berk
  Ustun, Thomas Hartvigsen]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling laws for learning with real and surrogate data]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04376</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.04376"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T04:17:53.629Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ayush Jain, Andrea Montanari, Eren Sasoglu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple online learning with consistent oracle]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.08055</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.08055"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T04:17:53.560Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alexander Kozachinskiy, Tomasz Steifer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Classical Verification of Quantum Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04843</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04843"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T15:14:09.456Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matthias C. Caro, Marcel Hinsche, Marios Ioannou, Alexander Nietner,
  Ryan Sweke]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Empirical Study of Self-supervised Learning with Wasserstein Distance]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10143</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.10143"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T15:14:08.881Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Makoto Yamada, Yuki Takezawa, Guillaume Houry, Kira Michaela
  Dusterwald, Deborah Sulem, Han Zhao, Yao-Hung Hubert Tsai]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variational Representations of Annealing Paths: Bregman Information
  under Monotonic Embedding]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.07481</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2209.07481"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T15:14:08.806Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rob Brekelmans, Frank Nielsen]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Provably Efficient UCB-type Algorithms For Learning Predictive State
  Representations]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.00405</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.00405"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T15:14:08.617Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ruiquan Huang, Yingbin Liang, Jing Yang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Large Margin Mechanism and Pseudo Query Set on Cross-Domain Few-Shot
  Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2005.09218</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2005.09218"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T15:14:08.613Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jia-Fong Yeh, Hsin-Ying Lee, Bing-Chen Tsai, Yi-Rong Chen and
  Ping-Chia Huang, Winston H. Hsu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complete intersections in binomial and lattice ideals]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1205.0772</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1205.0772"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T04:17:40.507Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hiram H. Lopez, Rafael H. Villarreal]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Projective nested cartesian codes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1411.6819</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1411.6819"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T04:17:40.503Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cicero Carvalho, V. G. Lopez Neumann, Hiram H. Lopez]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Affine cartesian codes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1202.0085</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1202.0085"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T03:16:09.633Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hiram H. Lopez, Carlos Renteria, Rafael H. Villarreal]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parameterized affine codes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1109.2353</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1109.2353"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T03:16:09.580Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hiram H. Lopez, Eliseo Sarmiento, Maria Vaz Pinto, Rafael H.
  Villarreal]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Computing the degree of a lattice ideal of dimension one]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1206.1892</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1206.1892"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T03:16:09.403Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hiram H. Lopez, Rafael H. Villarreal]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complete intersection vanishing ideals on degenerate tori over finite
  fields]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1207.0244</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1207.0244"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T03:16:09.392Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hiram H. Lopez, Rafael H. Villarreal, Leticia Zarate]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rank distribution of Delsarte codes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1510.01008</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1510.01008"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T03:16:09.388Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Javier de la Cruz, Elisa Gorla, Hiram H. Lopez, Alberto Ravagnani]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the combinatorics of commutators of Lie algebras]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1609.09407</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1609.09407"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T04:16:46.631Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eduardo Hitomi, Felipe Yasumura]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geometric properties of some totally ordered compact sets]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1207.0330</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1207.0330"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T03:15:47.413Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mohammad Daher, Khalil Saadi]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In constructive and informal mathematics, in contradistinction to any
  empirical science, the predicate of the current knowledge in the subject is
  necessary]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1309.2605</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1309.2605"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T03:15:47.410Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apoloniusz Tyszka]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Holographic Phase Transitions in (2+1)-dimensional black hole spacetimes
  in NMG]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1307.1460</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1307.1460"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T03:15:47.406Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[E. Abdalla, Jeferson de Oliveira, A. B. Pavan, C. E. Pellicer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impulse control maximising average cost per unit time: a non-uniformly
  ergodic case]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1606.08731</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1606.08731"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T03:15:47.307Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jan Palczewski, Lukasz Stettner]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nilpotent orbit theorem in $p$-adic Hodge theory]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1612.03367</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1612.03367"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T03:15:46.799Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mohammad Reza Rahmati, Gerardo Flores]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From geometry to invertibility preservers]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1304.0232</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1304.0232"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T03:16:27.389Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hans Havlicek, Peter \v{S}emrl]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cayley's surface revisited]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1304.0225</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1304.0225"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T03:16:27.376Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hans Havlicek]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On distant-isomorphisms of projective lines]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1304.0226</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1304.0226"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T03:16:27.063Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andrea Blunck, Hans Havlicek]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lifting of divisible designs]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1304.1337</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1304.1337"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T03:16:26.995Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andrea Blunck, Hans Havlicek, Corrado Zanella]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Divisible designs from twisted dual numbers]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1304.1338</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1304.1338"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T03:16:26.965Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andrea Blunck, Hans Havlicek, Corrado Zanella]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comparing Machine Learning Algorithms by Union-Free Generic Depth]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12839</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.12839"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T05:15:03.576Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hannah Blocher, Georg Schollmeyer, Malte Nalenz, Christoph Jansen]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Position Paper: Bayesian Deep Learning in the Age of Large-Scale AI]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.00809</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.00809"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T05:15:02.951Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Theodore Papamarkou, Maria Skoularidou, Konstantina Palla, Laurence
  Aitchison, Julyan Arbel, David Dunson, Maurizio Filippone, Vincent Fortuin,
  Philipp Hennig, Aliaksandr Hubin, Alexander Immer, Theofanis Karaletsos,
  Mohammad Emtiyaz Khan, Agustinus Kristiadi, Yingzhen Li, Jose Miguel
  Hernandez Lobato, Stephan Mandt, Christopher Nemeth, Michael A. Osborne, Tim
  G. J. Rudner, David R\"ugamer, Yee Whye Teh, Max Welling, Andrew Gordon
  Wilson, Ruqi Zhang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Benefits of Transformer: In-Context Learning in Linear Regression Tasks
  with Unstructured Data]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.00743</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.00743"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T05:15:02.714Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yue Xing, Xiaofeng Lin, Namjoon Suh, Qifan Song, Guang Cheng]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient Exploration for LLMs]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.00396</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2402.00396"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T05:15:02.704Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vikranth Dwaracherla, Seyed Mohammad Asghari, Botao Hao, Benjamin Van
  Roy]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Purely Algebraic Approach to The Generalized Jacobian Conjecture]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1203.1691</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1203.1691"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T03:16:01.870Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Susumu Oda]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mapping Exoplanets]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1704.07832</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1704.07832"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T03:16:01.537Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nicolas B. Cowan, Yuka Fujii]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atoms of None of the Elements Ionize While Atoms of Inert Behavior Split
  by Photonic Current]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1611.05392</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1611.05392"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T03:16:00.531Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mubarak Ali]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Lieb-Thirring inequality revisited]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1808.09017</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1808.09017"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T10:15:33.140Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rupert L. Frank, Dirk Hundertmark, Michal Jex, Phan Th\`anh Nam]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Algebraic approximations of compact K\"ahler threefolds]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.01083</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.01083"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T10:15:32.979Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hsueh-Yung Lin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the dual positive cones and the algebraicity of a compact K\"ahler
  manifold]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.10654</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.10654"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T10:15:32.974Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hsueh-Yung Lin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Branching process descriptions of information cascades on Twitter]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.08916</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.08916"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T10:15:32.960Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[James P. Gleeson, Tomokatsu Onaga, Peter Fennell, James Cotter,
  Raymond Burke, David J. P. O'Sullivan]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tautological classes and symmetry in Khovanov-Rozansky homology]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.01212</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2103.01212"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T10:15:32.955Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eugene Gorsky, Matthew Hogancamp, Anton Mellit]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neural networks for geospatial data]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09157</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09157"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T07:14:01.684Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wentao Zhan, Abhirup Datta]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multi-modal Molecule Structure-text Model for Text-based Retrieval and
  Editing]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.10789</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.10789"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T07:14:01.662Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shengchao Liu, Weili Nie, Chengpeng Wang, Jiarui Lu, Zhuoran Qiao,
  Ling Liu, Jian Tang, Chaowei Xiao, Anima Anandkumar]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effect of Weight Quantization on Learning Models by Typical Case
  Analysis]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17269</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.17269"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T07:14:01.629Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shuhei Kashiwamura, Ayaka Sakata, Masaaki Imaizumi]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiple Yield Curve Modeling and Forecasting using Deep Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16985</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16985"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T07:14:01.626Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ronald Richman, Salvatore Scognamiglio]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unified Transfer Learning Models in High-Dimensional Linear Regression]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.00238</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2307.00238"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T07:14:01.579Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shuo Shuo Liu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The sample complexity of multi-distribution learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04027</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2312.04027"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T07:14:51.968Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Binghui Peng]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Computer Vision Self-supervised Learning Methods on Time Series]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.00783</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.00783"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T07:14:51.811Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daesoo Lee, Erlend Aune]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Multi-Grained Symmetric Differential Equation Model for Learning
  Protein-Ligand Binding Dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15122</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.15122"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T07:14:51.805Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shengchao Liu, Weitao Du, Yanjing Li, Zhuoxinran Li, Vignesh
  Bhethanabotla, Nakul Rampal, Omar Yaghi, Christian Borgs, Anima Anandkumar,
  Hongyu Guo, Jennifer Chayes]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adversarial Attacks on Graph Neural Networks via Meta Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1902.08412</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1902.08412"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T07:14:51.741Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Daniel Z\"ugner, Stephan G\"unnemann]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Stones Hit One Bird: Bilevel Positional Encoding for Better Length
  Extrapolation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16421</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.16421"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T07:14:51.737Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zhenyu He, Guhao Feng, Shengjie Luo, Kai Yang, Di He, Jingjing Xu, Zhi
  Zhang, Hongxia Yang, Liwei Wang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rank Jumps and Growth of Shafarevich--Tate Groups for Elliptic Curves in
  $\mathbb{Z}/p\mathbb{Z}$-Extensions]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.09166</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2107.09166"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T08:18:11.026Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lea Beneish, Debanjana Kundu, Anwesh Ray]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Categorical Koszul duality]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.01705</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.01705"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T08:18:10.638Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Julian Holstein, Andrey Lazarev]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast-HotStuff: A Fast and Resilient HotStuff Protocol]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2010.11454</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2010.11454"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T08:18:10.634Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mohammad M. Jalalzai, Jianyu Niu, Chen Feng, Fangyu Gai]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Rigidity Theorem for Anosov Geodesic Flows]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.09524</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.09524"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T08:18:10.622Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[\'Italo Dowell, Sergio Roma\~na]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Affine Anosov representations and proper actions]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1711.09712</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1711.09712"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T08:18:10.618Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sourav Ghosh, Nicolaus Treib]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Signature Methods in Machine Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14674</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.14674"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T07:13:36.380Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Terry Lyons, Andrew D. McLeod]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ECoFLaP: Efficient Coarse-to-Fine Layer-Wise Pruning for Vision-Language
  Models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02998</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.02998"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T07:13:36.376Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yi-Lin Sung, Jaehong Yoon, Mohit Bansal]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A multiobjective continuation method to compute the regularization path
  of deep neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.12044</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.12044"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T07:13:36.372Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Augustina C. Amakor, Konstantin Sonntag, Sebastian Peitz]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Disparities in Post Hoc Machine Learning Explanation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.14539</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.14539"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T07:13:36.368Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vishwali Mhasawade, Salman Rahman, Zoe Haskell-Craig, Rumi Chunara]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-dimensional Functional Graphical Model Structure Learning via
  Neighborhood Selection Approach]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.02487</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2105.02487"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T07:13:36.360Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boxin Zhao, Percy S. Zhai, Y. Samuel Wang, Mladen Kolar]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Nest by an Automaton]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1904.10850</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1904.10850"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T08:17:51.498Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jurek Czyzowicz, Dariusz Dereniowski, Andrzej Pelc]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-fattening of mean curvature flow at singularities of mean convex
  type]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1704.00431</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1704.00431"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T08:17:51.482Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Or Hershkovits, Brian White]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RETRACTED: Yang-Mills theory for bundle gerbes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/hep-th/0509037</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/hep-th/0509037"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T08:17:51.177Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Varghese Mathai, David Roberts]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Two-Page "Derivation" of Schroedinger's Equation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1907.09917</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1907.09917"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T08:17:50.952Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[C. Baumgarten]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quadratic fields, Artin-Schreier extensions, and Bell numbers]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.04647</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.04647"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T08:17:50.919Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yoshinosuke Hirakawa]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CompactifAI: Extreme Compression of Large Language Models using
  Quantum-Inspired Tensor Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.14109</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.14109"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T04:18:48.455Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andrei Tomut, Saeed S. Jahromi, Sukhbinder Singh, Faysal Ishtiaq,
  Cesar Mu\~noz, Prabdeep Singh Bajaj, Ali Elborady, Gianni del Bimbo, Mehrazin
  Alizadeh, David Montero, Pablo Martin-Ramiro, Muhammad Ibrahim, Oussama
  Tahiri Alaoui, John Malcolm, Samuel Mugel, Roman Orus]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transfer Learning for Contextual Multi-armed Bandits]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.12612</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.12612"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T04:18:48.334Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Changxiao Cai, T. Tony Cai, Hongzhe Li]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[At the junction between deep learning and statistics of extremes:
  formalizing the landslide hazard definition]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.14210</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.14210"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T04:18:48.330Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ashok Dahal, Rapha\"el Huser, Luigi Lombardo]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Systematic Approach to Robustness Modelling for Deep Convolutional
  Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13751</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13751"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T04:18:48.313Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Charles Meyers, Mohammad Reza Saleh Sedghpour, Tommy L\"ofstedt, Erik
  Elmroth]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A V2X-based Privacy Preserving Federated Measuring and Learning System]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13848</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13848"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T04:18:48.310Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Levente Alekszejenk\'o, Tadeusz Dobrowiecki]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probabilistic Demand Forecasting with Graph Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13096</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13096"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T04:19:46.798Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nikita Kozodoi, Elizaveta Zinovyeva, Simon Valentin, Jo\~ao Pereira,
  Rodrigo Agundez]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep Latent Force Models: ODE-based Process Convolutions for Bayesian
  Deep Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.14828</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.14828"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T04:19:46.668Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thomas Baldwin-McDonald, Mauricio A. \'Alvarez]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Differentially Private Distributed Estimation and Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.15865</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.15865"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T04:19:46.664Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Marios Papachristou, M. Amin Rahimian]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can overfitted deep neural networks in adversarial training generalize?
  -- An approximation viewpoint]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13624</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13624"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T04:19:46.538Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zhongjie Shi, Fanghui Liu, Yuan Cao, Johan A.K. Suykens]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full Bayesian Significance Testing for Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13335</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13335"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T04:19:46.528Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zehua Liu, Zimeng Li, Jingyuan Wang, Yue He]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep multitask neural networks for solving some stochastic optimal
  control problems]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12923</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12923"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T05:15:11.783Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Christian Yeo]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bayesian identification of nonseparable Hamiltonians with multiplicative
  noise using deep learning and reduced-order modeling]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12476</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12476"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T05:15:10.802Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nicholas Galioto, Harsh Sharma, Boris Kramer, Alex Arkady Gorodetsky]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Stability Principle for Learning under Non-Stationarity]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18304</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2310.18304"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T05:15:10.793Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chengpiao Huang, Kaizheng Wang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep Neural Network Benchmarks for Selective Classification]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12708</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12708"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T05:15:10.783Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andrea Pugnana, Lorenzo Perini, Jesse Davis, Salvatore
  Ruggieri]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contrastive Learning and Cycle Consistency-based Transductive Transfer
  Learning for Target Annotation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12340</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.12340"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T05:15:10.779Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shoaib Meraj Sami, Md Mahedi Hasan, Nasser M. Nasrabadi, Raghuveer Rao]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum-classical phase transition with spontaneous superposition
  breaking and single photon detection]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1007.2538</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1007.2538"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T05:14:55.367Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vladan Pankovic]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orbital period derivative of a binary system using an exact orbital
  energy equation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/0707.4544</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/0707.4544"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T05:14:54.260Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vikram H. Zaveri]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Periodic relativity: the theory of gravity in flat space time]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/0707.4539</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/0707.4539"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T05:14:54.225Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vikram H. Zaveri]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bayesian nonparametric modeling for mean residual life regression]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1412.0367</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1412.0367"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T05:14:54.219Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valerie Poynor, Athanasios Kottas]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collapsing 4-manifolds under a lower curvature bound]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1205.0323</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1205.0323"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T05:14:54.206Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Takao Yamaguchi]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Braid group actions from categorical symmetric Howe duality on deformed
  Webster algebras]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1802.05358</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1802.05358"/>
        <updated>2024-01-22T04:19:33.875Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mikhail Khovanov, Aaron D. Lauda, Joshua Sussan, Yasuyoshi Yonezawa]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Characterizing Exoplanet Habitability]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1701.05205</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1701.05205"/>
        <updated>2024-01-22T04:19:33.332Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tyler D. Robinson]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Labeling Neural Representations with Inverse Recognition]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.13594</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.13594"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T07:14:24.212Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kirill Bykov, Laura Kopf, Shinichi Nakajima, Marius Kloft, Marina
  M.-C. H\"ohne]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upper and lower bounds for the Lipschitz constant of random neural
  networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.01356</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.01356"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T07:14:24.178Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paul Geuchen, Thomas Heindl, Dominik St\"oger, Felix Voigtlaender]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Training Neural Networks is NP-Hard in Fixed Dimension]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.17045</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.17045"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T07:14:24.163Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vincent Froese, Christoph Hertrich]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Augmentation-based Self-Supervised Representation Learning
  via RKHS Approximation and Regression]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.00788</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.00788"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T07:14:24.148Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Runtian Zhai, Bingbin Liu, Andrej Risteski, Zico Kolter, Pradeep
  Ravikumar]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Querying Easily Flip-flopped Samples for Deep Active Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09787</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.09787"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T07:14:24.107Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Seong Jin Cho, Gwangsu Kim, Junghyun Lee, Jinwoo Shin, Chang D.
  Yoo]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expected Utility Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.6714</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.6714"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T06:20:34.795Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pierfrancesco La Mura, Yoav Shoham]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.3870</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.3870"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T05:15:04.471Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pierfrancesco La Mura]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Projective Expected Utility]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/0802.3300</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/0802.3300"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T05:15:04.466Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pierfrancesco La Mura]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Team Decision Problems with Classical and Quantum Signals]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1107.0237</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1107.0237"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T05:15:04.455Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adam Brandenburger, Pierfrancesco La Mura]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local regularity of the Bergman projection on a class of pseudoconvex
  domains of finite type]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1406.6532</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1406.6532"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T05:15:04.451Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tran Vu Khanh, Andrew Raich]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Algebraic solutions of tropical optimization problems]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1406.1777</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1406.1777"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T05:15:04.446Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[N. Krivulin]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tangent functor on microformal morphisms, and non-linear pullbacks for
  forms and cohomology]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.04335</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.04335"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T06:20:25.299Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Theodore Th. Voronov]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal transient behavior in large dynamical systems on networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1906.10634</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1906.10634"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T06:20:24.477Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wojciech Tarnowski, Izaak Neri, Pierpaolo Vivo]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geometric analysis of 1+1 dimensional quasilinear wave equations]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.04692</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.04692"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T06:20:24.467Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leonardo Enrique Abbrescia, Willie Wai Yeung Wong]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global Optimization of Gaussian processes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2005.10902</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2005.10902"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T06:20:24.301Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Artur M. Schweidtmann, Dominik Bongartz, Daniel Grothe, Tim
  Kerkenhoff, Xiaopeng Lin, Jaromil Najman, Alexander Mitsos]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Ramanujan-Petersson ans Selberg conjectures for Maass forms]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.10956</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.10956"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T06:20:24.275Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andr'e Unterberger]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unifying supervised learning and VAEs -- coverage, systematics and
  goodness-of-fit in normalizing-flow based neural network models for
  astro-particle reconstructions]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2008.05825</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2008.05825"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T04:19:15.881Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thorsten Gl\"usenkamp]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Convergence of stochastic gradient descent under a local Lojasiewicz
  condition for deep neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09221</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.09221"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T04:19:15.786Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jing An, Jianfeng Lu]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Bayesian Networks with Heterogeneous Agronomic Data Sets via
  Mixed-Effect Models and Hierarchical Clustering]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.06399</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2308.06399"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T04:19:15.639Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lorenzo Valleggi, Marco Scutari, Federico Mattia Stefanini]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Imperfect Surrogates for Downstream Inference: Design-based
  Supervised Learning for Social Science Applications of Large Language Models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04746</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04746"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T04:19:15.613Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Naoki Egami, Musashi Hinck, Brandon M. Stewart, Hanying Wei]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modeling Latent Selection with Structural Causal Models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06925</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.06925"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T04:19:15.198Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leihao Chen, Onno Zoeter, Joris M. Mooij]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Explaining Neural Networks without Access to Training Data]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.04891</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.04891"/>
        <updated>2024-01-15T06:21:31.054Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sascha Marton, Stefan L\"udtke, Christian Bartelt, Andrej Tschalzev,
  Heiner Stuckenschmidt]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controlling Moments with Kernel Stein Discrepancies]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.05408</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2211.05408"/>
        <updated>2024-01-15T06:21:25.314Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Heishiro Kanagawa, Alessandro Barp, Arthur Gretton, Lester
  Mackey]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A finite sample analysis of the benign overfitting phenomenon for ridge
  function estimation]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.12882</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2007.12882"/>
        <updated>2024-01-15T06:21:25.279Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emmanuel Caron, Stephane Chretien]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Query Complexity of Training Data Reconstruction in Private
  Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.16372</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2303.16372"/>
        <updated>2024-01-15T06:21:25.162Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Prateeti Mukherjee, Satya Lokam]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EC-NAS: Energy Consumption Aware Tabular Benchmarks for Neural
  Architecture Search]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.06015</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.06015"/>
        <updated>2024-01-15T06:21:25.152Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pedram Bakhtiarifard, Christian Igel, Raghavendra Selvan]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Explainable Stacked Ensemble Model for Static Route-Free Estimation
  of Time of Arrival]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.09438</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.09438"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T05:15:16.664Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[S\"oren Schleibaum, J\"org P. M\"uller, Monika Sester]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ARMA Cell: A Modular and Effective Approach for Neural Autoregressive
  Modeling]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.14919</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.14919"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T05:15:16.660Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Philipp Schiele, Christoph Berninger, David R\"ugamer]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linear Spaces of Meanings: Compositional Structures in Vision-Language
  Models]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.14383</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.14383"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T05:15:16.494Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Matthew Trager, Pramuditha Perera, Luca Zancato, Alessandro Achille,
  Parminder Bhatia, Stefano Soatto]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GPEX, A Framework For Interpreting Artificial Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.09820</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.09820"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T05:15:16.491Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amir Akbarnejad, Gilbert Bigras, Nilanjan Ray]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CP-PINNs: Changepoints Detection in PDEs using Physics Informed Neural
  Networks with Total-Variation Penalty]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.08626</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2208.08626"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T05:15:16.463Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Zhikang Dong, Pawel Polak]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Theoretical View of Linear Backpropagation and Its Convergence]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.11018</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2112.11018"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T04:19:04.080Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ziang Li, Yiwen Guo, Haodi Liu, Changshui Zhang]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GANDALF: Gated Adaptive Network for Deep Automated Learning of Features]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.08548</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2207.08548"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T04:19:04.064Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manu Joseph, Harsh Raj]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hierarchical Correlation Clustering and Tree Preserving Embedding]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2002.07756</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2002.07756"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T04:19:04.060Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Morteza Haghir Chehreghani, Mostafa Haghir Chehreghani]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adaptive joint distribution learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.04829</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2110.04829"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T04:19:04.012Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Damir Filipovic, Michael Multerer, Paul Schneider]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalized Optimistic Methods for Convex-Concave Saddle Point Problems]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.09674</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2202.09674"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T04:19:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ruichen Jiang, Aryan Mokhtari]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New bounds on the strength of some restrictions of Hindman's Theorem]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1701.06095</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1701.06095"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T08:19:40.975Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lorenzo Carlucci, Leszek Aleksander Ko{\l}odziejczyk, Francesco
  Lepore, Konrad Zdanowski]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The zonoid algebra, generalized mixed volumes, and random determinants]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.14996</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2109.14996"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T08:19:40.889Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paul Breiding, Peter B\"urgisser, Antonio Lerario, L\'eo Mathis]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Virasoro Constraints for Toric Bundles]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1508.06282</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1508.06282"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T08:19:40.383Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Coates, Alexander Givental, Hsian-Hua Tseng]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lifelong Ensemble Learning based on Multiple Representations for
  Few-Shot Object Recognition]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.01982</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.01982"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T08:19:40.029Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hamidreza Kasaei, Songsong Xiong]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Evolution of A.I. and Machine Learning: Towards a Meta-level
  Measuring and Understanding Impact, Influence, and Leadership at Premier A.I.
  Conferences]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.13131</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2205.13131"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T08:19:40.020Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rafael B. Audibert, Henrique Lemos, Pedro Avelar, Anderson R. Tavares,
  Lu\'is C. Lamb]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chain of LoRA: Efficient Fine-tuning of Language Models via Residual
  Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04151</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04151"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T06:20:28.336Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wenhan Xia, Chengwei Qin, Elad Hazan]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal rates of approximation by shallow ReLU$^k$ neural networks and
  applications to nonparametric regression]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.01561</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2304.01561"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T06:20:28.287Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yunfei Yang, Ding-Xuan Zhou]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-separable Covariance Kernels for Spatiotemporal Gaussian Processes
  based on a Hybrid Spectral Method and the Harmonic Oscillator]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.09580</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2302.09580"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T06:20:28.275Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dionissios T.Hristopulos]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General-Purpose In-Context Learning by Meta-Learning Transformers]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.04458</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2212.04458"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T06:20:28.252Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Louis Kirsch, James Harrison, Jascha Sohl-Dickstein, Luke Metz]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Consistency of Wide and Deep ReLU Neural Networks and Minimax
  Optimal Convergence Rates for Kolmogorov-Donoho Optimal Function Classes]]></title>
        <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04286</id>
        <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.04286"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T06:20:28.249Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hyunouk Ko, Xiaoming Huo]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>arxivist feed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>